<resources>
    <string name="app_name">99 Names Of Allah</string>
    <string name="language">English</string>
    <string name="names_en">"1. Ya Rahmanu,2.	Ya Raheemu,3.	Ya Maliku,4.	Ya Quddusu,5.	Ya Salamu,6.	Ya Mu\'minu,7.	Ya Muhayminu,8.	Ya Azizu,9.	Ya Jabbaaru,10.	Ya Mutakabbiru,11.	Ya Khaaliqu,12.	Ya Baariu,13.	Ya Musawwiru,14.	Ya Ghaffaaru,15.	Ya Qahhaaru,16.	Ya Wahhaabu,17.	Ya Razzaaqu,18.	Ya Fattaahu,19.	Ya Alimu,20.	Ya Qaabidhu,21.	Ya Baasitu,22.	Ya Khaafidhu,23.	Ya Raafi\'u,24.	Ya Mu\'izzu,25.	Ya Muzillu,26.	Ya Sami\'u,27.	Ya Basiru,28.	Ya Hakamu,29.	Ya \'Adlu,30.	Ya Latifu,31.	Ya Khabiru,32.	Ya Halimu,33.	Ya-‘Adheemu,34.	Ya Ghafuru,35.	Ya Shakuru,36.	Ya Aliu,37.	Ya Kabiru,38.	Ya Hafidhu,39.	Ya Muqitu,40.	Ya Hasibu,41.	Ya Jalilu,42.	Ya Karimu,43.	Ya Raqibu,44.	Ya Mujibu,45.	Ya Wasi\'u,46.	Ya Hakimu,47.	Ya Wadudu,48.	Ya Majeedu,49.	Ya Ba\'ithu,50.	Ya Shaheedu,51.	Ya Haqqu,52.	Ya Wakilu,53.	Ya Qawiyyu,54.	Ya Mateenu,55.	Ya Waliu,56.	Ya Hamiduu,57.	Ya Muhsi,58.	Ya Mubdiu,59.	Ya Mu\'idu,60.	Ya Muhyi,61.	Ya Mumitu,62.	Ya Hayyu,63.	Ya Qayyumu,64.	Ya Waajidu,65.	Ya Maajidu,66.	Ya Waahidu,67.	Ya Ahadu,68.	Ya Samadu,69.	Ya Qaadiru,70.	Ya Muqtadiru,71.	Ya Muqaddimu,72.	Ya Mu\'akhkhiru,73.	Ya Awwalu,74.	Ya Aakhiru,75.	Ya Dhaahiru,76.	Ya Baatinu,77.	Ya Waaliu,78.	Ya Muta\'ali,79.	Ya Barru,80.	Ya Tawwaabu,81.	Ya Muntaqimu,82.	Ya \'Afuwwu,83.	Ya Ra\'ufu,84.	Ya Malik Al Mulki,85.	Ya Jal-Jalali Al Ikram,86.	Ya Muqsitu,87.	Ya Jaami\'u,88.	Ya Ghaniu,89.	Ya Mughniu,90.	Ya Mani\'u,91.	Ya Dharru,92.	Ya Nafi\'u,93.	Ya Nuru,94.	Ya Hadiu,95.	Ya Badi\'iu,96.	Ya Baaqiu,97.	Ya Waarithu,98.	Ya Rashidu,99.	Ya Sabooru"</string>
    <string name="meaning_en">"The Beneficent,The Merciful,The Eternal Lord,The Most Sacred,The Embodiment of Peace,The Infuser of Faith,The Preserver of Safety,The Mighty One,The Omnipotent One,The Dominant One,The Creator,The Evolver,The Flawless Shaper,The Great Forgiver,The All-Prevailing One,The Supreme Bestower,The Total Provider,The Supreme Solver,The All-Knowing One,The Restricting One,The Extender,The Reducer,The Elevating One,The Honourer-Bestower,The Abaser,The All-Hearer,The All-Seeing,The Impartial Judge,The Embodiment of Justice,The Knower of Subtleties,The All-Aware One,The Clement One,The Magnificent One,The Great Forgiver,The Acknowledging One,The Sublime One,The Great One,The Guarding One,The Sustaining One,The Reckoning One,The Majestic One,The Bountiful One,The Watchful One,The Responding One,The All-Pervading One,The Wise One,The Loving One,The Glorious One,The Infuser of New Life,The All Observing Witness,The Embodiment of Truth,The Universal Trustee,The Strong One,The Firm One,The Protecting Associate,The Sole-Laudable One,The All-Enumerating One,The Originator,The Restorer,The Maintainer of life,The Inflictor of Death,The Eternally Living One,The Self-Subsisting One,The Pointing One,The All-Noble One,The Only One,The Sole One,The Supreme Provider,The Omnipotent One,The All Authoritative One,The Expediting One,The Procrastinator,The Very First,The Infinite Last One,The Perceptible,The Imperceptible,The Holder of Supreme Authority,The Extremely Exalted One,The Fountain-Head of Truth,The Ever-Acceptor of Repentance,The Retaliator,The Supreme Pardoner,The Benign One,The Eternal Possessor of Sovereignty,The Possessor of Majesty and Honour,The Just One,The Assembler of Scattered Creations,The Self-Sufficient One,The Bestower of Sufficiency,The Preventer,The Distressor,The Bestower of Benefits,The Prime Light,The Provider of Guidance,The Unique One,The Ever Surviving One,The Eternal Inheritor,The Guide to Path of Rectitude,The Extensively Enduring One"</string>
    <string name="des_en">"Ya Rahmanu is the One who wills goodness and mercy for all His creatures. He bestows immense grace and blessings upon the universe... showing compassion to all beings. His mercy is vast and encompasses all things... irrespective of their faith or deeds. This name reflects Allah\'s nurturing care for all creation.,Ya Raheemu is the One who acts with extreme kindness and compassion... particularly towards believers. His mercy is everlasting and manifests both in this world and the Hereafter. This name signifies Allah\'s forgiveness and the rewards He prepares for the faithful. It emphasizes His gentle and compassionate nature.,Ya Maliku is the Sovereign Lord... the One with complete dominion over the universe. His rule is absolute... and His authority is perfect and free from any imperfection. This name illustrates Allah\’s power and control over all matters... both seen and unseen. He governs all creation with wisdom and justice.,Ya Quddusu is the One who is pure from any imperfection and is exalted above all flaws and weaknesses. He is free from all attributes that imply defect or deficiency. This name highlights Allah\’s purity and holiness. It reflects His transcendence and sanctity... being beyond human comprehension.,Ya Salamu is the One who is free from every imperfection and bestows peace and security upon His creation. He grants tranquility to hearts and minds... ensuring safety and harmony. This name signifies Allah\’s perfection and the peace that comes from submission to Him. It underscores His role as the giver of serenity.,Ya Mu\'minu is the One who provides security and affirms His faithful believers\' truth. He offers protection and peace... shielding them from fear and harm. This name emphasizes Allah\’s role in providing safety and trust. It also assures believers of the truth of their faith and the reality of His promises.,Ya Muhayminu is the One who watches over and protects all His creation... knowing their actions and thoughts. He maintains and oversees all things with perfect knowledge and authority. This name reflects Allah\’s vigilance and His guardianship over everything. It assures believers of His constant care and attention.,Ya Azizu is the One who is mighty and strong... the Defeater who is not defeated. He is unparalleled in might and honor... overpowering all His enemies. This name illustrates Allah\’s strength and invincibility. It shows His ability to prevail and protect those who seek His help.,Ya Jabbaaru is the One who compels and restores... exercising His will over His creation. He mends the broken and imposes His decree upon all that exists. This name signifies Allah\’s power to enforce His commands and rectify matters. It also reflects His ability to heal and restore balance.,Ya Mutakabbiru is the One who is clear from the attributes of the creatures and from resembling them... and who is supremely great. He alone possesses greatness and majesty beyond comprehension. This name highlights Allah\’s superiority and transcendence over all creation. It emphasizes His exalted status and the dignity of His divine essence.,Ya Khaaliqu is the One who brings everything from non-existence to existence. He creates all things with precision and purpose. This name reflects Allah\’s ability to originate and innovate creation. It underscores His role as the ultimate Creator of the universe and all it contains.,Ya Baariu is the Maker... the Creator who has the power to turn entities into different states. He brings forth and evolves His creation according to His wisdom. This name signifies Allah\’s creativity and His ability to form His creatures in unique ways. It highlights His role in shaping and developing all forms of life.,Ya Musawwiru is the One who forms His creatures in different shapes and forms. He gives each creation its unique characteristics and attributes. This name emphasizes Allah\’s artistic power and attention to detail in creation. It reflects His ability to design and give form to all beings.,Ya Ghaffaaru is the One who forgives the sins of His slaves time and time again. His forgiveness is vast... covering even the gravest of sins for those who repent. This name signifies Allah\’s boundless mercy and willingness to pardon. It underscores His readiness to forgive and cleanse those who seek His forgiveness.,Ya Qahhaaru is the Dominant... the One who has the perfect power and is not unable over anything. He overpowers and subdues His creation as He wills. This name illustrates Allah\’s absolute control and dominance over all things. It reflects His ability to subdue and His supreme authority.,Ya Wahhaabu is the One who is Generous in giving plenty without any return. He grants gifts and blessings out of His bounty and grace. This name signifies Allah\’s generosity and kindness. It highlights His role as the giver of all that benefits... whether lawful or forbidden.,Ya Razzaaqu is the Sustainer... the Provider who ensures the sustenance of all His creatures. He distributes provisions with wisdom and generosity. This name emphasizes Allah\’s role in providing for the needs of His creation. It underscores His care and benevolence in sustaining life.,Ya Fattaahu is the Opener... the Reliever... the Judge who opens for His slaves the closed worldly and religious matters. He grants victory... relief... and solutions to difficulties. This name signifies Allah\’s power to remove obstacles and provide guidance. It reflects His role in easing paths and resolving issues.,Ya Alimu is the Knowledgeable; the One nothing is absent from His knowledge. He is aware of all things... past... present... and future. This name emphasizes Allah\’s omniscience and His perfect knowledge of all affairs. It underscores His awareness and understanding of all creation.,Ya Qaabidhu is the One who constricts the sustenance by His wisdom. He withholds provisions according to His divine plan. This name signifies Allah\’s control over the distribution of resources. It highlights His wisdom in determining what is best for His creation.,Ya Baasitu is the One who expands and widens sustenance with His generosity and mercy. He increases provisions and grants abundance. This name reflects Allah\’s kindness and liberality. It emphasizes His ability to enlarge and bless His creation with bountiful resources.,Ya Khaafidhu is the One who lowers whoever He wills by His destruction. He brings down those who deserve to be humbled. This name signifies Allah\’s justice and His power to abase. It reflects His role in balancing the scales of justice by lowering the arrogant and unjust.,Ya Raafi\'u is the Elevator... the One who raises whoever He wills by His endowment. He elevates the status of the righteous and virtuous. This name highlights Allah\’s ability to honor and exalt. It reflects His generosity in granting high ranks and dignity to His faithful servants.,Ya Mu\'izzu is the One who gives esteem to whoever He wills; hence there is no one to degrade him. He bestows honor and dignity upon His chosen ones. This name signifies Allah\’s power to honor and elevate. It reflects His authority in granting respect and status.,Ya Muzillu is the Humiliator... the One who degrades whoever He wills; hence there is no one to give him esteem. He brings down the arrogant and unjust. This name emphasizes Allah\’s justice in lowering the undeserving. It reflects His power to humble and abase those who defy His commands.,Ya Sami\'u is the One who hears all things that are heard by His eternal hearing without an ear... instrument... or organ. He listens to the prayers and supplications of His creation. This name signifies Allah\’s perfect and comprehensive hearing. It reflects His attentiveness to the needs and pleas of His servants.,Ya Basiru is the One who sees all things that are seen by His eternal seeing without a pupil or any other instrument. He observes all actions and events in the universe. This name emphasizes Allah\’s omnipresent vision. It reflects His awareness and vigilance over all creation.,Ya Hakamu is the Ruler... and His judgment is His word. He settles all matters with justice and wisdom. This name signifies Allah\’s role as the ultimate arbiter and judge. It highlights His authority in making fair decisions and His final say in all affairs.,Ya \'Adlu is the One who is entitled to do what He does. His actions and judgments are fair and equitable. This name reflects Allah\’s perfect justice and balance. It underscores His role in maintaining fairness and righteousness in the universe.,Ya Latifu is the Gracious... the One who is kind to His slaves and endows upon them. He understands the finest mysteries and intricacies. This name signifies Allah\’s gentle and compassionate nature. It highlights His kindness and His subtle ways of bestowing grace and mercy.,Ya Khabiru is the One who knows the truth of things. He is fully aware of all hidden and apparent matters. This name emphasizes Allah\’s deep knowledge and awareness. It reflects His understanding of the true essence of all things.,Ya Halimu is the One who delays the punishment for those who deserve it and then might forgive them. He is patient and lenient. This name signifies Allah\’s tolerance and patience. It reflects His willingness to give time for repentance and correction.,Ya-\'Adheemu is the Mighty... the One deserving of exaltment... glory... extolment... and purity from all imperfection. He is majestic and grand in every aspect. This name highlights Allah\’s greatness and majesty. It reflects His exalted status and the reverence He deserves.,Ya Ghafuru is the Forgiving... the One who forgives a lot. His forgiveness is extensive and covers all sins for those who sincerely repent. This name signifies Allah\’s immense mercy and readiness to pardon. It emphasizes His graciousness in forgiving and overlooking faults.,Ya Shakuru is the One who gives a lot of reward for a little obedience. He acknowledges and rewards even the smallest acts of goodness. This name reflects Allah\’s generosity and appreciation for His servants\’ efforts. It highlights His willingness to multiply rewards for good deeds.,Ya Aliu is the One who is clear from the attributes of the creatures. He is exalted above all creation. This name signifies Allah\’s supreme status and transcendence. It reflects His high rank and the purity of His divine essence.,Ya Kabiru is the Great... the One who is greater than everything in status. His grandeur is beyond comprehension. This name emphasizes Allah\’s immense greatness. It highlights His superiority over all that exists.,Ya Hafidhu is the Protector... the One who protects whatever and whoever He wills to protect. He safeguards all creation from harm. This name signifies Allah\’s role as the guardian and preserver. It reflects His ability to maintain and protect His creation.,Ya Muqitu is the Guardian... the Feeder... the One who has the power to maintain all things. He provides sustenance and supports all life. This name highlights Allah\’s role in sustaining and nourishing His creation. It emphasizes His continuous care and provision.,Ya Hasibu is the One who gives satisfaction. He is sufficient as a protector and reckoner. This name signifies Allah\’s ability to account for all actions and deeds. It reflects His role in providing recompense and ensuring justice.,Ya Jalilu is the Beneficent... the One who is attributed with greatness of power and glory of status. He is majestic and revered. This name highlights Allah\’s grandeur and majesty. It reflects His exalted status and the reverence He commands.,Ya Karimu is the Gracious... the One who is attributed with greatness of power and glory of status. He is bountiful and kind. This name signifies Allah\’s generosity and benevolence. It highlights His willingness to give and bestow favors.,Ya Raqibu is the One that nothing is absent from Him. He observes all actions and thoughts. This name emphasizes Allah\’s vigilance and awareness. It reflects His ability to monitor and oversee all creation.,Ya Mujibu is the Hearkener... the One who answers the one in need if he asks Him and rescues the yearner if he calls upon Him. He responds to prayers and supplications. This name signifies Allah\’s readiness to answer and assist. It highlights His responsiveness to the calls of His servants.,Ya Wasi\'u is the Vast... the One whose knowledge and mercy encompass all things. He is limitless in His attributes. This name reflects Allah\’s infinite nature and boundless compassion. It emphasizes His ability to encompass all creation with His grace and knowledge.,Ya Hakimu is the Judge of Judges... the One who is correct in His doings. His wisdom governs all actions and decrees. This name signifies Allah\’s perfect wisdom and judgment. It highlights His ability to make decisions that are just and wise.,Ya Wadudu is the One who loves His believing slaves and whose believers love Him. His love is manifest in His mercy and praise for them. This name reflects Allah\’s affection and kindness towards His faithful servants. It emphasizes the reciprocal love between the Creator and His creation.,Ya Majeedu is the One who is with perfect power... high status... compassion... generosity... and kindness. He is majestic and honorable. This name signifies Allah\’s grandeur and nobility. It highlights His exalted position and the glory of His attributes.,Ya Ba\'ithu is the Raiser (from death)... the One who resurrects His slaves after death for reward and/or punishment. He brings the dead to life. This name signifies Allah\’s power over life and death. It reflects His ability to bring forth resurrection and judge all beings.,Ya Shaheedu is the One who nothing is absent from Him. He witnesses all actions and events. This name emphasizes Allah\’s omnipresence and His role as an ever-present witness. It reflects His awareness of all that transpires in the universe.,Ya Haqqu is the True... the One who truly exists. His existence is absolute and eternal. This name signifies Allah\’s reality and authenticity. It emphasizes His position as the ultimate truth and foundation of all existence.,Ya Wakilu is the One who gives satisfaction and is relied upon. He is the best guardian and trustee. This name reflects Allah\’s dependability and trustworthiness. It emphasizes His role as the one to whom all matters are entrusted.,Ya Qawiyyu is the Strong... the One with complete power. He is mighty and powerful beyond measure. This name signifies Allah\’s strength and authority. It highlights His ability to accomplish all things and protect His creation.,Ya Mateenu is the One with extreme power which is un-interrupted and He does not get tired. His strength is solid and unwavering. This name reflects Allah\’s firmness and resilience. It emphasizes His enduring power and steadfastness.,Ya Waliu is the Supporter and protector. He befriends and aids His righteous servants. This name signifies Allah\’s closeness and support. It reflects His role as a guardian and ally to those who seek His protection.,Ya Hamiduu is the praised One who deserves to be praised. His attributes and actions are worthy of all praise. This name reflects Allah\’s deservingness of gratitude and admiration. It emphasizes His praiseworthy nature and the honor due to Him.,Ya Muhsi is the One who the count of things is known to Him. He is aware of all quantities and measures. This name signifies Allah\’s comprehensive knowledge of all details. It reflects His ability to account for everything in existence.,Ya Mubdiu is the One who started the human being. He creates without any pre-existing model. This name signifies Allah\’s innovation and originality in creation. It highlights His role as the initial creator of all things.,Ya Mu\'idu is the One who brings back the creatures after death. He restores life and revives the dead. This name signifies Allah\’s power over life and death. It reflects His ability to resurrect and bring back His creation.,Ya Muhyi is the One who gives life to the lifeless. He revives both physical and spiritual life. This name signifies Allah\’s role in creating and sustaining life. It highlights His ability to grant and renew life.,Ya Mumitu is the One who renders the living dead. He has control over life and death. This name signifies Allah\’s power to take life away. It reflects His authority over the end of life and the transition to the hereafter.,Ya Hayyu is the One attributed with a life that is unlike our life and is not that of a combination of soul... flesh... or blood. He possesses eternal and self-sustaining life. This name signifies Allah\’s unique and everlasting existence. It reflects His vitality and the source of life itself.,Ya Qayyumu is the One who remains and does not end. He sustains all things by Himself and does not require any support. This name signifies Allah\’s self-sufficiency and independence. It reflects His eternal existence and His role as the sustainer of all creation.,Ya Waajidu is the Finder... the Rich who is never poor. He is self-sufficient and abundant in wealth. This name signifies Allah\’s richness and His ability to provide for all needs. It reflects His completeness and the sufficiency of His attributes.,Ya Maajidu is the Most Glorious... He who is with perfect power. His greatness is unmatched and radiant. This name signifies Allah\’s magnificence and splendor. It reflects His majestic presence and the glory of His divine essence.,Ya Waahidu is the One... the Eternal... the Independent. He is singular and incomparable. This name signifies Allah\’s oneness and uniqueness. It reflects His absolute unity and independence from all creation.,Ya Ahadu is the One without a partner... the Unique. He has no equal or rival. This name signifies Allah\’s indivisible unity and singularity. It reflects His exclusive status as the sole deity worthy of worship.,Ya Samadu is the Eternal... the Independent... the Master who is relied upon. He is eternal and unchanging. This name signifies Allah\’s everlasting nature and His role as the ultimate source of support. It reflects His permanence and constancy.,Ya Qaadiru is the Capable... the One attributed with Power. He has the ability to accomplish all things. This name signifies Allah\’s omnipotence and His control over all affairs. It reflects His unlimited power and authority.,Ya Muqtadiru is the Dominant... the One with complete Power. His authority is absolute and irresistible. This name signifies Allah\’s sovereignty and His ability to enforce His will. It reflects His supreme might and control over all creation.,Ya Muqaddimu is the One who advances and accelerates. He prioritizes and facilitates matters according to His wisdom. This name signifies Allah\’s ability to hasten and expedite events. It reflects His power to bring about outcomes swiftly and decisively.,Ya Mu\'akhkhiru is the One who delays and defers. He postpones events according to His divine plan. This name signifies Allah\’s wisdom in delaying outcomes for a greater purpose. It reflects His control over time and His ability to determine the pace of events.,Ya Awwalu is the First... the One who existed before all else. He is the origin and source of all creation. This name signifies Allah\’s precedence and His timeless existence. It reflects His primacy and the beginning of all things.,Ya Aakhiru is the Last... the One who will remain after all else has perished. He is eternal and everlasting. This name signifies Allah\’s permanence and His presence beyond the end of time. It reflects His finality and the ultimate conclusion of all existence.,Ya Dhaahiru is the Manifest... the One whose presence is evident and clear. He is apparent and visible in His signs and creations. This name signifies Allah\’s visibility and His manifestation in the universe. It reflects His clarity and the evident display of His attributes.,Ya Baatinu is the Hidden... the One whose essence is concealed and mysterious. He is beyond human perception and comprehension. This name signifies Allah\’s invisibility and His concealed nature. It reflects His transcendence and the depth of His divine essence.,Ya Waaliu is the Patron... the Protecting Friend who guides and supports His servants. He is their ally and guardian. This name signifies Allah\’s closeness and His role as a supportive companion. It reflects His care and guidance for those who seek His protection.,Ya Muta\'ali is the Supremely Exalted... the One whose status is beyond comparison. He is elevated above all creation. This name signifies Allah\’s transcendence and His exalted rank. It reflects His superiority and the loftiness of His divine essence.,Ya Barru is the Source of Goodness... the One who is kind and benevolent. He bestows blessings and favors upon His creation. This name signifies Allah\’s goodness and His abundant grace. It reflects His generosity and the abundance of His blessings.,Ya Tawwaabu is the Ever-Returning... the One who accepts repentance and forgives sins. He is merciful and compassionate. This name signifies Allah\’s willingness to forgive and His readiness to accept those who turn to Him in repentance. It reflects His boundless mercy and His invitation to return to Him.,Ya Muntaqimu is the Avenger... the One who punishes those who transgress His limits. He enforces justice and retribution. This name signifies Allah\’s wrath against wrongdoing and His commitment to uphold justice. It reflects His role as the ultimate judge and executor of divine justice.,Ya \'Afuwwu is the Pardoner... the One who pardons and overlooks faults. He erases sins and grants absolution. This name signifies Allah\’s mercy and His willingness to forgive without holding grudges. It reflects His generosity in pardoning His servants.,Ya Ra\'ufu is the Compassionate... the One who is tender and merciful. He feels empathy for His creation and shows them compassion. This name signifies Allah\’s gentleness and His caring nature. It reflects His sympathy and concern for the welfare of His servants.,Ya Malik Al Mulki is the Owner of Sovereignty... the One who possesses dominion over all things. He is the ultimate ruler and authority. This name signifies Allah\’s kingship and His absolute control over the universe. It reflects His sovereignty and His right to command and decree.,Ya Jal-Jalali Al Ikram is the One who possesses grandeur and nobility. He is majestic and worthy of all honor and respect. This name signifies Allah\’s exalted status and His deservingness of reverence. It reflects His dignity... magnificence... and the honor that is due to Him.,Ya Muqsitu is the One who is fair and just in all His judgments and actions. He maintains balance and equity in the universe. This name signifies Allah\’s commitment to justice and fairness. It reflects His role in ensuring that all deeds are rewarded or punished appropriately.,Ya Jaami\'u is the One who brings together what He wills... when He wills. He will gather all creatures for the Day of Judgment. This name signifies Allah\’s ability to assemble and unite. It reflects His power to bring together all beings for accountability.,Ya Ghaniu is the One who is free from any need. He is self-sufficient and independent of all creation. This name signifies Allah\’s richness and His lack of need for anything outside Himself. It reflects His absolute sufficiency and independence.,Ya Mughniu is the One who provides wealth and sufficiency to His creatures. He enriches whom He wills. This name signifies Allah\’s generosity and His ability to bestow prosperity. It reflects His role in granting abundance and wealth to His servants.,Ya Mani\'u is the One who prevents harm or evil from occurring. He is the protector and the defender. This name signifies Allah\’s ability to protect and shield from danger. It reflects His role in safeguarding His creation from harm.,Ya Dharru is the One who can bring about harm or affliction if He wills. He has control over all circumstances. This name signifies Allah\’s power over adversity and hardship. It reflects His authority to bring about trials as a test or punishment.,Ya Nafi\'u is the One who brings about benefits and blessings. He bestows goodness and welfare. This name signifies Allah\’s role in providing and facilitating positive outcomes. It reflects His ability to grant benefits and favor.,Ya Nuru is the Light... the One who illuminates the heavens and the earth. He guides and provides clarity. This name signifies Allah\’s role as a source of guidance and enlightenment. It reflects His ability to bring light to darkness and clarity to confusion.,Ya Hadiu is the One who guides His servants to the right path. He provides direction and inspiration. This name signifies Allah\’s role as a source of guidance and wisdom. It reflects His ability to lead His creation towards righteousness and truth.,Ya Badi\'iu is the Incomparable... the One who creates in unparalleled and wondrous ways. He is unique in His creation. This name signifies Allah\’s originality and His unmatched creative power. It reflects His ability to create without precedent or model.,Ya Baaqiu is the Everlasting... the One who remains when all else perishes. He is eternal and unchanging. This name signifies Allah\’s permanence and His existence beyond time. It reflects His continuity and the eternal nature of His being.,Ya Waarithu is the Heir... the One who remains after all of creation has come to an end. He will inherit the earth and everything on it. This name signifies Allah\’s ultimate ownership and His enduring presence. It reflects His role as the final possessor of all things.,Ya Rashidu is the Righteous Teacher... the One who guides to the path of righteousness. He provides wisdom and correct understanding. This name signifies Allah\’s role as a teacher and a guide. It reflects His ability to lead His servants to righteous and beneficial knowledge.,Ya Sabooru is the Patient One... the One who does not hasten to punish sinners. He is forbearing and tolerant. This name signifies Allah\’s patience and His restraint in delaying punishment. It reflects His willingness to give time for repentance and His endurance in dealing with human transgressions."</string>

    <!--    bangla -->
    <string name="app_name_bn">আল্লাহর ৯৯টি নাম</string>
    <string name="language_bn">বাংলা</string>
    <string name="names_bn">"১. ইয়া রহমানু, ২. ইয়া রাহিমু, ৩. ইয়া মালিকু, ৪. ইয়া কুদ্দুসু, ৫. ইয়া সালামু, ৬. ইয়া মুমিনু, ৭. ইয়া মুহাইমিনু, ৮. ইয়া আজিজু, ৯. ইয়া জাব্বারু, ১০. ইয়া মুতাকাব্বিরু, ১১. ইয়া খালিকু, ১২. ইয়া বারিউ, ১৩. ইয়া মুসাউইরু, ১৪. ইয়া গাফ্ফারু, ১৫. ইয়া কাহহারু, ১৬. ইয়া ওয়াহাবু, ১৭. ইয়া রাজ্জাকু, ১৮. ইয়া ফাত্তাহু, ১৯. ইয়া আলিমু, ২0. ইয়া কাবিধু, ২১. ইয়া বাসিতু, ২২. ইয়া খাফিদু, ২৩. ইয়া রাফিউ, ২৪. ইয়া মুইজ্জু, ২৫. ইয়া মুজিলু, ২৬. ইয়া সামিউ, ২৭. ইয়া বাসিরু, ২৮. ইয়া হাকামু, ২৯. ইয়া \'আদলু,৩0. ইয়া লতিফু, ৩১. ইয়া খাবিরু, ৩২. ইয়া হালিমু, ৩৩. ইয়া-আজিমু, ৩৪. ইয়া গাফুরু, ৩৫. ইয়া শাকুরু, ৩৬. ইয়া আলিউ, ৩৭. ইয়া কাবিরু, ৩৮. ইয়া হাফিদু, ৩৯. ইয়া মুকিতু, ৪0. ইয়া হাসিবু, ৪১. ইয়া জালিলু, ৪২. ইয়া করিমু, ৪৩. ইয়া রাকিবু, ৪৪. ইয়া মুজিবু, ৪৫. ইয়া ওয়াসিউ, ৪৬. ইয়া হাকিমু, ৪৭. ইয়া ওয়াদুদু, ৪৮ ইয়া মাজিদু, ৪৯. ইয়া বাইথু, ৫0. ইয়া শহীদু, ৫১. ইয়া হাক্কু, ৫২. ইয়া ওয়াকিলু, ৫৩. ইয়া কাওয়্যু, ৫৪. ইয়া মাতেনু, ৫৫. ইয়া ওয়ালিউ, ৫৬. ইয়া হামিদু, ৫৭. ইয়া মুহসি ,৫৮. ইয়া মুবদিউ, ৫৯. ইয়া মুইদু, ৬0. ইয়া মুহি, ৬১. ইয়া মুমিতু, ৬২. ইয়া হায়্যু, ৬৩. ইয়া কাইয়ুমু, ৬৪. ইয়া ওয়াজিদু, ৬৫. ইয়া মাজিদু, ৬৬. ইয়া ওয়াহিদু, ৬৭. ইয়া আহাদু, ৬৮. ইয়া সামাদু, ৬৯. ইয়া কাদিরু, ৭0. ইয়া মুকতাদিরু, ৭১. ইয়া মুকাদ্দিমু, ৭২. ইয়া মুআখখিরু, ৭৩. ইয়া আউয়ালু, ৭৪. ইয়া আখিরু, ৭৫. ইয়া দাহিরু, ৭৬. ইয়া বাতিনু,৭৭. ইয়া ওয়ালিউ, ৭৮. ইয়া মুতাআলী, ৭৯. ইয়া বাররু, ৮0. ইয়া তাওয়াবু, ৮১. ইয়া মুনতাকিমু, ৮২. ইয়া আফুউউউ, ৮৩. ইয়া রাউফু, ৮৪. ইয়া মালিক আল মুলকি, ৮৫. ইয়া জাল-জালালি আল ইকরাম,৮৬. ইয়া মুকসিতু, ৮৭. ইয়া জামিউ, ৮৮. ইয়া গনিউ, ৮৯. ইয়া মুগনিউ, ৯০. ইয়া মানিউ,৯১. ইয়া দাররু, ৯২. ইয়া নাফিউ,৯৩. ইয়া নুরু,৯৪. ইয়া হাদিউ, ৯৫. ইয়া বদিউ,৯৬. ইয়া বাকিউ,৯৭. ইয়া ওয়ারিসু, ৯৮. ইয়া রাশিদু, ৯৯. ইয়া সবুরু"</string>
    <string name="meaning_bn">"দয়াময়,করুণাময়,চিরস্থায়ী প্রভু,পবিত্রতম,শান্তির প্রতিমূর্তি,বিশ্বাসের সঞ্চারকারী,নিরাপত্তার রক্ষক,পরাক্রমশালী,সর্বশক্তিমান,প্রতাপশালী,সৃষ্টিকর্তা,পরিবর্তনকারী,নিখুঁত গঠনকারী,মহা ক্ষমাশীল,সর্বশক্তিমান,সর্বোচ্চ দাতা,মোট প্রদানকারী,সর্বোচ্চ সমাধানকারী,সর্বজ্ঞানী,সীমিতকারী,প্রসারক,সংকোচনকারী,উচ্চতর,সম্মানিতকারী-দাতা,অপমানকারী,শ্রোতা,দর্শক,নিরপেক্ষ বিচারক,ন্যায়ের প্রতিমূর্তি,গোপন জ্ঞানের অধিকারী,সচেতন,সুধী,মহান,মহান ক্ষমাশীল,স্বীকারকারী,উচ্চতম,মহান,রক্ষক,পালক,হিসাবকারী,মহান,দাতা,পর্যবেক্ষক,প্রতিকারকারী,সর্বব্যাপী,জ্ঞানী,প্রেমময়,মহান,নতুন জীবনের সঞ্চারকারী,পর্যবেক্ষক সাক্ষী,সত্যের প্রতিমূর্তি,বিশ্বস্ত,শক্তিশালী,মজবুত,রক্ষাকারী,প্রশংসিত,গণনাকারী,উদ্ভাবক,পুনর্জীবনকারী,জীবনের রক্ষক,মৃত্যুর সঞ্চারকারী,চিরন্তন জীবিত,স্বয়ংসম্পূর্ণ,ইঙ্গিতকারী,মহান,একমাত্র,অপরিহার্য,সর্বোচ্চ প্রদানকারী,সর্বশক্তিমান,সর্বশাসক,বেগবর্ধনকারী,বিলম্বকারী,প্রথম,শেষ,উপলব্ধ,অদৃশ্য,সর্বোচ্চ ক্ষমতার অধিকারী,অত্যন্ত মহান,সত্যের উৎস,তওবা গ্রহণকারী,প্রতিশোধ গ্রহণকারী,ক্ষমাশীল,কল্যাণময়,চিরস্থায়ী শাসকের অধিকারী,মহানতা ও সম্মানের অধিকারী,ন্যায়পরায়ণ,বিচ্ছিন্ন সৃষ্টির সমবেতকারী,স্বয়ংসম্পূর্ণ,পর্যাপ্ততার দাতা,প্রতিরোধকারী,ক্ষতিকর,লাভদাতা,প্রধান আলো,নির্দেশক,অনন্য,চিরস্থায়ী,চিরন্তন উত্তরাধিকারী,সঠিক পথের নির্দেশক,অত্যন্ত স্থায়ী"</string>

    <!--    hindi -->
    <string name="app_name_hi">अल्लाह के 99 नाम</string>
    <string name="language_hi">हिंदी</string>
    <string name="names_hi">"1. या रहमाना, 2. या रहीमू, 3. या मालिकू, 4. या कुद्दुसू, 5. या सलामू, 6. या मु'मिनू, 7. या मुहैयमिनू, 8. या अजीजू, 9. या जब्बारू, 10. या मुतकब्बिरू, 11. या खालिकू, 12. या बारीऊ, 13. या मुसव्विरू, 14. या गफ्फारू, 15. या क़ह्हारू, 16. या वह्हाबू, 17. या रज़्ज़ाकू, 18. या फत्ताहू, 19. या अलीमू, 20. या क़ाबिदू, 21. या बासितू, 22. या ख़ाफिदू, 23. या राफ़िऊ, 24. या मु'इज़्ज़ू, 25. या मुज़िल्लू, 26. या समी'ऊ, 27. या बसीरू, 28. या हाकमु, 29. या 'अद्लू, 30. या लतीफू, 31. या ख़बीरू, 32. या हलीमू, 33. या 'अज़ीमू, 34. या गफूरू, 35. या शाकूरू, 36. या 'अलियू, 37. या कबीरू, 38. या हफिदू, 39. या मुकितू, 40. या हसीबू, 41. या जलीलू, 42. या करीमू, 43. या रक़ीबू, 44. या मुझीबू, 45. या वासिऊ, 46. या हकीमू, 47. या वदूदू, 48. या मजीदू, 49. या बाअिथू, 50. या शहीदू, 51. या हक्कू, 52. या वकीलू, 53. या कवीय्यू, 54. या मतीनू, 55. या वलियू, 56. या हामिदू, 57. या मुह्सी, 58. या मुबदिउ, 59. या मु'ईदू, 60. या मुहयी, 61. या मुमीतू, 62. या हय्यू, 63. या क़य्यूमू, 64. या वाजिदू, 65. या माजिदू, 66. या वाहिदू, 67. या अहदू, 68. या समदू, 69. या क़ादिरू, 70. या मुक़तादिरू, 71. या मुकद्दिमू, 72. या मु'अख्खिरू, 73. या अव्वलू, 74. या आख़िरू, 75. या जाहिरू, 76. या बातिनू, 77. या वालियू, 78. या मुत'आली, 79. या बर्रू, 80. या तव्वाबू, 81. या मुन्तकिमू, 82. या 'अफुव्वू, 83. या रऊफू, 84. या मलिक अल मुलकी, 85. या जल-जालाली अल इकराम, 86. या मुक्सितू, 87. या जामी'ऊ, 88. या ग़नियू, 89. या मुग़नियू, 90. या मानी'ऊ, 91. या ज़ार्रू, 92. या नाफ़िऊ, 93. या नूरू, 94. या हादीऊ, 95. या बदी'ऊ, 96. या बाक़िऊ, 97. या वारिथू, 98. या रशीदू, 99. या सबूरू"</string>
    <string name="meaning_hi">"दया करने वाला, अत्यंत दयालु, अनन्त प्रभु, सबसे पवित्र, शांति का प्रतीक, विश्वास का संचारक, सुरक्षा का रक्षक, महान शक्तिशाली, सर्वशक्तिमान, सर्वाधिक प्रभुत्वशाली, सृष्टिकर्ता, विकसित करने वाला, त्रुटिहीन आकार देने वाला, महान क्षमाशील, सर्वव्यापी, सर्वोच्च दाता, पूर्ण प्रदाता, सर्वोच्च हलकर्ता, सर्वज्ञानी, सीमित करने वाला, विस्तार करने वाला, घटाने वाला, उन्नत करने वाला, सम्मान दाता, नीचा दिखाने वाला, सब कुछ सुनने वाला, सब कुछ देखने वाला, निष्पक्ष न्यायाधीश, न्याय का प्रतीक, सूक्ष्मताओं का जानकार, सर्वज्ञानी, सहनशील, भव्य, महान क्षमाशील, मान्यता देने वाला, श्रेष्ठ, महान, रक्षक, पोषण करने वाला, गणना करने वाला, भव्य, उदार, निरीक्षण करने वाला, प्रत्युत्तर देने वाला, सर्वव्यापी, बुद्धिमान, प्रेममय, महिमामंडित, नया जीवन देने वाला, सब कुछ देखने वाला गवाह, सत्य का प्रतीक, सार्वभौमिक संरक्षक, शक्तिशाली, दृढ़, संरक्षक सहयोगी, एकमात्र प्रशंसनीय, सब कुछ गिनने वाला, सृष्टिकर्ता, पुनः स्थापित करने वाला, जीवन का पोषक, मृत्यु देने वाला, अनन्त जीवन वाला, स्वयं-निर्भर, संकेत करने वाला, श्रेष्ठ, केवल एक, एकमात्र, सर्वोच्च प्रदाता, सर्वशक्तिमान, सम्पूर्ण अधिकारी, शीघ्रता से करने वाला, विलंब करने वाला, सबसे पहला, अनन्त अंतिम, दृश्य, अदृश्य, सर्वोच्च अधिकार का धारक, अत्यंत महान, सत्य का स्रोत, पश्चाताप स्वीकार करने वाला, प्रतिशोध लेने वाला, सर्वोच्च क्षमाशील, कोमल, शाश्वत सत्ता का धारक, महानता और सम्मान का धारक, न्यायपूर्ण, बिखरी हुई रचनाओं का संग्राहक, आत्मनिर्भर, पर्याप्तता देने वाला, रोकने वाला, कष्ट देने वाला, लाभ देने वाला, प्रमुख प्रकाश, मार्गदर्शन देने वाला, अद्वितीय, सदैव जीवित, शाश्वत उत्तराधिकारी, सत्य मार्ग पर मार्गदर्शक, अत्यधिक सहनशील"</string>

    <!--    arabic-->
    <string name="app_name_arabic">٩٩ أسماء الله</string>
    <string name="language_arab">العربية</string>
    <string name="names_arabic">"١. يا رحمن, ٢. يا رحيم, ٣. يا ملك, ٤. يا قدوس, ٥. يا سلام, ٦. يا مؤمن, ٧. يا مهيمن, ٨. يا عزيز, ٩. يا جبار, ١٠. يا متكبر, ١١. يا خالق, ١٢. يا بارئ, ١٣. يا مصور, ١٤. يا غفار, ١٥. يا قهار, ١٦. يا وهاب, ١٧. يا رزاق, ١٨. يا فتاح, ١٩. يا عليم, ٢٠. يا قابض, ٢١. يا باسط, ٢٢. يا خافض, ٢٣. يا رافع, ٢٤. يا معز, ٢٥. يا مذل, ٢٦. يا سميع, ٢٧. يا بصير, ٢٨. يا حكم, ٢٩. يا عدل, ٣٠. يا لطيف, ٣١. يا خبير, ٣٢. يا حليم, ٣٣. يا عظيم, ٣٤. يا غفور, ٣٥. يا شكور, ٣٦. يا علي, ٣٧. يا كبير, ٣٨. يا حفيظ, ٣٩. يا مقيت, ٤٠. يا حسيب, ٤١. يا جليل, ٤٢. يا كريم, ٤٣. يا رقيب, ٤٤. يا مجيب, ٤٥. يا واسع, ٤٦. يا حكيم, ٤٧. يا ودود, ٤٨. يا مجيد, ٤٩. يا باعث, ٥٠. يا شهيد, ٥١. يا حق, ٥٢. يا وكيل, ٥٣. يا قوي, ٥٤. يا متين, ٥٥. يا ولي, ٥٦. يا حميد, ٥٧. يا محصي, ٥٨. يا مبدئ, ٥٩. يا معيد, ٦٠. يا محيي, ٦١. يا مميت, ٦٢. يا حي, ٦٣. يا قيوم, ٦٤. يا واجد, ٦٥. يا ماجد, ٦٦. يا واحد, ٦٧. يا أحد, ٦٨. يا صمد, ٦٩. يا قادر, ٧٠. يا مقتدر, ٧١. يا مقدم, ٧٢. يا مؤخر, ٧٣. يا أول, ٧٤. يا آخر, ٧٥. يا ظاهر, ٧٦. يا باطن, ٧٧. يا والي, ٧٨. يا متعالي, ٧٩. يا بر, ٨٠. يا تواب, ٨١. يا منتقم, ٨٢. يا عفو, ٨٣. يا رؤوف, ٨٤. يا مالك الملك, ٨٥. يا ذو الجلال والإكرام, ٨٦. يا مقسط, ٨٧. يا جامع, ٨٨. يا غني, ٨٩. يا مغني, ٩٠. يا مانع, ٩١. يا ضار, ٩٢. يا نافع, ٩٣. يا نور, ٩٤. يا هادي, ٩٥. يا بديع, ٩٦. يا باقي, ٩٧. يا وارث, ٩٨. يا رشيد, ٩٩. يا صبور"</string>
    <string name="meaning_arabic">"الرحمن,الرحيم,الرب الأبدي,الأقدس,تجسيد السلام,مانح الإيمان,حافظ الأمان,العزيز,القدير,المهيمن,الخالق,المصور,الشكل المثالي,الغفور العظيم,القاهر,الواهب الأعظم,المزود الكلي,الحلال الأعظم,العليم,المقيد,الباسط,الخافض,الرافع,المعز-الواهب,المذل,السميع,البصير,الحكم العادل,تجسيد العدل,العليم بالأسرار,الخبير,الحليم,العظيم,الغفور العظيم,المعترف,المتسامي,العظيم,الحافظ,المقيم,المحاسب,الجليل,الكريم,الرقيب,المجيب,المحيط,الحكيم,الودود,المجيد,مانح الحياة الجديدة,الشاهد,تجسيد الحقيقة,الوكيل,القوي,المتين,الحافظ,الحميد,المحصي,المبدع,المعيد,المحافظ على الحياة,المميت,الحي الأبدي,القيوم,المرشد,الكريم,الواحد,الأحد,الرازق,القدير,الحاكم,المعجل,المؤخر,الأول,الآخر,الظاهر,الباطن,مالك الملك,المتعالي,ينبوع الحقيقة,تواب,المنتقم,العفو,اللطيف,ملك الملوك الأبدي,ذو الجلال والإكرام,العادل,جامع الخلائق,الغني,المغني,المانع,الضار,النافع,النور الأول,الهادي,الفرد,الباقي,الوارث,المرشد إلى الطريق المستقيم,الباقي"</string>
    <string name="des_arabic">"الرحمن هو الذي يريد الخير والرحمة لجميع خلقه. يمنح نعمة وبركات عظيمة على الكون، ويظهر رحمة لكل الكائنات. رحمته واسعة وتشمل كل شيء، بغض النظر عن إيمانهم أو أعمالهم. يعكس هذا الاسم رعاية الله الحنونة لجميع خلقه.,الرحيم هو الذي يعمل بلطف وشفقة فائقة، خصوصًا تجاه المؤمنين. رحمته أبدية وتظهر في هذا العالم والآخرة. يشير هذا الاسم إلى مغفرة الله والمكافآت التي يعدها للمؤمنين. يؤكد على طبيعته الرقيقة والرحيمة.,الملك هو السيد الحاكم، الذي يملك السيادة الكاملة على الكون. حكمه مطلق، وسلطته كاملة وخالية من أي عيب. يوضح هذا الاسم قوة الله وتحكمه في جميع الأمور، سواء المرئية أو غير المرئية. يدير جميع الخلق بحكمة وعدل.,القدوس هو الذي هو نقي من أي نقص وهو مرفوع فوق جميع العيوب والضعف. هو خالٍ من جميع الصفات التي تدل على العيب أو النقص. يبرز هذا الاسم نقاء الله وقداسته. يعكس تفوقه وقداسته، حيث يكون فوق فهم الإنسان.,السلام هو الذي هو خالٍ من كل عيب ويمنح السلام والأمان لخلقه. يمنح الطمأنينة للقلوب والعقول، ويضمن السلامة والانسجام. يشير هذا الاسم إلى كمال الله والسلام الذي يأتي من الخضوع له. يؤكد على دوره كمانح السكينة.,المؤمن هو الذي يوفر الأمان ويؤكد حقيقة المؤمنين المخلصين. يقدم الحماية والسلام، ويحميهم من الخوف والأذى. يؤكد هذا الاسم دور الله في توفير السلامة والثقة. كما يضمن للمؤمنين حقيقة إيمانهم وواقعية وعوده.,المهيمن هو الذي يراقب ويحمي جميع خلقه، ويعرف أفعالهم وأفكارهم. يحافظ ويشرف على كل شيء بمعرفة وسلطة كاملة. يعكس هذا الاسم يقظة الله ورعايته على كل شيء. يؤكد للمؤمنين رعايته المستمرة واهتمامه.,العزيز هو الذي هو قوي وقوي، المنتصر الذي لا يُهزم. لا نظير له في القوة والشرف، يتغلب على جميع أعدائه. يوضح هذا الاسم قوة الله وعدم قابليته للهزيمة. يظهر قدرته على التغلب وحماية أولئك الذين يطلبون مساعدته.,الجبار هو الذي يجبر ويستعيد، يمارس إرادته على خلقه. يصلح الكسور ويفرض مرسومه على كل ما يوجد. يشير هذا الاسم إلى قدرة الله على فرض أوامره وتصحيح الأمور. كما يعكس قدرته على الشفاء واستعادة التوازن.,المتكبر هو الذي هو واضح من صفات المخلوقات ومن مشابهتهم، وهو العظيم. وحده يمتلك العظمة والجلال بما يفوق الفهم. يبرز هذا الاسم تفوق الله وتعاليه على جميع الخلق. يؤكد على وضعه المرفوع وكرامة جوهره الإلهي.,الخالق هو الذي يأتي بكل شيء من عدم الوجود إلى الوجود. يخلق كل شيء بدقة وهدف. يعكس هذا الاسم قدرة الله على الابتكار والإبداع. يؤكد على دوره كخالق نهائي للكون وكل ما يحتويه.,البارئ هو الصانع، الخالق الذي لديه القدرة على تحويل الكائنات إلى حالات مختلفة. يخرج ويطور خلقه وفقًا لحكمته. يشير هذا الاسم إلى إبداع الله وقدرته على تشكيل خلقه بطرق فريدة. يبرز دوره في تشكيل وتطوير جميع أشكال الحياة.,المصور هو الذي يشكل خلقه في أشكال وصور مختلفة. يمنح كل خلق خصائصه وصفاته الفريدة. يؤكد هذا الاسم على القوة الفنية لله والاهتمام بالتفاصيل في الخلق. يعكس قدرته على التصميم ومنح الشكل لجميع الكائنات.,الغفار هو الذي يغفر ذنوب عبيده مرة تلو الأخرى. مغفرته واسعة، تغطي حتى أعظم الذنوب لمن يتوب. يشير هذا الاسم إلى رحمة الله اللامحدودة واستعداده للعفو. يؤكد على استعداده للمغفرة وتطهير من يسعون إلى مغفرته.,القهار هو المسيطر، الذي لديه القوة الكاملة ولا يعجز عن أي شيء. يغلب ويقهر خلقه كما يشاء. يوضح هذا الاسم تحكم الله المطلق وسيطرته على كل شيء. يعكس قدرته على التغلب وسلطته العليا.,الوهاب هو الذي يعطي بسخاء دون أي عائد. يمنح الهدايا والبركات من كرمه وفضله. يشير هذا الاسم إلى سخاء الله ولطفه. يبرز دوره كمانح لكل ما هو مفيد، سواء كان حلالًا أو حرامًا.,الرزاق هو المعطي، الذي يضمن رزق جميع مخلوقاته. يوزع الأرزاق بحكمة وكرم. هذا الاسم يبرز دور الله في توفير احتياجات خلقه. يؤكد على عنايته وفضله في الحفاظ على الحياة., الفتاح هو الذي يفتح لعباده الأمور المغلقة في الدنيا والدين. يمنح النصر والفرج والحلول للصعوبات. هذا الاسم يدل على قدرة الله في إزالة العقبات وتوفير الهداية. يعكس دوره في تيسير الأمور وحل المشاكل., العليم هو العالم؛ الذي لا يغيب عن علمه شيء. هو مدرك لكل شيء، الماضي، الحاضر، والمستقبل. هذا الاسم يبرز علم الله الشامل ومعرفته الكاملة بكل الأمور. يؤكد على وعيه وفهمه الكامل لجميع الخلق., القابض هو الذي يقبض الرزق بحكمته. يمنع الأرزاق وفقًا لخطته الإلهية. هذا الاسم يدل على سيطرة الله على توزيع الموارد. يبرز حكمته في تحديد ما هو الأفضل لخلقه., الباسط هو الذي يوسع الرزق بكرمه ورحمته. يزيد في الأرزاق ويمنح الوفرة. يعكس هذا الاسم لطف الله وكرمه. يؤكد على قدرته في توسيع رزقه وبركة خلقه بموارد وفيرة., الخافض هو الذي يخفض من يشاء بعقابه. ينزل من يستحق الذل. هذا الاسم يدل على عدل الله وقدرته على إذلال المتكبرين والظالمين. يعكس دوره في موازنة العدالة بخفض المستحقين., الرافع هو الذي يرفع من يشاء بعطائه. يرفع من مكانة الصالحين والفاضلين. هذا الاسم يبرز قدرة الله على تكريم وتعظيم. يعكس كرمه في منح الدرجات العالية والكرامة لعباده المؤمنين., المعز هو الذي يمنح الكرامة لمن يشاء؛ فلا أحد يذله. يمنح الشرف والكرامة لمن يختارهم. هذا الاسم يدل على قدرة الله في تكريم ورفع. يعكس سلطته في منح الاحترام والمكانة., المذل هو الذي يذل من يشاء؛ فلا أحد يمنحه الكرامة. يخفض المتكبرين والظالمين. يؤكد هذا الاسم عدل الله في إذلال غير المستحقين. يعكس قدرته على إذلال وتحقير من يعصون أوامره., السميع هو الذي يسمع كل شيء يسمع بسمعه الأزلي دون أذن أو أداة. يستمع إلى دعاء وتضرعات خلقه. هذا الاسم يدل على سمع الله الكامل والشامل. يعكس انتباهه لاحتياجات ودعوات عباده., البصير هو الذي يرى كل شيء يرى ببصره الأزلي دون بؤبؤ أو أي أداة. يراقب كل الأفعال والأحداث في الكون. هذا الاسم يبرز رؤية الله الشاملة. يعكس وعيه ويقظته على كل الخلق., الحكم هو الحاكم، وكلمته هي حكمه. يحكم في جميع الأمور بالعدل والحكمة. هذا الاسم يدل على دور الله كالقاضي والحكم النهائي. يبرز سلطته في اتخاذ القرارات العادلة وكلمته النهائية في كل الأمور., العدل هو الذي يحق له أن يفعل ما يفعل. أفعاله وأحكامه عادلة ومنصفة. يعكس هذا الاسم عدل الله الكامل والتوازن. يؤكد على دوره في الحفاظ على الإنصاف والحق في الكون., اللطيف هو الرؤوف، الذي يكون لطيفًا مع عباده ويمنحهم. يفهم أدق الأسرار والتفاصيل. هذا الاسم يدل على طبيعة الله اللطيفة والرحيمة. يبرز لطفه وطرق تقديمه النعمة والرحمة بطرق دقيقة., الخبير هو الذي يعرف حقيقة الأشياء. هو مدرك تمامًا لكل الأمور المخفية والظاهرة. يبرز هذا الاسم معرفة الله العميقة ووعيه. يعكس فهمه لحقيقة كل شيء., الحليم هو الذي يؤجل العقوبة لمن يستحقها وقد يغفر لهم. هو صبور ومتسامح. هذا الاسم يدل على تسامح الله وصبره. يعكس استعداده لمنح الوقت للتوبة والتصحيح., العظيم هو العظيم، الذي يستحق التعظيم، المجد، التمجيد، والتنزه عن كل نقص. هو جليل وعظيم في كل جانب. يبرز هذا الاسم عظمة الله وجلاله. يعكس مكانته الرفيعة والتوقير الذي يستحقه., الغفور هو الغفور، الذي يغفر كثيرًا. مغفرته واسعة وتشمل جميع الذنوب لمن يتوب بصدق. هذا الاسم يدل على رحمة الله العظيمة واستعداده للعفو. يبرز كرمه في المغفرة وتجاوز الأخطاء., الشكور هو الذي يعطي الكثير من الأجر على القليل من الطاعة. يعترف ويكافئ حتى أصغر الأعمال الصالحة. يعكس هذا الاسم كرم الله وتقديره لجهود عباده. يبرز استعداده لمضاعفة الأجر على الأعمال الصالحة., العلي هو الذي هو منزه عن صفات المخلوقات. هو مرفوع فوق كل خلقه. يدل هذا الاسم على مكانة الله العليا وتعاليه. يعكس رتبته الرفيعة ونقاء جوهره الإلهي., الكبير هو العظيم، الذي هو أعظم من كل شيء في المكانة. عظمته تتجاوز الفهم. يؤكد هذا الاسم عظمة الله الكبيرة. يبرز تفوقه على كل ما يوجد., الحفيظ هو الحافظ، الذي يحفظ ما يشاء ومن يشاء حمايته. يحمي جميع الخلق من الأذى. هذا الاسم يدل على دور الله كحارس وحافظ. يعكس قدرته على الحفاظ وحماية خلقه., المقيت هو الحافظ، المعين، الذي لديه القدرة على الحفاظ على كل شيء. يوفر الغذاء ويدعم جميع الحياة. يبرز هذا الاسم دور الله في الحفاظ وتغذية خلقه. يؤكد على رعايته المستمرة وتقديمه., الحسيب هو الذي يعطي الرضا. هو كافٍ كحافظ وحاسب. يدل هذا الاسم على قدرة الله في محاسبة جميع الأفعال والأعمال. يعكس دوره في تقديم العوض وضمان العدل., الجليل هو الكريم، الذي يتصف بعظمة القوة والمكانة. هو جليل ومبجل. يبرز هذا الاسم عظمة الله وجلاله. يعكس مكانته الرفيعة والتقدير الذي يستحقه., الكريم هو الكريم، الذي يتصف بعظمة القوة والمكانة. هو سخي ولطيف. يدل هذا الاسم على سخاء الله وفضله. يبرز استعداده للعطاء ومنح النعم., الرقيب هو الذي لا يغيب عنه شيء. يراقب كل الأفعال والأفكار. يؤكد هذا الاسم على يقظة الله ووعيه. يعكس قدرته على المراقبة والإشراف على جميع خلقه.,المجيب هو الذي يجيب من دعاه ويغيث الملهوف إذا ناداه. يستجيب للدعاء والتضرعات. هذا الاسم يدل على استعداد الله للإجابة والمساعدة. يبرز استجابته لدعوات عباده., الواسع هو الذي وسع علمه ورحمته كل شيء. هو بلا حدود في صفاته. يعكس هذا الاسم طبيعة الله اللامتناهية ورحمته الواسعة. يؤكد قدرته على شمول كل الخلق برحمته ومعرفته., الحكيم هو قاضي القضاة، الذي يكون صوابًا في أفعاله. تحكم حكمته كل الأفعال والقرارات. يدل هذا الاسم على حكمة الله الكاملة وحكمه العادل. يبرز قدرته على اتخاذ القرارات العادلة والحكيمة., الودود هو الذي يحب عباده المؤمنين ويحبونه. يتجلى حبه في رحمته وثنائه عليهم. يعكس هذا الاسم محبة الله ولطفه تجاه عباده المؤمنين. يؤكد على المحبة المتبادلة بين الخالق وخلقه., المجيد هو الذي يتمتع بالقوة الكاملة، والمكانة العالية، والرحمة، والكرم، واللطف. هو جليل ومشرف. يدل هذا الاسم على عظمة الله ونبله. يبرز مكانته الرفيعة ومجد صفاته., الباعث هو الذي يبعث عباده بعد الموت للثواب أو العقاب. يعيد الأموات إلى الحياة. يدل هذا الاسم على قدرة الله على الحياة والموت. يعكس قدرته على البعث والحكم على جميع الكائنات., الشهيد هو الذي لا يغيب عنه شيء. يشهد جميع الأفعال والأحداث. يؤكد هذا الاسم على حضور الله الدائم ودوره كشاهد دائم. يعكس وعيه بكل ما يحدث في الكون., الحق هو الحق، الذي وجوده حق. وجوده مطلق وأبدي. يدل هذا الاسم على حقيقة الله وأصالته. يؤكد مكانته كالحقيقة المطلقة وأساس الوجود كله., الوكيل هو الذي يعطي الرضا ويمكن الاعتماد عليه. هو أفضل الحماة والموكِّلين. يعكس هذا الاسم اعتمادية الله وأمانته. يؤكد دوره كمن تُوكل إليه جميع الأمور., القوي هو القوي، الذي لديه القوة الكاملة. هو عظيم وقوي بلا حدود. يدل هذا الاسم على قوة الله وسلطته. يبرز قدرته على تحقيق كل شيء وحماية خلقه., المتين هو الذي يتمتع بالقوة الكبيرة التي لا تنقطع ولا يتعب. قوته ثابتة ولا تتزعزع. يعكس هذا الاسم صلابة الله وثباته. يؤكد على قوته الدائمة وثباته., الولي هو الداعم والحامي. يصادق ويساعد عباده الصالحين. يدل هذا الاسم على قرب الله ودعمه. يعكس دوره كحارس وصديق لأولئك الذين يطلبون حمايته., الحميد هو الذي يستحق الثناء. صفاته وأفعاله تستحق كل الثناء. يعكس هذا الاسم استحقاق الله للشكر والإعجاب. يؤكد على طبيعته المستحقة للمديح والتكريم., المحصي هو الذي يُعرف عدد الأشياء. هو مدرك لجميع الكميات والمقاييس. يدل هذا الاسم على معرفة الله الشاملة بكل التفاصيل. يعكس قدرته على حساب كل شيء في الوجود., المبدع هو الذي بدأ الإنسان. يخلق بدون أي نموذج مسبق. يدل هذا الاسم على إبداع الله وأصالته في الخلق. يبرز دوره كخالق أصلي لكل الأشياء., المعيد هو الذي يعيد المخلوقات بعد الموت. يعيد الحياة ويحيي الأموات. يدل هذا الاسم على قدرة الله على الحياة والموت. يعكس قدرته على البعث وإعادة خلقه., المحيي هو الذي يحيي الميت. يحيي الحياة الجسدية والروحية. يدل هذا الاسم على دور الله في الخلق والحفاظ على الحياة. يبرز قدرته على منح وتجديد الحياة., المميت هو الذي يجعل الأحياء أمواتًا. له السيطرة على الحياة والموت. يدل هذا الاسم على قدرة الله على أخذ الحياة. يعكس سلطته على نهاية الحياة والانتقال إلى الآخرة., الحي هو الذي ينسب إليه الحياة التي تختلف عن حياتنا ولا تتكون من الروح أو اللحم أو الدم. يمتلك حياة أبدية ومستدامة. يدل هذا الاسم على وجود الله الفريد والأبدي. يعكس حيويته ومصدر الحياة ذاته., القيوم هو الذي يبقى ولا ينتهي. يدعم كل الأشياء بنفسه ولا يحتاج إلى أي دعم. يدل هذا الاسم على اكتفاء الله الذاتي واستقلاله. يعكس وجوده الأبدي ودوره كمحافظ على كل الخلق., الواجد هو الغني الذي لا يفتقر أبدًا. هو مكتفٍ ذاتيًا وغني بالثروات. يدل هذا الاسم على غنى الله وقدرته على توفير كل الاحتياجات. يعكس كماله واكتفاء صفاته., المجيد هو الأكثر مجدًا، الذي يتمتع بالقوة الكاملة. عظمته لا تضاهى ومتألقة. يدل هذا الاسم على عظمة الله وروعة صفاته. يعكس حضوره الجليل ومجد جوهره الإلهي., الواحد هو الواحد، الأبدي، المستقل. هو فريد ولا مثيل له. يدل هذا الاسم على وحدانية الله وتفرده. يعكس وحدته المطلقة واستقلاله عن كل الخلق., الأحد هو الذي لا شريك له، الفريد. لا يملك نظير أو منافس. يدل هذا الاسم على وحدة الله التي لا تتجزأ وتفرده. يعكس مكانته الحصرية كالإله الوحيد المستحق للعبادة., الصمد هو الأبدي، المستقل، السيد الذي يعتمد عليه. هو أبدي ولا يتغير. يدل هذا الاسم على طبيعة الله الأبدية ودوره كمصدر الدعم النهائي. يعكس ديمومته وثباته., القدير هو القادر، الذي ينسب إليه القوة. لديه القدرة على تحقيق كل الأشياء. يدل هذا الاسم على قدرة الله الشاملة وسلطته على جميع الأمور. يعكس قوته وسلطته اللامحدودة., المقتدر هو المسيطر، الذي يتمتع بالقوة الكاملة. سلطته مطلقة ولا تقاوم. يدل هذا الاسم على سيادة الله وقدرته على فرض إرادته. يعكس قوته العليا وسيطرته على جميع الخلق., المقدم هو الذي يقدم ويسرع. يعطي الأولوية ويسهل الأمور وفقًا لحكمته. يدل هذا الاسم على قدرة الله على التعجيل وتسريع الأحداث. يعكس قدرته على تحقيق النتائج بسرعة وحزم., المؤخر هو الذي يؤخر ويؤجل. يؤجل الأحداث وفقًا لخطته الإلهية. يدل هذا الاسم على حكمة الله في تأخير النتائج لأغراض أعظم. يعكس سيطرته على الوقت وقدرته على تحديد وتيرة الأحداث., الأول هو الأول، الذي كان موجودًا قبل كل شيء. هو الأصل ومصدر كل الخلق. يدل هذا الاسم على سبق الله ووجوده الذي لا يحده زمن. يعكس أسبقيته وبداية كل الأشياء., الآخر هو الآخر، الذي سيبقى بعد أن يفنى كل شيء. هو أبدي وأزلي. يدل هذا الاسم على ديمومة الله وحضوره بعد نهاية الزمان. يعكس نهايته والختام النهائي لكل الوجود., الظاهر هو الظاهر، الذي حضوره واضح وجلي. هو ظاهر ومرئي في آياته وخلقه. يدل هذا الاسم على وضوح الله وتجليه في الكون. يعكس وضوحه والعرض الواضح لصفاته., الباطن هو الباطن، الذي جوهره مخفي وغامض. هو ما وراء الإدراك البشري والفهم. يدل هذا الاسم على خفاء الله وطبيعته المخفية. يعكس تساميه وعمق جوهره الإلهي., الولي هو الحامي، الصديق الحامي الذي يرشد ويدعم عباده. هو حليفهم وحاميهم. يدل هذا الاسم على قرب الله ودوره كرفيق داعم. يعكس رعايته وإرشاده لأولئك الذين يطلبون حمايته., المتعالي هو المتعالي، الذي مقامه فوق المقارنة. هو مرفوع فوق كل خلقه. يدل هذا الاسم على تسامي الله ورفعة مكانته. يعكس تفوقه ورفعة جوهره الإلهي., البر هو مصدر الخير، الذي هو لطيف وكريم. يهب النعم والفوائد على خلقه. يدل هذا الاسم على صلاح الله وغناه بالرحمة. يعكس كرمه وغنى نعمه., التواب هو الذي يقبل التوبة ويغفر الذنوب. هو رحيم ورؤوف. يدل هذا الاسم على استعداد الله للمغفرة واستعداده لقبول من يتوب إليه. يعكس رحمته اللامحدودة ودعوته للعودة إليه., المنتقم هو المنتقم، الذي يعاقب الذين يتجاوزون حدوده. يفرض العدل والانتقام. يدل هذا الاسم على غضب الله تجاه الظلم والتزامه بتحقيق العدل. يعكس دوره كقاضي نهائي ومنفذ للعدل الإلهي., العفو هو العفو، الذي يعفو ويتجاوز عن الذنوب. يمحو الخطايا ويمنح الصفح. يدل هذا الاسم على رحمة الله واستعداده للعفو دون حقد. يعكس كرمه في الصفح عن عباده., الرؤوف هو الرؤوف، الذي هو عطوف ورحيم. يشعر بالشفقة على خلقه ويظهر لهم الرحمة. يدل هذا الاسم على لطف الله وطبيعته الرحيمة. يعكس تعاطفه واهتمامه برفاهية عباده., مالك الملك هو مالك الملك، الذي يمتلك السيادة على كل شيء. هو الحاكم النهائي والسلطة العليا. يدل هذا الاسم على مملكة الله وسيطرته المطلقة على الكون. يعكس سيادته وحقه في الحكم والإملاء., ذو الجلال والإكرام هو الذي يمتلك العظمة والكرامة. هو جليل ويستحق كل الاحترام والتكريم. يدل هذا الاسم على مقام الله الرفيع واستحقاقه للإجلال. يعكس كرامته، عظمته، والشرف الذي يستحقه., المقسط هو الذي يعدل في جميع أحكامه وأفعاله. يحافظ على التوازن والعدل في الكون. يدل هذا الاسم على التزام الله بالعدل والإنصاف. يعكس دوره في ضمان أن تكون جميع الأفعال مكافأة أو معاقبة بشكل مناسب., الجامع هو الذي يجمع ما يشاء، عندما يشاء. سيجمع جميع المخلوقات ليوم القيامة. يدل هذا الاسم على قدرة الله على الجمع والتوحيد. يعكس قدرته على جمع جميع الكائنات للمساءلة.,.الغني هو الذي هو غني عن كل حاجة. هو مكتفٍ بذاته ومستقل عن كل الخلق. يدل هذا الاسم على غنى الله وعدم حاجته لأي شيء خارجه. يعكس اكتفاءه الذاتي المطلق واستقلاله., المغني هو الذي يوفر الثروة والاكتفاء لمخلوقاته. يغني من يشاء. يدل هذا الاسم على كرم الله وقدرته على منح الرخاء. يعكس دوره في منح الوفرة والثروة لعباده., المانع هو الذي يمنع الضرر أو الشر من الحدوث. هو الحامي والمدافع. يدل هذا الاسم على قدرة الله على الحماية والوقاية من الخطر. يعكس دوره في حفظ خلقه من الضرر., الضار هو الذي يمكن أن يسبب الضرر أو المصيبة إذا شاء. له السيطرة على جميع الظروف. يدل هذا الاسم على قدرة الله على التحكم في المحن والصعاب. يعكس سلطته في جلب الاختبارات كاختبار أو عقاب., النافع هو الذي يجلب الفوائد والنعم. يمنح الخير والرفاهية. يدل هذا الاسم على دور الله في توفير وتسخير النتائج الإيجابية. يعكس قدرته على منح الفوائد والفضل., النور هو النور، الذي يضيء السماوات والأرض. يهدي ويوفر الوضوح. يدل هذا الاسم على دور الله كمصدر للهداية والتنوير. يعكس قدرته على جلب النور إلى الظلام والوضوح إلى الارتباك., الهادي هو الذي يهدي عباده إلى الطريق الصحيح. يوفر التوجيه والإلهام. يدل هذا الاسم على دور الله كمصدر للهداية والحكمة. يعكس قدرته على قيادة خلقه نحو الصواب والحقيقة., البديع هو الفريد، الذي يخلق بطرق لا مثيل لها وعجيبة. هو فريد في خلقه. يدل هذا الاسم على أصالة الله وقدرته الإبداعية التي لا مثيل لها. يعكس قدرته على الخلق بدون سابقة أو نموذج., الباقي هو الباقي، الذي يبقى عندما يفنى كل شيء آخر. هو أبدي ولا يتغير. يدل هذا الاسم على ديمومة الله ووجوده الذي يتجاوز الزمن. يعكس استمراريته وطبيعة كيانه الأبدية., الوارث هو الوارث، الذي يبقى بعد أن تنتهي كل الخلق. سيرث الأرض وكل ما عليها. يدل هذا الاسم على الملكية النهائية لله وحضوره الدائم. يعكس دوره كمالك نهائي لكل الأشياء., الرشيد هو المعلم الصالح، الذي يهدي إلى طريق الصلاح. يوفر الحكمة والفهم الصحيح. يدل هذا الاسم على دور الله كمعلم ومرشد. يعكس قدرته على قيادة عباده إلى المعرفة الصالحة والمفيدة., الصبور هو الصبور، الذي لا يعجل في معاقبة الخطاة. هو متسامح ومتساهل. يدل هذا الاسم على صبر الله وحلمه في تأخير العقاب. يعكس استعداده لإعطاء وقت للتوبة وتحمله في التعامل مع تجاوزات البشر."</string>


    <!--indonesian-->
    <string name="app_name_ind">99 Nama Allah</string>
    <string name="language_ind">Bahasa Indonesia</string>
    <string name="names_ind">"1. Ya Rahmanu,2.	Ya Raheemu,3.	Ya Maliku,4.	Ya Quddusu,5.	Ya Salamu,6.	Ya Mu\'minu,7.	Ya Muhayminu,8.	Ya Azizu,9.	Ya Jabbaaru,10.	Ya Mutakabbiru,11.	Ya Khaaliqu,12.	Ya Baariu,13.	Ya Musawwiru,14.	Ya Ghaffaaru,15.	Ya Qahhaaru,16.	Ya Wahhaabu,17.	Ya Razzaaqu,18.	Ya Fattaahu,19.	Ya Alimu,20.	Ya Qaabidhu,21.	Ya Baasitu,22.	Ya Khaafidhu,23.	Ya Raafi\'u,24.	Ya Mu\'izzu,25.	Ya Muzillu,26.	Ya Sami\'u,27.	Ya Basiru,28.	Ya Hakamu,29.	Ya \'Adlu,30.	Ya Latifu,31.	Ya Khabiru,32.	Ya Halimu,33.	Ya-‘Adheemu,34.	Ya Ghafuru,35.	Ya Shakuru,36.	Ya Aliu,37.	Ya Kabiru,38.	Ya Hafidhu,39.	Ya Muqitu,40.	Ya Hasibu,41.	Ya Jalilu,42.	Ya Karimu,43.	Ya Raqibu,44.	Ya Mujibu,45.	Ya Wasi\'u,46.	Ya Hakimu,47.	Ya Wadudu,48.	Ya Majeedu,49.	Ya Ba\'ithu,50.	Ya Shaheedu,51.	Ya Haqqu,52.	Ya Wakilu,53.	Ya Qawiyyu,54.	Ya Mateenu,55.	Ya Waliu,56.	Ya Hamiduu,57.	Ya Muhsi,58.	Ya Mubdiu,59.	Ya Mu\'idu,60.	Ya Muhyi,61.	Ya Mumitu,62.	Ya Hayyu,63.	Ya Qayyumu,64.	Ya Waajidu,65.	Ya Maajidu,66.	Ya Waahidu,67.	Ya Ahadu,68.	Ya Samadu,69.	Ya Qaadiru,70.	Ya Muqtadiru,71.	Ya Muqaddimu,72.	Ya Mu\'akhkhiru,73.	Ya Awwalu,74.	Ya Aakhiru,75.	Ya Dhaahiru,76.	Ya Baatinu,77.	Ya Waaliu,78.	Ya Muta\'ali,79.	Ya Barru,80.	Ya Tawwaabu,81.	Ya Muntaqimu,82.	Ya \'Afuwwu,83.	Ya Ra\'ufu,84.	Ya Malik Al Mulki,85.	Ya Jal-Jalali Al Ikram,86.	Ya Muqsitu,87.	Ya Jaami\'u,88.	Ya Ghaniu,89.	Ya Mughniu,90.	Ya Mani\'u,91.	Ya Dharru,92.	Ya Nafi\'u,93.	Ya Nuru,94.	Ya Hadiu,95.	Ya Badi\'iu,96.	Ya Baaqiu,97.	Ya Waarithu,98.	Ya Rashidu,99.	Ya Sabooru"</string>
    <string name="meaning_ind">"Yang Maha Pengasih,Yang Maha Penyayang,Tuhan yang Kekal,Yang Maha Suci,Perwujudan Damai,Pemberi Iman,Pelindung Keamanan,Yang Maha Perkasa,Yang Maha Kuasa,Yang Berkuasa,Yang Menciptakan,Yang Mengembangkan,Yang Membentuk Tanpa Cacat,Yang Maha Pengampun,Yang Maha Mengalahkan,Yang Maha Pemberi,Yang Maha Pemberi Rezeki,Yang Maha Penyelesai,Yang Maha Mengetahui,Yang Maha Menyempitkan,Yang Maha Meluaskan,Yang Maha Merendahkan,Yang Maha Meninggikan,Yang Memuliakan,Pemberi Kemuliaan,Yang Maha Mendengar,Yang Maha Melihat,Hakim Yang Adil,Perwujudan Keadilan,Yang Maha Mengetahui Hal-Hal Tersembunyi,Yang Maha Mengetahui,Yang Maha Penyantun,Yang Maha Agung,Yang Maha Pengampun,Yang Mengakui,Yang Maha Tinggi,Yang Maha Besar,Yang Maha Menjaga,Yang Maha Menjamin,Yang Maha Menghitung,Yang Maha Mulia,Yang Maha Dermawan,Yang Maha Mengawasi,Yang Maha Menjawab,Yang Maha Meliputi,Yang Maha Bijaksana,Yang Maha Pengasih,Yang Maha Mulia,Yang Pemberi Kehidupan Baru,Yang Maha Menyaksikan,Perwujudan Kebenaran,Yang Maha Mengawasi,Yang Kuat,Yang Teguh,Yang Melindungi,Yang Terpuji,Yang Maha Menghitung,Yang Maha Memulai,Yang Maha Mengembalikan,Pemelihara Kehidupan,Yang Maha Mematikan,Yang Hidup Abadi,Yang Maha Berdiri Sendiri,Yang Menunjukkan,Yang Maha Mulia,Yang Esa,Yang Tunggal,Penyedia Tertinggi,Yang Maha Kuasa,Yang Berkuasa Penuh,Yang Mempercepat,Yang Menunda,Yang Pertama,Yang Terakhir,Yang Terlihat,Yang Tak Terlihat,Yang Memiliki Kekuasaan Tertinggi,Yang Sangat Tinggi,Sumber Kebenaran,Penerima Tobat,Yang Membalas,Dzat Yang Maha Pemaaf,Yang Maha Lembut,Pemilik Kekuasaan Abadi,Yang Maha Memiliki Kebesaran dan Kemuliaan,Yang Adil,Yang Mengumpulkan Ciptaan Yang Terpisah,Yang Maha Mandiri,Pemberi Kecukupan,Yang Mencegah,Yang Memberi Kesusahan,Pemberi Manfaat,Cahaya Utama,Pemberi Petunjuk,Yang Unik,Yang Kekal,Yang Abadi,Pemberi Petunjuk ke Jalan yang Benar,Yang Sangat Bertahan Lama"</string>
    <string name="des_ind">"Ya Rahmanu adalah Yang Maha Pengasih... yang menghendaki kebaikan dan rahmat untuk semua makhluk-Nya. Dia menganugerahkan kasih karunia dan berkat yang besar kepada alam semesta... menunjukkan belas kasihan kepada semua makhluk. Rahmat-Nya sangat luas dan mencakup segala sesuatu... tanpa memandang iman atau perbuatan mereka. Nama ini mencerminkan perawatan penuh kasih Allah terhadap semua ciptaan-Nya.,Ya Raheemu adalah Yang Maha Penyayang... yang bertindak dengan kebaikan dan belas kasihan yang luar biasa... terutama kepada orang-orang beriman. Rahmat-Nya kekal dan terwujud baik di dunia ini maupun di Akhirat. Nama ini menandakan pengampunan Allah dan pahala yang Dia persiapkan untuk orang-orang beriman. Ini menekankan sifat lembut dan penuh belas kasih-Nya.,Ya Maliku adalah Raja yang berdaulat... Yang memiliki kekuasaan penuh atas alam semesta. Kekuasaan-Nya mutlak... dan otoritas-Nya sempurna dan bebas dari segala ketidaksempurnaan. Nama ini menggambarkan kekuatan dan kontrol Allah atas semua urusan... baik yang terlihat maupun yang tidak terlihat. Dia memerintah semua ciptaan dengan kebijaksanaan dan keadilan.,Ya Quddusu adalah Yang Maha Suci... yang bebas dari segala ketidaksempurnaan dan yang ditinggikan di atas semua cacat dan kelemahan. Dia bebas dari semua sifat yang menunjukkan kekurangan atau kelemahan. Nama ini menyoroti kesucian dan kemurnian Allah. Ini mencerminkan keagungan dan kesucian-Nya... yang melampaui pemahaman manusia.,Ya Salamu adalah Yang Maha Sejahtera... yang bebas dari segala ketidaksempurnaan dan memberikan kedamaian dan keamanan kepada ciptaan-Nya. Dia memberikan ketenangan kepada hati dan pikiran... memastikan keselamatan dan harmoni. Nama ini menandakan kesempurnaan Allah dan kedamaian yang datang dari kepatuhan kepada-Nya. Ini menekankan peran-Nya sebagai pemberi ketenangan.,Ya Mu\'minu adalah Yang Maha Pemberi Keamanan... yang memberikan rasa aman dan meneguhkan kebenaran orang-orang beriman. Dia menawarkan perlindungan dan kedamaian... melindungi mereka dari ketakutan dan bahaya. Nama ini menekankan peran Allah dalam memberikan keselamatan dan kepercayaan. Ini juga memastikan orang-orang beriman akan kebenaran iman mereka dan kenyataan janji-Nya.,Ya Muhayminu adalah Yang Maha Memelihara... yang mengawasi dan melindungi semua ciptaan-Nya... mengetahui tindakan dan pikiran mereka. Dia memelihara dan mengawasi segala sesuatu dengan pengetahuan dan otoritas yang sempurna. Nama ini mencerminkan kewaspadaan Allah dan pemeliharaan-Nya atas segala sesuatu. Ini memastikan orang-orang beriman akan perhatian dan kasih sayang-Nya yang terus-menerus.,Ya Azizu adalah Yang Maha Perkasa... Yang tidak terkalahkan. Dia tiada bandingannya dalam kekuatan dan kehormatan... mengalahkan semua musuh-Nya. Nama ini menggambarkan kekuatan dan ketidak terkalahkan Allah. Ini menunjukkan kemampuan-Nya untuk menang dan melindungi mereka yang mencari pertolongan-Nya.,Ya Jabbaaru adalah Yang Maha Memaksa dan Yang Maha Memulihkan... yang menjalankan kehendak-Nya atas ciptaan-Nya. Dia memperbaiki yang rusak dan memaksakan ketetapan-Nya atas segala sesuatu yang ada. Nama ini menandakan kekuasaan Allah untuk menegakkan perintah-Nya dan memperbaiki keadaan. Ini juga mencerminkan kemampuan-Nya untuk menyembuhkan dan mengembalikan keseimbangan.,Ya Mutakabbiru adalah Yang Maha Megah... yang bebas dari sifat-sifat makhluk dan dari menyerupai mereka... dan yang sangat agung. Hanya Dia yang memiliki kebesaran dan keagungan yang melampaui pemahaman. Nama ini menyoroti keunggulan dan transendensi Allah atas semua ciptaan. Ini menekankan status-Nya yang ditinggikan dan martabat dari esensi ilahi-Nya.,Ya Khaaliqu adalah Yang Maha Pencipta... yang membawa segala sesuatu dari tidak ada menjadi ada. Dia menciptakan segala sesuatu dengan presisi dan tujuan. Nama ini mencerminkan kemampuan Allah untuk menciptakan dan berinovasi. Ini menekankan peran-Nya sebagai Pencipta utama alam semesta dan segala isinya.,Ya Baariu adalah Yang Maha Membuat... Pencipta yang memiliki kekuatan untuk mengubah entitas menjadi berbagai keadaan. Dia mengeluarkan dan mengembangkan ciptaan-Nya sesuai dengan kebijaksanaan-Nya. Nama ini menandakan kreativitas Allah dan kemampuan-Nya untuk membentuk ciptaan-Nya dengan cara yang unik. Ini menyoroti peran-Nya dalam membentuk dan mengembangkan segala bentuk kehidupan.,Ya Musawwiru adalah Yang Maha Membentuk... yang membentuk ciptaan-Nya dalam berbagai bentuk dan rupa. Dia memberikan setiap ciptaan karakteristik dan atribut yang unik. Nama ini menekankan kekuatan artistik Allah dan perhatian terhadap detail dalam ciptaan. Ini mencerminkan kemampuan-Nya untuk merancang dan memberikan bentuk kepada semua makhluk.,Ya Ghaffaaru adalah Yang Maha Pengampun... yang mengampuni dosa hamba-hamba-Nya berulang kali. Pengampunan-Nya luas... mencakup bahkan dosa yang paling besar bagi mereka yang bertaubat. Nama ini menandakan rahmat Allah yang tak terbatas dan kesediaan-Nya untuk memaafkan. Ini menekankan kesiapan-Nya untuk mengampuni dan membersihkan mereka yang mencari pengampunan-Nya.,Ya Qahhaaru adalah Yang Maha Menundukkan... yang memiliki kekuasaan sempurna dan tidak ada yang tidak mampu atas-Nya. Dia menguasai dan menundukkan ciptaan-Nya sesuai kehendak-Nya. Nama ini menggambarkan kekuasaan dan dominasi mutlak Allah atas segala sesuatu. Ini mencerminkan kemampuan-Nya untuk menundukkan dan otoritas tertinggi-Nya.,Ya Wahhaabu adalah Yang Maha Pemberi... yang Memberi dengan murah hati tanpa mengharapkan imbalan. Dia menganugerahkan hadiah dan berkat dari kelimpahan dan kasih karunia-Nya. Nama ini menandakan kemurahan hati dan kebaikan Allah. Ini menyoroti peran-Nya sebagai pemberi segala yang bermanfaat... baik yang halal maupun yang haram.,Ya Razzaaqu adalah Yang Maha Pemberi Rezeki... yang menjamin penghidupan semua makhluk-Nya. Dia mendistribusikan rezeki dengan kebijaksanaan dan kemurahan hati. Nama ini menekankan peran Allah dalam memenuhi kebutuhan ciptaan-Nya. Ini menegaskan kasih sayang dan kebaikan-Nya dalam mempertahankan kehidupan.,Ya Fattaahu adalah Yang Maha Membuka... Yang Maha Menghilangkan Kesulitan... Yang Maha Menghakimi yang membuka bagi hamba-hamba-Nya urusan dunia dan agama yang tertutup. Dia memberikan kemenangan... kelegaan... dan solusi atas kesulitan. Nama ini menandakan kekuasaan Allah untuk menghilangkan rintangan dan memberikan petunjuk. Ini mencerminkan peran-Nya dalam mempermudah jalan dan menyelesaikan masalah.,Ya Alimu adalah Yang Maha Mengetahui; tidak ada sesuatu pun yang luput dari pengetahuan-Nya. Dia mengetahui segala sesuatu... masa lalu... masa kini... dan masa depan. Nama ini menekankan sifat maha tahu Allah dan pengetahuan sempurna-Nya tentang semua urusan. Ini menegaskan kesadaran dan pemahaman-Nya tentang semua ciptaan.,Ya Qaabidhu adalah Yang Maha Menyempitkan... yang menyempitkan rezeki dengan kebijaksanaan-Nya. Dia menahan rezeki sesuai dengan rencana ilahi-Nya. Nama ini menandakan kendali Allah atas distribusi sumber daya. Ini menekankan kebijaksanaan-Nya dalam menentukan apa yang terbaik untuk ciptaan-Nya.,Ya Baasitu adalah Yang Maha Melapangkan... yang meluaskan dan memperluas rezeki dengan kemurahan hati dan rahmat-Nya. Dia meningkatkan rezeki dan memberikan kelimpahan. Nama ini mencerminkan kebaikan dan kedermawanan Allah. Ini menekankan kemampuan-Nya untuk memperbesar dan memberkati ciptaan-Nya dengan sumber daya yang melimpah.,Ya Khaafidhu adalah Yang Maha Merendahkan... yang merendahkan siapa saja yang Dia kehendaki dengan kehancuran-Nya. Dia merendahkan mereka yang pantas untuk direndahkan. Nama ini menandakan keadilan Allah dan kekuasaan-Nya untuk merendahkan. Ini mencerminkan peran-Nya dalam menyeimbangkan keadilan dengan merendahkan yang sombong dan tidak adil.,Ya Raafi\'u adalah Yang Maha Meninggikan... yang meninggikan siapa saja yang Dia kehendaki dengan anugerah-Nya. Dia mengangkat derajat orang-orang yang saleh dan berbudi luhur. Nama ini menyoroti kemampuan Allah untuk memuliakan dan meninggikan. Ini mencerminkan kemurahan hati-Nya dalam memberikan derajat tinggi dan martabat kepada hamba-hamba-Nya yang setia.,Ya Mu\'izzu adalah Yang Maha Memuliakan... yang memberikan kemuliaan kepada siapa saja yang Dia kehendaki; sehingga tidak ada yang bisa merendahkannya. Dia menganugerahkan kehormatan dan martabat kepada orang-orang pilihan-Nya. Nama ini menandakan kekuasaan Allah untuk memuliakan dan meninggikan. Ini mencerminkan otoritas-Nya dalam memberikan penghargaan dan status.,Ya Muzillu adalah Yang Maha Menghinakan... yang merendahkan siapa saja yang Dia kehendaki; sehingga tidak ada yang bisa memberinya kemuliaan. Dia merendahkan orang-orang yang sombong dan tidak adil. Nama ini menekankan keadilan Allah dalam merendahkan yang tidak pantas. Ini mencerminkan kekuasaan-Nya untuk menghinakan dan merendahkan mereka yang menentang perintah-Nya.,Ya Sami\'u adalah Yang Maha Mendengar... yang mendengar segala sesuatu yang didengar dengan pendengaran-Nya yang kekal tanpa telinga... alat... atau organ. Dia mendengarkan doa dan permohonan ciptaan-Nya. Nama ini menandakan pendengaran sempurna dan menyeluruh Allah. Ini mencerminkan perhatian-Nya terhadap kebutuhan dan permohonan hamba-hamba-Nya.,Ya Basiru adalah Yang Maha Melihat... yang melihat segala sesuatu yang terlihat dengan penglihatan-Nya yang kekal tanpa pupil atau alat lainnya. Dia mengamati semua tindakan dan peristiwa di alam semesta. Nama ini menekankan visi maha hadir Allah. Ini mencerminkan kesadaran dan kewaspadaan-Nya terhadap semua ciptaan.,Ya Hakamu adalah Yang Maha Menghakimi... dan keputusan-Nya adalah firman-Nya. Dia menyelesaikan semua urusan dengan keadilan dan kebijaksanaan. Nama ini menandakan peran Allah sebagai arbiter dan hakim tertinggi. Ini menyoroti otoritas-Nya dalam membuat keputusan yang adil dan kata akhir-Nya dalam semua urusan.,Ya \'Adlu adalah Yang Maha Adil... yang berhak melakukan apa yang Dia lakukan. Tindakan dan keputusan-Nya adil dan seimbang. Nama ini mencerminkan keadilan dan keseimbangan sempurna Allah. Ini menekankan peran-Nya dalam menjaga keadilan dan kebenaran di alam semesta.,Ya Latifu adalah Yang Maha Lembut... yang baik kepada hamba-hamba-Nya dan menganugerahkan mereka. Dia memahami misteri dan seluk-beluk yang paling halus. Nama ini menandakan sifat lembut dan penuh kasih Allah. Ini menyoroti kebaikan-Nya dan cara-cara halus-Nya dalam memberikan rahmat dan kasih sayang.,Ya Khabiru adalah Yang Maha Waspada... yang mengetahui kebenaran segala sesuatu. Dia sepenuhnya menyadari semua hal yang tersembunyi dan yang tampak. Nama ini menekankan pengetahuan dan kesadaran mendalam Allah. Ini mencerminkan pemahaman-Nya tentang esensi sejati segala sesuatu.,Ya Halimu adalah Yang Maha Penyantun... yang menunda hukuman bagi mereka yang pantas mendapatkannya dan kemudian mungkin mengampuni mereka. Dia sabar dan lembut hati. Nama ini menandakan toleransi dan kesabaran Allah. Ini mencerminkan kesediaan-Nya untuk memberi waktu bagi pertobatan dan perbaikan.,Ya-\'Adheemu adalah Yang Maha Agung... yang berhak mendapat pemuliaan... kemuliaan... sanjungan... dan kemurnian dari segala ketidaksempurnaan. Dia agung dan megah dalam segala aspek. Nama ini menyoroti keagungan dan kemegahan Allah. Ini mencerminkan status-Nya yang ditinggikan dan penghormatan yang Dia pantas dapatkan.,Ya Ghafuru adalah Yang Maha Pengampun... yang banyak mengampuni. Pengampunan-Nya luas dan mencakup semua dosa bagi mereka yang bertaubat dengan tulus. Nama ini menandakan rahmat besar Allah dan kesiapan-Nya untuk memaafkan. Ini menekankan kemurahan hati-Nya dalam mengampuni dan melupakan kesalahan.,Ya Shakuru adalah Yang Maha Bersyukur... yang memberikan banyak pahala untuk ketaatan yang sedikit. Dia mengakui dan memberi penghargaan bahkan untuk tindakan kebaikan yang paling kecil. Nama ini mencerminkan kemurahan hati dan penghargaan Allah terhadap usaha hamba-hamba-Nya. Ini menyoroti kesediaan-Nya untuk melipatgandakan pahala untuk perbuatan baik.,Ya Aliu adalah Yang Maha Tinggi... yang jelas dari sifat-sifat makhluk. Dia ditinggikan di atas semua ciptaan. Nama ini menandakan status tertinggi dan transendensi Allah. Ini mencerminkan derajat-Nya yang tinggi dan kemurnian esensi ilahi-Nya.,Ya Kabiru adalah Yang Maha Besar... yang statusnya lebih tinggi dari segala sesuatu. Keagungan-Nya tak terbayangkan. Nama ini menekankan kebesaran Allah yang luar biasa. Ini menyoroti keunggulan-Nya atas segala yang ada.,Ya Hafidhu adalah Yang Maha Pelindung... yang melindungi apa dan siapa pun yang Dia kehendaki untuk dilindungi. Dia menjaga seluruh ciptaan dari bahaya. Nama ini menandakan peran Allah sebagai penjaga dan pelindung. Ini mencerminkan kemampuan-Nya untuk memelihara dan melindungi ciptaan-Nya.,Ya Muqitu adalah Yang Maha Memelihara... Yang Maha Memberi Makan... yang memiliki kekuasaan untuk memelihara segala sesuatu. Dia menyediakan rezeki dan mendukung semua kehidupan. Nama ini menyoroti peran Allah dalam menopang dan memberi makan ciptaan-Nya. Ini menekankan perhatian dan pemberian-Nya yang berkelanjutan.,Ya Hasibu adalah Yang Maha Memadai... yang memberikan kepuasan. Dia cukup sebagai pelindung dan pemberi perhitungan. Nama ini menandakan kemampuan Allah untuk menghitung semua tindakan dan perbuatan. Ini mencerminkan peran-Nya dalam memberikan ganjaran dan memastikan keadilan.,Ya Jalilu adalah Yang Maha Mulia... yang memiliki kekuasaan besar dan status yang mulia. Dia agung dan dihormati. Nama ini menyoroti kebesaran dan kemuliaan Allah. Ini mencerminkan status-Nya yang ditinggikan dan penghormatan yang Dia perintahkan.,Ya Karimu adalah Yang Maha Pemurah... yang memiliki kekuasaan besar dan status yang mulia. Dia murah hati dan baik hati. Nama ini menandakan kemurahan hati dan kebaikan Allah. Ini menyoroti kesediaan-Nya untuk memberi dan melimpahkan anugerah.,Ya Raqibu adalah Yang Maha Mengawasi... yang tidak ada sesuatu pun yang luput dari-Nya. Dia mengamati semua tindakan dan pikiran. Nama ini menekankan kewaspadaan dan kesadaran Allah. Ini mencerminkan kemampuan-Nya untuk memonitor dan mengawasi seluruh ciptaan.,Ya Mujibu adalah Yang Maha Mengabulkan... yang menjawab orang yang membutuhkan jika dia memohon kepada-Nya dan menyelamatkan orang yang merindukan jika dia memanggil-Nya. Dia menjawab doa dan permohonan. Nama ini menandakan kesediaan Allah untuk menjawab dan membantu. Ini menyoroti responsivitas-Nya terhadap seruan hamba-hamba-Nya.,Ya Wasi\'u adalah Yang Maha Luas... yang pengetahuan dan rahmat-Nya mencakup segala sesuatu. Dia tidak terbatas dalam atribut-Nya. Nama ini mencerminkan sifat Allah yang tak terbatas dan kasih sayang-Nya yang tanpa batas. Ini menekankan kemampuan-Nya untuk mencakup seluruh ciptaan dengan rahmat dan pengetahuan-Nya.,Ya Hakimu adalah Hakim yang Maha Adil... yang benar dalam segala perbuatan-Nya. Kebijaksanaan-Nya mengatur semua tindakan dan keputusan. Nama ini menandakan kebijaksanaan dan keputusan sempurna Allah. Ini menyoroti kemampuan-Nya untuk membuat keputusan yang adil dan bijaksana.,Ya Wadudu adalah Yang Maha Mengasihi... yang mencintai hamba-hamba-Nya yang beriman dan yang hamba-hamba-Nya yang beriman mencintai-Nya. Kasih-Nya terwujud dalam rahmat dan pujian-Nya untuk mereka. Nama ini mencerminkan kasih sayang dan kebaikan Allah terhadap hamba-hamba-Nya yang setia. Ini menekankan cinta timbal balik antara Pencipta dan ciptaan-Nya.,Ya Majeedu adalah Yang Maha Mulia... yang memiliki kekuasaan sempurna... status tinggi... kasih sayang... kemurahan hati... dan kebaikan. Dia agung dan terhormat. Nama ini menandakan kebesaran dan kebangsawanan Allah. Ini menyoroti posisi-Nya yang ditinggikan dan kemuliaan atribut-Nya.,Ya Ba\'ithu adalah Yang Maha Membangkitkan (dari kematian)... yang membangkitkan hamba-hamba-Nya setelah kematian untuk mendapatkan ganjaran dan/atau hukuman. Dia menghidupkan kembali yang mati. Nama ini menandakan kekuasaan Allah atas kehidupan dan kematian. Ini mencerminkan kemampuan-Nya untuk membangkitkan dan menghakimi semua makhluk.,Ya Shaheedu adalah Yang Maha Menyaksikan... yang tidak ada sesuatu pun yang luput dari-Nya. Dia menyaksikan semua tindakan dan peristiwa. Nama ini menekankan sifat maha hadir Allah dan peran-Nya sebagai saksi yang selalu ada. Ini mencerminkan kesadaran-Nya terhadap semua yang terjadi di alam semesta.,Ya Haqqu adalah Yang Maha Benar... yang benar-benar ada. Keberadaan-Nya mutlak dan abadi. Nama ini menandakan realitas dan keaslian Allah. Ini menekankan posisi-Nya sebagai kebenaran utama dan dasar dari semua keberadaan.,Ya Wakilu adalah Yang Maha Memadai... yang memberikan kepuasan dan dapat diandalkan. Dia adalah penjaga dan pelindung terbaik. Nama ini mencerminkan dapat diandalkannya dan kepercayaan kepada Allah. Ini menekankan peran-Nya sebagai tempat semua urusan dipercayakan.,Ya Qawiyyu adalah Yang Maha Kuat... yang memiliki kekuatan sempurna. Dia kuat dan berkuasa tanpa batas. Nama ini menandakan kekuatan dan otoritas Allah. Ini menyoroti kemampuan-Nya untuk mencapai segala sesuatu dan melindungi ciptaan-Nya.,Ya Mateenu adalah Yang Maha Kokoh... yang memiliki kekuatan yang sangat kuat dan tidak terganggu serta tidak pernah lelah. Kekuatan-Nya solid dan tak tergoyahkan. Nama ini mencerminkan keteguhan dan ketahanan Allah. Ini menekankan kekuatan-Nya yang abadi dan keteguhan.,Ya Waliu adalah Yang Maha Melindungi dan Penolong. Dia menjadi teman dan membantu hamba-hamba-Nya yang saleh. Nama ini menandakan kedekatan dan dukungan Allah. Ini mencerminkan peran-Nya sebagai penjaga dan sekutu bagi mereka yang mencari perlindungan-Nya.,Ya Hamiduu adalah Yang Maha Terpuji... yang layak dipuji. Atribut dan tindakan-Nya layak untuk semua pujian. Nama ini mencerminkan bahwa Allah layak untuk mendapatkan rasa syukur dan kekaguman. Ini menekankan sifat terpuji-Nya dan kehormatan yang pantas bagi-Nya.,Ya Muhsi adalah Yang Maha Menghitung... yang mengetahui jumlah segala sesuatu. Dia sadar akan semua kuantitas dan ukuran. Nama ini menandakan pengetahuan menyeluruh Allah tentang semua detail. Ini mencerminkan kemampuan-Nya untuk menghitung segala sesuatu yang ada.,Ya Mubdiu adalah Yang Maha Memulai... yang menciptakan manusia. Dia mencipta tanpa model sebelumnya. Nama ini menandakan inovasi dan orisinalitas Allah dalam penciptaan. Ini menyoroti peran-Nya sebagai pencipta awal dari segala sesuatu.,Ya Mu\'idu adalah Yang Maha Mengembalikan... yang mengembalikan makhluk setelah kematian. Dia menghidupkan kembali dan mengembalikan yang mati. Nama ini menandakan kekuasaan Allah atas kehidupan dan kematian. Ini mencerminkan kemampuan-Nya untuk membangkitkan dan mengembalikan ciptaan-Nya.,Ya Muhyi adalah Yang Maha Menghidupkan... yang memberikan kehidupan kepada yang tak bernyawa. Dia menghidupkan kembali kehidupan fisik dan spiritual. Nama ini menandakan peran Allah dalam menciptakan dan mempertahankan kehidupan. Ini menyoroti kemampuan-Nya untuk memberi dan memperbarui kehidupan.,Ya Mumitu adalah Yang Maha Mematikan... yang membuat makhluk hidup menjadi mati. Dia memiliki kendali atas kehidupan dan kematian. Nama ini menandakan kekuasaan Allah untuk mengambil nyawa. Ini mencerminkan otoritas-Nya atas akhir kehidupan dan transisi ke akhirat.,Ya Hayyu adalah Yang Maha Hidup... yang memiliki kehidupan yang tidak seperti kehidupan kita dan tidak terdiri dari jiwa... daging... atau darah. Dia memiliki kehidupan yang kekal dan mandiri. Nama ini menandakan keberadaan Allah yang unik dan abadi. Ini mencerminkan vitalitas-Nya dan sumber kehidupan itu sendiri.,Ya Qayyumu adalah Yang Maha Berdiri Sendiri... yang tetap ada dan tidak pernah berakhir. Dia menopang segala sesuatu dengan diri-Nya sendiri dan tidak memerlukan dukungan apapun. Nama ini menandakan kemandirian dan ketidakbergantungan Allah. Ini mencerminkan keberadaan-Nya yang kekal dan peran-Nya sebagai pemelihara semua ciptaan.,Ya Waajidu adalah Yang Maha Menemukan... Yang Maha Kaya yang tidak pernah miskin. Dia mandiri dan kaya dalam segala hal. Nama ini menandakan kekayaan Allah dan kemampuan-Nya untuk memenuhi semua kebutuhan. Ini mencerminkan kesempurnaan-Nya dan kecukupan atribut-Nya.,Ya Maajidu adalah Yang Maha Mulia... Dia yang memiliki kekuasaan sempurna. Kebesaran-Nya tidak tertandingi dan bersinar. Nama ini menandakan keagungan dan kemuliaan Allah. Ini mencerminkan kehadiran-Nya yang agung dan kemuliaan dari esensi ilahi-Nya.,Ya Waahidu adalah Yang Maha Esa... Yang Kekal... Yang Mandiri. Dia tunggal dan tak tertandingi. Nama ini menandakan keesaan dan keunikan Allah. Ini mencerminkan kesatuan absolut-Nya dan ketidakbergantungan dari segala ciptaan.,Ya Ahadu adalah Yang Maha Tunggal tanpa sekutu... Yang Unik. Dia tidak memiliki yang setara atau saingan. Nama ini menandakan kesatuan yang tak terpisahkan dan singularitas Allah. Ini mencerminkan status eksklusif-Nya sebagai satu-satunya tuhan yang layak disembah.,Ya Samadu adalah Yang Maha Kekal... Yang Mandiri... Tuan yang diandalkan. Dia kekal dan tak berubah. Nama ini menandakan sifat kekal Allah dan peran-Nya sebagai sumber dukungan tertinggi. Ini mencerminkan ketetapan dan ketahanan-Nya.,Ya Qaadiru adalah Yang Maha Kuasa... yang memiliki kekuasaan. Dia memiliki kemampuan untuk mencapai segala sesuatu. Nama ini menandakan kemahakuasaan Allah dan kendali-Nya atas semua urusan. Ini mencerminkan kekuatan dan otoritas-Nya yang tak terbatas.,Ya Muqtadiru adalah Yang Maha Berkuasa... yang memiliki kekuasaan sempurna. Otoritas-Nya mutlak dan tak tertahankan. Nama ini menandakan kedaulatan Allah dan kemampuan-Nya untuk menegakkan kehendak-Nya. Ini mencerminkan kekuatan dan kendali tertinggi-Nya atas semua ciptaan.,Ya Muqaddimu adalah Yang Maha Memajukan dan Mempercepat. Dia memprioritaskan dan memfasilitasi urusan sesuai dengan kebijaksanaan-Nya. Nama ini menandakan kemampuan Allah untuk mempercepat dan mempercepat kejadian. Ini mencerminkan kekuatan-Nya untuk menghasilkan hasil dengan cepat dan tegas.,Ya Mu\'akhkhiru adalah Yang Maha Menunda dan Menangguhkan. Dia menunda kejadian sesuai dengan rencana ilahi-Nya. Nama ini menandakan kebijaksanaan Allah dalam menunda hasil untuk tujuan yang lebih besar. Ini mencerminkan kendali-Nya atas waktu dan kemampuan-Nya untuk menentukan kecepatan kejadian.,Ya Awwalu adalah Yang Maha Awal... yang ada sebelum segala sesuatu. Dia adalah asal dan sumber dari semua ciptaan. Nama ini menandakan keutamaan Allah dan keberadaan-Nya yang tak terbatas oleh waktu. Ini mencerminkan primasi-Nya dan permulaan dari segala sesuatu.,Ya Aakhiru adalah Yang Maha Akhir... yang akan tetap ada setelah segala sesuatu berakhir. Dia kekal dan abadi. Nama ini menandakan ketetapan Allah dan keberadaan-Nya melampaui akhir waktu. Ini mencerminkan finalitas-Nya dan kesimpulan tertinggi dari segala keberadaan.,Ya Dhaahiru adalah Yang Maha Nyata... yang kehadirannya jelas dan terang. Dia terlihat dan nyata dalam tanda-tanda dan ciptaan-Nya. Nama ini menandakan keterlihatan Allah dan manifestasi-Nya dalam alam semesta. Ini mencerminkan kejelasan-Nya dan tampilan atribut-Nya yang nyata.,Ya Baatinu adalah Yang Maha Tersembunyi... yang esensinya tersembunyi dan misterius. Dia melampaui persepsi dan pemahaman manusia. Nama ini menandakan ketidaklihatan Allah dan sifat-Nya yang tersembunyi. Ini mencerminkan transendensi-Nya dan kedalaman esensi ilahi-Nya.,Ya Waaliu adalah Pelindung... Teman yang Melindungi yang membimbing dan mendukung hamba-hamba-Nya. Dia adalah sekutu dan penjaga mereka. Nama ini menandakan kedekatan Allah dan peran-Nya sebagai teman yang mendukung. Ini mencerminkan perhatian dan bimbingan-Nya bagi mereka yang mencari perlindungan-Nya.,Ya Muta\'ali adalah Yang Maha Tinggi... yang statusnya tak tertandingi. Dia ditinggikan di atas segala ciptaan. Nama ini menandakan transendensi Allah dan peringkat-Nya yang tinggi. Ini mencerminkan keunggulan-Nya dan keagungan esensi ilahi-Nya.,Ya Barru adalah Sumber Kebaikan... yang baik hati dan dermawan. Dia melimpahkan berkah dan anugerah kepada ciptaan-Nya. Nama ini menandakan kebaikan Allah dan rahmat-Nya yang melimpah. Ini mencerminkan kemurahan hati-Nya dan kelimpahan berkah-Nya.,Ya Tawwaabu adalah Yang Maha Menerima Tobat... yang menerima tobat dan mengampuni dosa. Dia penuh rahmat dan belas kasih. Nama ini menandakan kesediaan Allah untuk mengampuni dan kesiapan-Nya untuk menerima mereka yang bertaubat kepada-Nya. Ini mencerminkan rahmat-Nya yang tak terbatas dan undangan-Nya untuk kembali kepada-Nya.,Ya Muntaqimu adalah Yang Maha Pembalas... yang menghukum mereka yang melampaui batas-Nya. Dia menegakkan keadilan dan pembalasan. Nama ini menandakan murka Allah terhadap kejahatan dan komitmen-Nya untuk menegakkan keadilan. Ini mencerminkan peran-Nya sebagai hakim tertinggi dan pelaksana keadilan ilahi.,Ya \'Afuwwu adalah Yang Maha Pemaaf... yang memaafkan dan mengabaikan kesalahan. Dia menghapus dosa dan memberikan pengampunan. Nama ini menandakan rahmat Allah dan kesediaan-Nya untuk memaafkan tanpa menyimpan dendam. Ini mencerminkan kemurahan hati-Nya dalam memaafkan hamba-hamba-Nya.,Ya Ra\'ufu adalah Yang Maha Belas Kasih... yang lembut dan penyayang. Dia merasakan empati terhadap ciptaan-Nya dan menunjukkan belas kasihan kepada mereka. Nama ini menandakan kelembutan Allah dan sifat penyayang-Nya. Ini mencerminkan simpati dan kepedulian-Nya terhadap kesejahteraan hamba-hamba-Nya.,Ya Malik Al Mulki adalah Pemilik Kekuasaan... yang memiliki kekuasaan atas segala sesuatu. Dia adalah penguasa dan otoritas tertinggi. Nama ini menandakan kerajaan Allah dan kendali-Nya yang mutlak atas alam semesta. Ini mencerminkan kedaulatan-Nya dan hak-Nya untuk memerintah dan memutuskan.,Ya Jal-Jalali Al Ikram adalah Yang Maha Memiliki Keagungan dan Kemuliaan. Dia agung dan layak untuk dihormati dan dihargai. Nama ini menandakan status Allah yang ditinggikan dan kelayakan-Nya untuk mendapatkan penghormatan. Ini mencerminkan martabat-Nya... keagungan-Nya... dan kehormatan yang layak bagi-Nya.,Ya Muqsitu adalah Yang Maha Adil... yang adil dalam semua penilaian dan tindakan-Nya. Dia menjaga keseimbangan dan keadilan di alam semesta. Nama ini menandakan komitmen Allah terhadap keadilan dan kejujuran. Ini mencerminkan peran-Nya dalam memastikan bahwa semua perbuatan diberi ganjaran atau hukuman yang sesuai.,Ya Jaami\'u\' adalah Yang Maha Mengumpulkan... yang mengumpulkan apa yang Dia kehendaki... kapan Dia kehendaki. Dia akan mengumpulkan semua makhluk untuk Hari Penghakiman. Nama ini menandakan kemampuan Allah untuk mengumpulkan dan menyatukan. Ini mencerminkan kekuasaan-Nya untuk mengumpulkan semua makhluk untuk pertanggungjawaban.,Ya Ghaniu adalah Yang Maha Kaya... yang bebas dari segala kebutuhan. Dia mandiri dan tidak bergantung pada semua ciptaan. Nama ini menandakan kekayaan Allah dan ketidakbutuhan-Nya akan apapun di luar diri-Nya. Ini mencerminkan kecukupan dan ketidakbergantungan-Nya yang mutlak.,Ya Mughniu adalah Yang Maha Memberi Kekayaan... yang menyediakan kekayaan dan kecukupan kepada makhluk-Nya. Dia memperkaya siapa yang Dia kehendaki. Nama ini menandakan kemurahan hati Allah dan kemampuan-Nya untuk memberikan kemakmuran. Ini mencerminkan peran-Nya dalam memberikan kelimpahan dan kekayaan kepada hamba-hamba-Nya.,Ya Mani\'u\' adalah Yang Maha Mencegah... yang mencegah bahaya atau kejahatan terjadi. Dia adalah pelindung dan pembela. Nama ini menandakan kemampuan Allah untuk melindungi dan melindungi dari bahaya. Ini mencerminkan peran-Nya dalam menjaga ciptaan-Nya dari bahaya.,Ya Dharru adalah Yang Maha Mendatangkan Bahaya... yang dapat mendatangkan bahaya atau kesengsaraan jika Dia kehendaki. Dia memiliki kendali atas semua keadaan. Nama ini menandakan kekuasaan Allah atas kesulitan dan penderitaan. Ini mencerminkan otoritas-Nya untuk mendatangkan ujian atau hukuman sebagai ujian atau pembalasan.,Ya Nafi\'u adalah Yang Maha Memberi Manfaat... yang mendatangkan manfaat dan berkah. Dia memberikan kebaikan dan kesejahteraan. Nama ini menandakan peran Allah dalam menyediakan dan memfasilitasi hasil yang positif. Ini mencerminkan kemampuan-Nya untuk memberikan manfaat dan anugerah.,Ya Nuru adalah Cahaya... yang menerangi langit dan bumi. Dia membimbing dan memberikan kejelasan. Nama ini menandakan peran Allah sebagai sumber petunjuk dan pencerahan. Ini mencerminkan kemampuan-Nya untuk membawa cahaya ke dalam kegelapan dan kejelasan ke dalam kebingungan.,Ya Hadiu adalah Yang Maha Membimbing... yang membimbing hamba-hamba-Nya ke jalan yang benar. Dia memberikan arahan dan inspirasi. Nama ini menandakan peran Allah sebagai sumber petunjuk dan kebijaksanaan. Ini mencerminkan kemampuan-Nya untuk memimpin ciptaan-Nya menuju kebenaran dan kebaikan.,Ya Badi\'iu adalah Yang Maha Pencipta yang Tiada Bandingannya... yang menciptakan dengan cara yang tak tertandingi dan menakjubkan. Dia unik dalam ciptaan-Nya. Nama ini menandakan keaslian Allah dan kekuatan kreatif-Nya yang tak tertandingi. Ini mencerminkan kemampuan-Nya untuk menciptakan tanpa preseden atau model.,Ya Baaqiu adalah Yang Maha Kekal... yang tetap ada ketika semua yang lain binasa. Dia kekal dan tak berubah. Nama ini menandakan ketetapan Allah dan keberadaan-Nya yang melampaui waktu. Ini mencerminkan kesinambungan-Nya dan sifat kekal dari keberadaan-Nya.,Ya Waarithu adalah Yang Maha Pewaris... yang tetap ada setelah semua ciptaan berakhir. Dia akan mewarisi bumi dan segala isinya. Nama ini menandakan kepemilikan terakhir Allah dan kehadiran-Nya yang abadi. Ini mencerminkan peran-Nya sebagai pemilik akhir dari segala sesuatu.,Ya Rashidu adalah Guru yang Benar... yang membimbing ke jalan kebenaran. Dia memberikan kebijaksanaan dan pemahaman yang benar. Nama ini menandakan peran Allah sebagai guru dan pembimbing. Ini mencerminkan kemampuan-Nya untuk memimpin hamba-hamba-Nya kepada pengetahuan yang benar dan bermanfaat.,Ya Sabooru adalah Yang Maha Sabar... yang tidak tergesa-gesa menghukum orang berdosa. Dia penyabar dan toleran. Nama ini menandakan kesabaran Allah dan kesabaran-Nya dalam menunda hukuman. Ini mencerminkan kesediaan-Nya untuk memberikan waktu untuk bertaubat dan ketahanan-Nya dalam menghadapi pelanggaran manusia."</string>

    <!--    spanish-->
    <string name="app_name_sp">99 Nombres de Alá</string>
    <string name="language_sp">Español</string>
    <string name="names_sp">"1. Ya Rahmanu,2.	Ya Raheemu,3.	Ya Maliku,4.	Ya Quddusu,5.	Ya Salamu,6.	Ya Mu\'minu,7.	Ya Muhayminu,8.	Ya Azizu,9.	Ya Jabbaaru,10.	Ya Mutakabbiru,11.	Ya Khaaliqu,12.	Ya Baariu,13.	Ya Musawwiru,14.	Ya Ghaffaaru,15.	Ya Qahhaaru,16.	Ya Wahhaabu,17.	Ya Razzaaqu,18.	Ya Fattaahu,19.	Ya Alimu,20.	Ya Qaabidhu,21.	Ya Baasitu,22.	Ya Khaafidhu,23.	Ya Raafi\'u,24.	Ya Mu\'izzu,25.	Ya Muzillu,26.	Ya Sami\'u,27.	Ya Basiru,28.	Ya Hakamu,29.	Ya \'Adlu,30.	Ya Latifu,31.	Ya Khabiru,32.	Ya Halimu,33.	Ya-‘Adheemu,34.	Ya Ghafuru,35.	Ya Shakuru,36.	Ya Aliu,37.	Ya Kabiru,38.	Ya Hafidhu,39.	Ya Muqitu,40.	Ya Hasibu,41.	Ya Jalilu,42.	Ya Karimu,43.	Ya Raqibu,44.	Ya Mujibu,45.	Ya Wasi\'u,46.	Ya Hakimu,47.	Ya Wadudu,48.	Ya Majeedu,49.	Ya Ba\'ithu,50.	Ya Shaheedu,51.	Ya Haqqu,52.	Ya Wakilu,53.	Ya Qawiyyu,54.	Ya Mateenu,55.	Ya Waliu,56.	Ya Hamiduu,57.	Ya Muhsi,58.	Ya Mubdiu,59.	Ya Mu\'idu,60.	Ya Muhyi,61.	Ya Mumitu,62.	Ya Hayyu,63.	Ya Qayyumu,64.	Ya Waajidu,65.	Ya Maajidu,66.	Ya Waahidu,67.	Ya Ahadu,68.	Ya Samadu,69.	Ya Qaadiru,70.	Ya Muqtadiru,71.	Ya Muqaddimu,72.	Ya Mu\'akhkhiru,73.	Ya Awwalu,74.	Ya Aakhiru,75.	Ya Dhaahiru,76.	Ya Baatinu,77.	Ya Waaliu,78.	Ya Muta\'ali,79.	Ya Barru,80.	Ya Tawwaabu,81.	Ya Muntaqimu,82.	Ya \'Afuwwu,83.	Ya Ra\'ufu,84.	Ya Malik Al Mulki,85.	Ya Jal-Jalali Al Ikram,86.	Ya Muqsitu,87.	Ya Jaami\'u,88.	Ya Ghaniu,89.	Ya Mughniu,90.	Ya Mani\'u,91.	Ya Dharru,92.	Ya Nafi\'u,93.	Ya Nuru,94.	Ya Hadiu,95.	Ya Badi\'iu,96.	Ya Baaqiu,97.	Ya Waarithu,98.	Ya Rashidu,99.	Ya Sabooru"</string>

    <string name="meaning_sp">"El Benefactor,El Misericordioso,El Señor Eterno,El Más Sagrado,La Encarnación de la Paz,El Infusor de Fe,El Preservador de la Seguridad,El Poderoso,El Omnipotente,El Dominante,El Creador,El Evolucionador,El Formador Perfecto,El Gran Perdoador,El Todo-Poderoso,El Supremo Dador,El Proveedor Total,El Supremo Solucionador,El Omnisciente,El Reductor,El Extensor,El Disminuidor,El Elevador,El Honrador-Dador,El Humillador,El Oyente,El Vidente,El Juez Imparcial,La Encarnación de la Justicia,El Conocedor de Sutilezas,El Conocedor de Todo,El Clemente,El Magnífico,El Gran Perdoador,El Reconocedor,El Sublime,El Grande,El Guardián,El Sustentador,El Contador,El Majestuoso,El Generoso,El Vigilante,El Respondedor,El Todo-Penetrante,El Sabio,El Amoroso,El Glorioso,El Infusor de Nueva Vida,El Testigo Observador,La Encarnación de la Verdad,El Fiduciario Universal,El Fuerte,El Firme,El Protector Asociado,El Digno de Alabanza,El Enumerador,El Originador,El Restaurador,El Mantenedor de la Vida,El Infusor de Muerte,El Eternamente Vivo,El Auto-Subsistente,El Indicador,El Noble,El Único,El Supremo Proveedor,El Omnipotente,El Autoritario,El Expedidor,El Procrastinador,El Muy Primero,El Infinito Último,El Perceptible,El Imperceptible,El Poseedor de Autoridad Suprema,El Exaltado,La Fuente de la Verdad,El Siempre Aceptador del Arrepentimiento,El Vengador,El Supremo Perdonador,El Benigno,El Eterno Poseedor de la Soberanía,El Poseedor de Majestad y Honor,El Justo,El Recolector de Creaciones Dispersas,El Autosuficiente,El Donador de Suficiencia,El Preventor,El Causador de Angustia,El Donador de Beneficios,La Luz Principal,El Proveedor de Guía,El Único,El Siempre Viviente,El Heredero Eterno,El Guía hacia el Camino de la Rectitud,El Muy Duradero"</string>
    <string name="des_sp">"Ya Rahmanu es el que quiere la bondad y la misericordia para todas sus criaturas. Él otorga inmensa gracia y bendiciones al universo... mostrando compasión a todos los seres. Su misericordia es vasta y abarca todas las cosas... independientemente de su fe o acciones. Este nombre refleja el cuidado nutritivo de Alá para toda la creación., Ya Raheemu es el que actúa con extrema bondad y compasión... particularmente hacia los creyentes. Su misericordia es eterna y se manifiesta tanto en este mundo como en el más allá. Este nombre significa el perdón de Alá y las recompensas que prepara para los fieles. Enfatiza su naturaleza gentil y compasiva., Ya Maliku es el Señor Soberano... el que tiene dominio completo sobre el universo. Su gobierno es absoluto y su autoridad es perfecta y libre de cualquier imperfección. Este nombre ilustra el poder y control de Alá sobre todas las cosas... tanto visibles como invisibles. Él gobierna toda la creación con sabiduría y justicia., Ya Quddusu es el que está libre de cualquier imperfección y es exaltado por encima de todos los defectos y debilidades. Está libre de todos los atributos que impliquen defecto o deficiencia. Este nombre resalta la pureza y santidad de Alá. Refleja su trascendencia y santidad... siendo incomprensible para el ser humano., Ya Salamu es el que está libre de toda imperfección y otorga paz y seguridad a su creación. Él concede tranquilidad a los corazones y mentes... asegurando seguridad y armonía. Este nombre significa la perfección de Alá y la paz que proviene de la sumisión a Él. Subraya su papel como el dador de serenidad., Ya Mu\'minu es el que proporciona seguridad y afirma la verdad de sus fieles creyentes. Ofrece protección y paz... protegiéndolos del miedo y el daño. Este nombre enfatiza el papel de Alá en proporcionar seguridad y confianza. También asegura a los creyentes la verdad de su fe y la realidad de sus promesas., Ya Muhayminu es el que vigila y protege a toda su creación... conociendo sus acciones y pensamientos. Él mantiene y supervisa todas las cosas con perfecto conocimiento y autoridad. Este nombre refleja la vigilancia de Alá y su guardianía sobre todo. Asegura a los creyentes su constante cuidado y atención., Ya Azizu es el que es poderoso y fuerte... el vencedor que no es vencido. Es inigualable en poder y honor... superando a todos sus enemigos. Este nombre ilustra la fuerza e invencibilidad de Alá. Muestra su capacidad para prevalecer y proteger a aquellos que buscan su ayuda., Ya Jabbaaru es el que obliga y restaura... ejerciendo su voluntad sobre su creación. Él repara lo roto e impone su decreto sobre todo lo que existe. Este nombre significa el poder de Alá para imponer sus mandatos y rectificar asuntos. También refleja su capacidad para curar y restaurar el equilibrio., Ya Mutakabbiru es el que está libre de los atributos de las criaturas y de parecerse a ellas... y que es supremamente grande. Solo él posee grandeza y majestad incomprensibles. Este nombre resalta la superioridad y trascendencia de Alá sobre toda la creación. Enfatiza su estatus exaltado y la dignidad de su esencia divina., Ya Khaaliqu es el que trae todo de la inexistencia a la existencia. Crea todas las cosas con precisión y propósito. Este nombre refleja la capacidad de Alá para originar e innovar la creación. Subraya su papel como el Creador supremo del universo y todo lo que contiene., Ya Baariu es el Hacedor... el Creador que tiene el poder de transformar entidades en diferentes estados. Él da lugar y evoluciona su creación según su sabiduría. Este nombre significa la creatividad de Alá y su capacidad para formar sus criaturas de maneras únicas. Resalta su papel en moldear y desarrollar todas las formas de vida., Ya Musawwiru es el que forma sus criaturas en diferentes formas y figuras. Él da a cada creación sus características y atributos únicos. Este nombre enfatiza el poder artístico de Alá y su atención al detalle en la creación. Refleja su capacidad para diseñar y dar forma a todos los seres., Ya Ghaffaaru es el que perdona los pecados de sus siervos una y otra vez. Su perdón es vasto... cubriendo incluso los pecados más graves de aquellos que se arrepienten. Este nombre significa la misericordia ilimitada de Alá y su disposición a perdonar. Subraya su disposición a perdonar y limpiar a aquellos que buscan su perdón., Ya Qahhaaru es el Dominante... el que tiene el poder perfecto y no es incapaz de nada. Él domina y somete a su creación según su voluntad. Este nombre ilustra el control absoluto de Alá y su dominio sobre todas las cosas. Refleja su capacidad para someter y su autoridad suprema., Ya Wahhaabu es el que es Generoso al dar en abundancia sin ningún retorno. Él concede dones y bendiciones de su generosidad y gracia. Este nombre significa la generosidad y bondad de Alá. Resalta su papel como el dador de todo lo que beneficia... ya sea lícito o prohibido.,Ya Razzaaqu es el Sustentador... el Proveedor que asegura el sustento de todas sus criaturas. Él distribuye provisiones con sabiduría y generosidad. Este nombre enfatiza el papel de Alá en proporcionar para las necesidades de su creación. Subraya su cuidado y benevolencia en sustentar la vida., Ya Fattaahu es el que abre... el que alivia... el Juez que abre para sus siervos los asuntos mundanos y religiosos cerrados. Él concede victoria... alivio y soluciones a las dificultades. Este nombre significa el poder de Alá para eliminar obstáculos y proporcionar guía. Refleja su papel en facilitar caminos y resolver problemas., Ya Alimu es el Conocedor; el que nada está ausente de su conocimiento. Él está al tanto de todas las cosas... pasadas... presentes y futuras. Este nombre enfatiza la omnisciencia de Alá y su perfecto conocimiento de todos los asuntos. Subraya su conciencia y comprensión de toda la creación., Ya Qaabidhu es el que constriñe el sustento con su sabiduría. Él retiene provisiones de acuerdo con su plan divino. Este nombre significa el control de Alá sobre la distribución de recursos. Resalta su sabiduría en determinar lo que es mejor para su creación., Ya Baasitu es el que expande y ensancha el sustento con su generosidad y misericordia. Él aumenta las provisiones y concede abundancia. Este nombre refleja la bondad y liberalidad de Alá. Enfatiza su capacidad para aumentar y bendecir a su creación con recursos abundantes., Ya Khaafidhu es el que humilla a quien él quiere con su destrucción. Él baja a los que merecen ser humillados. Este nombre significa la justicia de Alá y su poder para abatir. Refleja su papel en equilibrar la justicia al bajar a los arrogantes e injustos., Ya Raafi\'u es el Elevador... el que eleva a quien él quiere con su dádiva. Él eleva el estatus de los justos y virtuosos. Este nombre destaca la capacidad de Alá para honrar y exaltar. Refleja su generosidad al otorgar altos rangos y dignidad a sus fieles siervos., Ya Mu\'izzu es el que da estima a quien él quiere; por lo tanto... no hay nadie que lo degrade. Él otorga honor y dignidad a sus elegidos. Este nombre significa el poder de Alá para honrar y elevar. Refleja su autoridad al otorgar respeto y estatus., Ya Muzillu es el Humillador... el que degrada a quien él quiere; por lo tanto... no hay nadie que le dé estima. Él baja a los arrogantes e injustos. Este nombre enfatiza la justicia de Alá al humillar a los indignos. Refleja su poder para humillar y abatir a aquellos que desafían sus mandatos., Ya Sami\'u es el que escucha todas las cosas que se escuchan con su oído eterno sin oreja... instrumento u órgano. Él escucha las oraciones y súplicas de su creación. Este nombre significa la perfecta y comprensiva audición de Alá. Refleja su atención a las necesidades y plegarias de sus siervos., Ya Basiru es el que ve todas las cosas que se ven con su vista eterna sin pupila ni ningún otro instrumento. Él observa todas las acciones y eventos en el universo. Este nombre enfatiza la visión omnipresente de Alá. Refleja su conciencia y vigilancia sobre toda la creación., Ya Hakamu es el Gobernante... y su juicio es su palabra. Él resuelve todos los asuntos con justicia y sabiduría. Este nombre significa el papel de Alá como el árbitro y juez supremo. Destaca su autoridad para tomar decisiones justas y su palabra final en todos los asuntos., Ya \'Adlu es el que tiene derecho a hacer lo que hace. Sus acciones y juicios son justos y equitativos. Este nombre refleja la perfecta justicia y equilibrio de Alá. Subraya su papel en mantener la equidad y rectitud en el universo., Ya Latifu es el Gracioso... el que es amable con sus siervos y les otorga favores. Él comprende los más finos misterios e intricacias. Este nombre significa la naturaleza gentil y compasiva de Alá. Destaca su bondad y sus sutiles maneras de otorgar gracia y misericordia., Ya Khabiru es el que conoce la verdad de las cosas. Él está completamente al tanto de todos los asuntos ocultos y aparentes. Este nombre enfatiza el profundo conocimiento y conciencia de Alá. Refleja su comprensión de la verdadera esencia de todas las cosas., Ya Halimu es el que retrasa el castigo para aquellos que lo merecen y luego puede perdonarlos. Él es paciente e indulgente. Este nombre significa la tolerancia y paciencia de Alá. Refleja su disposición a dar tiempo para el arrepentimiento y la corrección., Ya-\'Adheemu es el Poderoso... el que merece exaltación... gloria... alabanza y pureza de toda imperfección. Él es majestuoso y grandioso en todos los aspectos. Este nombre destaca la grandeza y majestad de Alá. Refleja su estatus exaltado y la reverencia que merece., Ya Ghafuru es el Perdonador... el que perdona mucho. Su perdón es extenso y cubre todos los pecados de aquellos que se arrepienten sinceramente. Este nombre significa la inmensa misericordia de Alá y su disposición a perdonar. Enfatiza su gracia al perdonar y pasar por alto las faltas., Ya Shakuru es el que da mucha recompensa por poca obediencia. Él reconoce y recompensa incluso los actos más pequeños de bondad. Este nombre refleja la generosidad y apreciación de Alá por los esfuerzos de sus siervos. Destaca su disposición a multiplicar las recompensas por las buenas obras., Ya Aliu es el que está libre de los atributos de las criaturas. Él está exaltado por encima de toda la creación. Este nombre significa el estatus supremo y la trascendencia de Alá. Refleja su alto rango y la pureza de su esencia divina.,Ya Kabiru es el Grande... el que es mayor que todo en estatus. Su grandeza es incomprensible. Este nombre enfatiza la inmensa grandeza de Alá. Resalta su superioridad sobre todo lo que existe., Ya Hafidhu es el Protector... el que protege lo que y a quien él quiere proteger. Él salvaguarda a toda su creación del daño. Este nombre significa el papel de Alá como guardián y preservador. Refleja su capacidad para mantener y proteger a su creación., Ya Muqitu es el Guardián... el Alimentador... el que tiene el poder de mantener todas las cosas. Él proporciona sustento y apoya toda la vida. Este nombre destaca el papel de Alá en sostener y nutrir a su creación. Enfatiza su continuo cuidado y provisión., Ya Hasibu es el que da satisfacción. Él es suficiente como protector y contador. Este nombre significa la capacidad de Alá para contabilizar todas las acciones y hechos. Refleja su papel en proporcionar recompensa y asegurar justicia., Ya Jalilu es el Benefactor... el que es atribuido con grandeza de poder y gloria de estatus. Él es majestuoso y reverenciado. Este nombre destaca la grandeza y majestad de Alá. Refleja su estatus exaltado y la reverencia que comanda., Ya Karimu es el Bondadoso... el que es atribuido con grandeza de poder y gloria de estatus. Él es generoso y amable. Este nombre significa la generosidad y benevolencia de Alá. Resalta su disposición a dar y otorgar favores., Ya Raqibu es el que nada está ausente de Él. Él observa todas las acciones y pensamientos. Este nombre enfatiza la vigilancia y conciencia de Alá. Refleja su capacidad para monitorear y supervisar toda la creación., Ya Mujibu es el Respondedor... el que responde a quien está en necesidad si le pide y rescata al anhelante si le llama. Él responde a las oraciones y súplicas. Este nombre significa la disposición de Alá para responder y asistir. Resalta su capacidad de responder a las llamadas de sus siervos., Ya Wasi\'u es el Infinito... el que cuyo conocimiento y misericordia abarcan todas las cosas. Él es ilimitado en sus atributos. Este nombre refleja la naturaleza infinita y la compasión sin límites de Alá. Enfatiza su capacidad para abarcar toda la creación con su gracia y conocimiento., Ya Hakimu es el Juez de Jueces... el que es correcto en sus acciones. Su sabiduría gobierna todas las acciones y decretos. Este nombre significa la perfecta sabiduría y juicio de Alá. Resalta su capacidad para tomar decisiones justas y sabias., Ya Wadudu es el que ama a sus siervos creyentes y cuyos creyentes le aman a Él. Su amor se manifiesta en su misericordia y alabanza para ellos. Este nombre refleja el afecto y la bondad de Alá hacia sus fieles siervos. Enfatiza el amor recíproco entre el Creador y su creación., Ya Majeedu es el que tiene perfecto poder... alto estatus... compasión... generosidad y bondad. Él es majestuoso y honorable. Este nombre significa la grandeza y nobleza de Alá. Resalta su posición exaltada y la gloria de sus atributos., Ya Ba\'ithu es el que Resucita (de la muerte)... el que resucita a sus siervos después de la muerte para recompensa y/o castigo. Él devuelve la vida a los muertos. Este nombre significa el poder de Alá sobre la vida y la muerte. Refleja su capacidad para traer la resurrección y juzgar a todos los seres., Ya Shaheedu es el que nada está ausente de Él. Él es testigo de todas las acciones y eventos. Este nombre enfatiza la omnipresencia de Alá y su papel como testigo siempre presente. Refleja su conciencia de todo lo que ocurre en el universo., Ya Haqqu es el Verdadero... el que verdaderamente existe. Su existencia es absoluta y eterna. Este nombre significa la realidad y autenticidad de Alá. Enfatiza su posición como la verdad última y fundamento de toda existencia., Ya Wakilu es el que da satisfacción y en quien se confía. Él es el mejor guardián y fiduciario. Este nombre refleja la confiabilidad y la confianza en Alá. Enfatiza su papel como el que se encarga de todos los asuntos., Ya Qawiyyu es el Fuerte... el que tiene completo poder. Él es poderoso y fuerte más allá de toda medida. Este nombre significa la fuerza y autoridad de Alá. Resalta su capacidad para lograr todas las cosas y proteger su creación., Ya Mateenu es el que tiene un poder extremo que es ininterrumpido y no se cansa. Su fuerza es sólida e inquebrantable. Este nombre refleja la firmeza y la resiliencia de Alá. Enfatiza su poder duradero y constancia., Ya Waliu es el Apoyo y protector. Él se hace amigo y ayuda a sus siervos justos. Este nombre significa la cercanía y el apoyo de Alá. Refleja su papel como guardián y aliado de aquellos que buscan su protección., Ya Hamiduu es el Alabado... el que merece ser alabado. Sus atributos y acciones son dignos de toda alabanza. Este nombre refleja la merecedora gratitud y admiración de Alá. Enfatiza su naturaleza digna de alabanza y el honor que se le debe., Ya Muhsi es el que conoce la cuenta de todas las cosas. Él está al tanto de todas las cantidades y medidas. Este nombre significa el conocimiento integral de Alá de todos los detalles. Refleja su capacidad para contabilizar todo en la existencia., Ya Mubdiu es el que inició al ser humano. Él crea sin ningún modelo preexistente. Este nombre significa la innovación y originalidad de Alá en la creación. Resalta su papel como el creador inicial de todas las cosas., Ya Mu\'idu es el que devuelve a las criaturas después de la muerte. Él restaura la vida y revive a los muertos. Este nombre significa el poder de Alá sobre la vida y la muerte. Refleja su capacidad para resucitar y devolver a su creación., Ya Muhyi es el que da vida a lo inerte. Él revive tanto la vida física como espiritual. Este nombre significa el papel de Alá en crear y sostener la vida. Resalta su capacidad para otorgar y renovar la vida.,Ya Mumitu es el que hace que los vivos mueran. Él tiene control sobre la vida y la muerte. Este nombre significa el poder de Alá para quitar la vida. Refleja su autoridad sobre el fin de la vida y la transición al más allá., Ya Hayyu es el que tiene una vida que no es como la nuestra y no es una combinación de alma... carne o sangre. Posee una vida eterna y autosuficiente. Este nombre significa la existencia única y eterna de Alá. Refleja su vitalidad y la fuente misma de la vida., Ya Qayyumu es el que permanece y no termina. Él sostiene todas las cosas por sí mismo y no requiere ningún apoyo. Este nombre significa la autosuficiencia e independencia de Alá. Refleja su existencia eterna y su papel como el sustentador de toda la creación., Ya Waajidu es el Hallador... el Rico que nunca es pobre. Él es autosuficiente y abundante en riqueza. Este nombre significa la riqueza de Alá y su capacidad para proveer todas las necesidades. Refleja su plenitud y la suficiencia de sus atributos., Ya Maajidu es el Más Glorioso... el que tiene un poder perfecto. Su grandeza es inigualable y radiante. Este nombre significa la magnificencia y esplendor de Alá. Refleja su presencia majestuosa y la gloria de su esencia divina., Ya Waahidu es el Único... el Eterno... el Independiente. Él es singular e incomparable. Este nombre significa la unidad y singularidad de Alá. Refleja su absoluta unidad e independencia de toda la creación., Ya Ahadu es el Único sin compañero... el Único. No tiene igual ni rival. Este nombre significa la indivisible unidad y singularidad de Alá. Refleja su estatus exclusivo como la única deidad digna de adoración., Ya Samadu es el Eterno... el Independiente... el Maestro en quien se confía. Él es eterno e inmutable. Este nombre significa la naturaleza eterna de Alá y su papel como la fuente última de apoyo. Refleja su permanencia y constancia., Ya Qaadiru es el Capaz... el que tiene poder. Él tiene la capacidad de lograr todas las cosas. Este nombre significa la omnipotencia de Alá y su control sobre todos los asuntos. Refleja su poder y autoridad ilimitados., Ya Muqtadiru es el Dominante... el que tiene poder completo. Su autoridad es absoluta e irresistible. Este nombre significa la soberanía de Alá y su capacidad para imponer su voluntad. Refleja su suprema fuerza y control sobre toda la creación., Ya Muqaddimu es el que adelanta y acelera. Él prioriza y facilita los asuntos según su sabiduría. Este nombre significa la capacidad de Alá para apresurar y acelerar los eventos. Refleja su poder para traer resultados rápida y decisivamente., Ya Mu\'akhkhiru es el que retrasa y difiere. Él pospone los eventos según su plan divino. Este nombre significa la sabiduría de Alá en retrasar los resultados para un propósito mayor. Refleja su control sobre el tiempo y su capacidad para determinar el ritmo de los eventos., Ya Awwalu es el Primero... el que existió antes de todo lo demás. Él es el origen y la fuente de toda la creación. Este nombre significa la precedencia de Alá y su existencia intemporal. Refleja su primacía y el comienzo de todas las cosas., Ya Aakhiru es el Último... el que permanecerá después de que todo lo demás haya perecido. Él es eterno y perdurable. Este nombre significa la permanencia de Alá y su presencia más allá del fin del tiempo. Refleja su finalidad y la conclusión última de toda existencia., Ya Dhaahiru es el Manifiesto... el que cuya presencia es evidente y clara. Él es aparente y visible en sus signos y creaciones. Este nombre significa la visibilidad de Alá y su manifestación en el universo. Refleja su claridad y la demostración evidente de sus atributos., Ya Baatinu es el Oculto... el que cuya esencia está oculta y misteriosa. Él está más allá de la percepción y comprensión humanas. Este nombre significa la invisibilidad de Alá y su naturaleza oculta. Refleja su trascendencia y la profundidad de su esencia divina., Ya Waaliu es el Patrón... el Amigo Protector que guía y apoya a sus siervos. Él es su aliado y guardián. Este nombre significa la cercanía de Alá y su papel como compañero de apoyo. Refleja su cuidado y guía para aquellos que buscan su protección., Ya Muta\'ali es el Supremamente Exaltado... el que tiene un estatus incomparable. Él está elevado por encima de toda la creación. Este nombre significa la trascendencia de Alá y su rango exaltado. Refleja su superioridad y la elevación de su esencia divina., Ya Barru es la Fuente de Bondad... el que es amable y benevolente. Él otorga bendiciones y favores a su creación. Este nombre significa la bondad de Alá y su abundante gracia. Refleja su generosidad y la abundancia de sus bendiciones., Ya Tawwaabu es el Siempre-Volvente... el que acepta el arrepentimiento y perdona los pecados. Él es misericordioso y compasivo. Este nombre significa la disposición de Alá para perdonar y su disposición para aceptar a aquellos que se vuelven a Él en arrepentimiento. Refleja su misericordia infinita y su invitación a regresar a Él., Ya Muntaqimu es el Vengador... el que castiga a los que transgreden sus límites. Él impone justicia y retribución. Este nombre significa la ira de Alá contra la maldad y su compromiso de mantener la justicia. Refleja su papel como el juez supremo y ejecutor de la justicia divina., Ya \'Afuwwu es el Perdonador... el que perdona y pasa por alto las faltas. Él borra los pecados y otorga absolución. Este nombre significa la misericordia de Alá y su disposición para perdonar sin guardar rencor. Refleja su generosidad al perdonar a sus siervos., Ya Ra\'ufu es el Compasivo... el que es tierno y misericordioso. Él siente empatía por su creación y les muestra compasión. Este nombre significa la ternura y la naturaleza misericordiosa de Alá. Refleja su simpatía y preocupación por el bienestar de sus siervos., Ya Malik Al Mulki es el Dueño de la Soberanía... el que posee el dominio sobre todas las cosas. Él es el gobernante y autoridad última. Este nombre significa la realeza de Alá y su control absoluto sobre el universo. Refleja su soberanía y su derecho a mandar y decretar., Ya Jal-Jalali Al Ikram es el que posee grandeza y nobleza. Él es majestuoso y digno de todo honor y respeto. Este nombre significa el estatus exaltado de Alá y su dignidad. Refleja su magnificencia y el honor que se le debe.,Ya Muqsitu es el que es justo y equitativo en todos Sus juicios y acciones. Él mantiene el equilibrio y la equidad en el universo. Este nombre significa el compromiso de Alá con la justicia y la equidad. Refleja Su papel en garantizar que todos los actos sean recompensados o castigados apropiadamente., Ya Jaami\'u\' es el que reúne lo que Él quiere... cuando Él quiere. Reunirá a todas las criaturas para el Día del Juicio. Este nombre significa la capacidad de Alá para reunir y unir. Refleja Su poder para reunir a todos los seres para la rendición de cuentas., Ya Ghaniu es el que no necesita de nada. Él es autosuficiente e independiente de toda la creación. Este nombre significa la riqueza de Alá y Su falta de necesidad de cualquier cosa fuera de Sí mismo. Refleja Su absoluta suficiencia e independencia., Ya Mughniu es el que proporciona riqueza y suficiencia a Sus criaturas. Él enriquece a quien quiere. Este nombre significa la generosidad de Alá y Su capacidad para otorgar prosperidad. Refleja Su papel en conceder abundancia y riqueza a Sus siervos., Ya Mani\'u\' es el que previene que el daño o el mal ocurran. Él es el protector y el defensor. Este nombre significa la capacidad de Alá para proteger y resguardar del peligro. Refleja Su papel en salvaguardar Su creación del daño., Ya Dharru es el que puede causar daño o aflicción si Él quiere. Él tiene control sobre todas las circunstancias. Este nombre significa el poder de Alá sobre la adversidad y la dificultad. Refleja Su autoridad para provocar pruebas como un test o castigo., Ya Nafi\'u es el que trae beneficios y bendiciones. Él otorga bondad y bienestar. Este nombre significa el papel de Alá en proveer y facilitar resultados positivos. Refleja Su capacidad para conceder beneficios y favores., Ya Nuru es la Luz... el que ilumina los cielos y la tierra. Él guía y proporciona claridad. Este nombre significa el papel de Alá como fuente de guía y iluminación. Refleja Su capacidad para llevar luz a la oscuridad y claridad a la confusión., Ya Hadiu es el que guía a Sus siervos por el camino correcto. Él proporciona dirección e inspiración. Este nombre significa el papel de Alá como fuente de guía y sabiduría. Refleja Su capacidad para llevar a Su creación hacia la rectitud y la verdad., Ya Badi\'iu es el Incomparable... el que crea de manera inigualable y maravillosa. Él es único en Su creación. Este nombre significa la originalidad de Alá y Su poder creativo sin igual. Refleja Su capacidad para crear sin precedentes ni modelos., Ya Baaqiu es el Eterno... el que permanece cuando todo lo demás perece. Él es eterno e inmutable. Este nombre significa la permanencia de Alá y Su existencia más allá del tiempo. Refleja Su continuidad y la naturaleza eterna de Su ser., Ya Waarithu es el Heredero... el que permanece después de que toda la creación ha llegado a su fin. Él heredará la tierra y todo lo que hay en ella. Este nombre significa la propiedad última de Alá y Su presencia perdurable. Refleja Su papel como el poseedor final de todas las cosas., Ya Rashidu es el Maestro Justo... el que guía por el camino de la rectitud. Él proporciona sabiduría y entendimiento correcto. Este nombre significa el papel de Alá como maestro y guía. Refleja Su capacidad para llevar a Sus siervos al conocimiento recto y beneficioso., Ya Sabooru es el Paciente... el que no se apresura a castigar a los pecadores. Él es indulgente y tolerante. Este nombre significa la paciencia de Alá y Su contención al demorar el castigo. Refleja Su disposición para dar tiempo para el arrepentimiento y Su resistencia al tratar con las transgresiones humanas."</string>

    <!--    french-->
    <string name="app_name_fr">99 Noms d\'Allah</string>
    <string name="language_fr">Français</string>
    <string name="names_fr">"1. Ya Rahmanu,2.	Ya Raheemu,3.	Ya Maliku,4.	Ya Quddusu,5.	Ya Salamu,6.	Ya Mu\'minu,7.	Ya Muhayminu,8.	Ya Azizu,9.	Ya Jabbaaru,10.	Ya Mutakabbiru,11.	Ya Khaaliqu,12.	Ya Baariu,13.	Ya Musawwiru,14.	Ya Ghaffaaru,15.	Ya Qahhaaru,16.	Ya Wahhaabu,17.	Ya Razzaaqu,18.	Ya Fattaahu,19.	Ya Alimu,20.	Ya Qaabidhu,21.	Ya Baasitu,22.	Ya Khaafidhu,23.	Ya Raafi\'u,24.	Ya Mu\'izzu,25.	Ya Muzillu,26.	Ya Sami\'u,27.	Ya Basiru,28.	Ya Hakamu,29.	Ya \'Adlu,30.	Ya Latifu,31.	Ya Khabiru,32.	Ya Halimu,33.	Ya-‘Adheemu,34.	Ya Ghafuru,35.	Ya Shakuru,36.	Ya Aliu,37.	Ya Kabiru,38.	Ya Hafidhu,39.	Ya Muqitu,40.	Ya Hasibu,41.	Ya Jalilu,42.	Ya Karimu,43.	Ya Raqibu,44.	Ya Mujibu,45.	Ya Wasi\'u,46.	Ya Hakimu,47.	Ya Wadudu,48.	Ya Majeedu,49.	Ya Ba\'ithu,50.	Ya Shaheedu,51.	Ya Haqqu,52.	Ya Wakilu,53.	Ya Qawiyyu,54.	Ya Mateenu,55.	Ya Waliu,56.	Ya Hamiduu,57.	Ya Muhsi,58.	Ya Mubdiu,59.	Ya Mu\'idu,60.	Ya Muhyi,61.	Ya Mumitu,62.	Ya Hayyu,63.	Ya Qayyumu,64.	Ya Waajidu,65.	Ya Maajidu,66.	Ya Waahidu,67.	Ya Ahadu,68.	Ya Samadu,69.	Ya Qaadiru,70.	Ya Muqtadiru,71.	Ya Muqaddimu,72.	Ya Mu\'akhkhiru,73.	Ya Awwalu,74.	Ya Aakhiru,75.	Ya Dhaahiru,76.	Ya Baatinu,77.	Ya Waaliu,78.	Ya Muta\'ali,79.	Ya Barru,80.	Ya Tawwaabu,81.	Ya Muntaqimu,82.	Ya \'Afuwwu,83.	Ya Ra\'ufu,84.	Ya Malik Al Mulki,85.	Ya Jal-Jalali Al Ikram,86.	Ya Muqsitu,87.	Ya Jaami\'u,88.	Ya Ghaniu,89.	Ya Mughniu,90.	Ya Mani\'u,91.	Ya Dharru,92.	Ya Nafi\'u,93.	Ya Nuru,94.	Ya Hadiu,95.	Ya Badi\'iu,96.	Ya Baaqiu,97.	Ya Waarithu,98.	Ya Rashidu,99.	Ya Sabooru"</string>

    <string name="meaning_fr">"Le Bienfaiteur,Le Miséricordieux,Le Seigneur Éternel,Le Très Saint,L\'Incarnation de la Paix,Le Donneur de Foi,Le Préservateur de la Sécurité,Le Puissant,Le Tout-Puissant,Le Dominant,Le Créateur,L\'Évolueur,Le Façonneur Parfait,Le Grand Pardonneur,Le Tout-Prévalant,Le Donateur Suprême,Le Pourvoyeur Total,Le Résolveur Suprême,Le Tout-Sachant,Le Réducteur,Le Réducteur,Le Diminuteur,Le Supérieur,Le Honoreur-Donneur,L\'Abaisseur,L\'Auditeur,Le Voyant,Le Juge Impartial,L\'Incarnation de la Justice,Le Connaisseur des Subtilités,Le Tout-Connaissant,Le Clément,Le Magnifique,Le Grand Pardonneur,Le Reconnaissant,Le Sublime,Le Grand,Le Gardien,Le Sustenteur,Le Comptable,Le Majestueux,Le Généreux,Le Vigilant,Le Répondant,Le Tout-Pervasif,Le Sage,Le Bien-Aimé,Le Glorieux,Le Donneur de Nouvelle Vie,Le Témoignant,Le Véritable,Le Fiduciaire Universel,Le Fort,Le Ferme,Le Protecteur Associé,Le Louable Unique,Le Compteur,Le Créateur,Le Restaurateur,Le Mainteneur de la vie,Le Donneur de Mort,Le Vivant Éternel,Le Subsistant par Lui-même,Le Pointeur,Le Noble,Le Seul,Le Unique,Le Fournisseur Suprême,Le Tout-Puissant,L\'Autorité Suprême,Le Hâtif,Le Procrastinateur,Le Très Premier,Le Très Dernier,L\'Apparent,L\'Inapparent,Le Détenteur de l\'Autorité Suprême,Le Très Élevé,La Source de Vérité,Le Très Acceptateur de Repentance,Le Vengeur,Le Pardonneur Suprême,Le Bienveillant,Le Possesseur Éternel de la Souveraineté,Le Possesseur de Majesté et d\'Honneur,Le Juste,Le Rassembleur des Créations Éparpillées,Le Suffisant,Le Donneur de Suffisance,Le Préventeur,Le Détresseur,Le Donneur de Bénéfices,La Lumière Principale,Le Guide,Le Unique,Le Éternel,Le Héritier Éternel,Le Guide vers le Chemin de la Rectitude,Le Très Endurant"</string>
    <string name="des_fr">"Ya Rahmanu est Celui qui veut le bien et la miséricorde pour toutes Ses créatures. Il accorde une immense grâce et des bénédictions à l\'univers... montrant de la compassion à tous les êtres. Sa miséricorde est vaste et englobe toutes choses... indépendamment de leur foi ou de leurs actes. Ce nom reflète le soin nourricier d\'Allah pour toute la création.,Ya Raheemu est Celui qui agit avec une extrême bonté et compassion... en particulier envers les croyants. Sa miséricorde est éternelle et se manifeste à la fois dans ce monde et dans l\'Au-delà. Ce nom signifie le pardon d\'Allah et les récompenses qu\'Il prépare pour les fidèles. Il souligne Sa nature douce et compatissante.,Ya Maliku est le Seigneur Souverain... Celui qui a la domination complète sur l\'univers. Son règne est absolu... et Son autorité est parfaite et exempte de toute imperfection. Ce nom illustre la puissance et le contrôle d\'Allah sur toutes les affaires... visibles et invisibles. Il gouverne toute la création avec sagesse et justice.,Ya Quddusu est Celui qui est pur de toute imperfection et exalté au-dessus de tous les défauts et faiblesses. Il est exempt de tous les attributs qui impliquent un défaut ou une insuffisance. Ce nom met en lumière la pureté et la sainteté d\'Allah. Il reflète Sa transcendance et Sa sainteté... étant au-delà de la compréhension humaine.,Ya Salamu est Celui qui est exempt de toute imperfection et qui accorde la paix et la sécurité à Sa création. Il procure la tranquillité aux cœurs et aux esprits... assurant sécurité et harmonie. Ce nom signifie la perfection d\'Allah et la paix qui découle de la soumission à Lui. Il souligne Son rôle en tant que donneur de sérénité.,Ya Mu\'minu est Celui qui fournit la sécurité et confirme la vérité de Ses croyants fidèles. Il offre protection et paix... les protégeant de la peur et du mal. Ce nom met en avant le rôle d\'Allah dans la fourniture de sécurité et de confiance. Il assure également aux croyants la vérité de leur foi et la réalité de Ses promesses.,Ya Muhayminu est Celui qui veille sur toute Sa création... connaissant leurs actions et pensées. Il maintient et supervise toutes choses avec une connaissance et une autorité parfaites. Ce nom reflète la vigilance d\'Allah et Sa garde sur tout. Il assure aux croyants Son soin constant et Son attention.,Ya Azizu est Celui qui est puissant et fort... le Vainqueur qui n\'est pas vaincu. Il est incomparable en puissance et en honneur... surpassant tous Ses ennemis. Ce nom illustre la force et l\'invincibilité d\'Allah. Il montre Sa capacité à prévaloir et à protéger ceux qui cherchent Son aide.,Ya Jabbaaru est Celui qui contraint et restaure... exerçant Sa volonté sur Sa création. Il répare les brisés et impose Son décret sur tout ce qui existe. Ce nom signifie la capacité d\'Allah à faire appliquer Ses commandements et à rectifier les affaires. Il reflète également Sa capacité à guérir et à rétablir l\'équilibre.,Ya Mutakabbiru est Celui qui est clair des attributs des créatures et de leur ressemblance... et qui est suprêmement grand. Lui seul possède la grandeur et la majesté au-delà de toute compréhension. Ce nom met en avant la supériorité et la transcendance d\'Allah sur toute la création. Il souligne Son statut exalté et la dignité de Son essence divine.,Ya Khaaliqu est Celui qui fait passer toute chose du non-être à l’existence. Il crée toutes choses avec précision et but. Ce nom reflète la capacité d\'Allah à originer et à innover la création. Il souligne Son rôle en tant que Créateur ultime de l\'univers et de tout ce qu\'il contient.,Ya Baariu est le Fabricant... le Créateur qui a le pouvoir de transformer les entités en différents états. Il fait surgir et évolue Sa création selon Sa sagesse. Ce nom signifie la créativité d\'Allah et Sa capacité à former Ses créatures de manière unique. Il met en avant Son rôle dans la formation et le développement de toutes les formes de vie.,Ya Musawwiru est Celui qui façonne Ses créatures en différentes formes et figures. Il donne à chaque création ses caractéristiques et attributs uniques. Ce nom souligne le pouvoir artistique d\'Allah et son attention aux détails dans la création. Il reflète Sa capacité à concevoir et à donner forme à tous les êtres.,Ya Ghaffaaru est Celui qui pardonne les péchés de Ses serviteurs encore et encore. Son pardon est vaste... couvrant même les péchés les plus graves pour ceux qui se repentent. Ce nom signifie la miséricorde infinie d\'Allah et Sa volonté de pardonner. Il souligne Sa disposition à pardonner et à purifier ceux qui cherchent Son pardon.,Ya Qahhaaru est le Dominant... Celui qui a le pouvoir parfait et qui n’est incapable de rien. Il domine et soumet Sa création comme Il le veut. Ce nom illustre le contrôle absolu et la domination d\'Allah sur toutes choses. Il reflète Sa capacité à soumettre et Son autorité suprême.,Ya Wahhaabu est Celui qui est Généreux en donnant en abondance sans rien attendre en retour. Il accorde des dons et des bénédictions de Sa grâce. Ce nom signifie la générosité et la bonté d\'Allah. Il met en avant Son rôle en tant que donneur de tout ce qui est bénéfique... que ce soit licite ou interdit.,Ya Razzaaqu est le Soutien... le Pourvoyeur qui assure la subsistance de toutes Ses créatures. Il distribue les provisions avec sagesse et générosité. Ce nom souligne le rôle d\'Allah en fournissant aux besoins de Sa création. Il met en avant Son soin et Sa bienveillance en soutenant la vie.,Ya Fattaahu est l\'Ouvert... le Libérateur... le Juge qui ouvre pour Ses serviteurs les affaires mondaines et religieuses fermées. Il accorde victoire... soulagement et solutions aux difficultés. Ce nom signifie le pouvoir d\'Allah à lever les obstacles et à fournir des orientations. Il reflète Son rôle dans le fait de faciliter les chemins et de résoudre les problèmes.,Ya Alimu est le Savant; Celui dont rien n\'échappe à Sa connaissance. Il est conscient de toutes choses... passées... présentes et futures. Ce nom souligne l\'omniscience d\'Allah et Sa connaissance parfaite de toutes les affaires. Il met en avant Sa conscience et Sa compréhension de toute la création.,Ya Qaabidhu est Celui qui restreint la subsistance par Sa sagesse. Il retient les provisions selon Son plan divin. Ce nom signifie le contrôle d\'Allah sur la distribution des ressources. Il met en avant Sa sagesse dans la détermination de ce qui est le mieux pour Sa création.,Ya Baasitu est Celui qui élargit et augmente la subsistance avec Sa générosité et Sa miséricorde. Il accroît les provisions et accorde l\'abondance. Ce nom reflète la bonté et la libéralité d\'Allah. Il met en avant Sa capacité à agrandir et à bénir Sa création avec des ressources abondantes.,Ya Khaafidhu est Celui qui abaisse ceux qu\'Il veut par Sa destruction. Il rabaisse ceux qui méritent d\'être humiliés. Ce nom signifie la justice d\'Allah et Son pouvoir d\'abaisser. Il reflète Son rôle dans l\'équilibrage des balances de la justice en abaissant les arrogants et les injustes.,Ya Raafi\'u est l\'Élévateur... Celui qui élève ceux qu\'Il veut par Ses dons. Il élève le statut des justes et des vertueux. Ce nom souligne la capacité d\'Allah à honorer et à exalter. Il reflète Sa générosité en accordant des rangs élevés et de la dignité à Ses serviteurs fidèles.,Ya Mu\'izzu est Celui qui donne de l\'estime à qui Il veut; il n\'y a donc personne pour le dégrader. Il accorde honneur et dignité à Ses élus. Ce nom signifie le pouvoir d\'Allah à honorer et à élever. Il reflète Son autorité en accordant respect et statut.,Ya Muzillu est l\'Humiliateur... Celui qui dégrade ceux qu\'Il veut; il n\'y a donc personne pour lui donner de l\'estime. Il rabaisse les arrogants et les injustes. Ce nom souligne la justice d\'Allah en abaissant ceux qui ne le méritent pas. Il reflète Son pouvoir d\'humilier et d\'abaisser ceux qui défient Ses commandements.,Ya Sami\'u est Celui qui entend toutes les choses qui sont entendues par Son ouïe éternelle sans oreille... instrument ou organe. Il écoute les prières et les supplications de Sa création. Ce nom signifie l\'ouïe parfaite et complète d\'Allah. Il reflète Son attention aux besoins et aux requêtes de Ses serviteurs.,Ya Basiru est Celui qui voit toutes les choses qui sont vues par Sa vision éternelle sans pupille ni aucun autre instrument. Il observe toutes les actions et les événements dans l\'univers. Ce nom souligne la vision omniprésente d\'Allah. Il reflète Sa conscience et Sa vigilance sur toute la création.,Ya Hakamu est le Juge... et Son jugement est Sa parole. Il règle toutes les affaires avec justice et sagesse. Ce nom signifie le rôle d\'Allah en tant qu\'arbitre et juge ultime. Il met en avant Son autorité pour prendre des décisions justes et Son dernier mot dans toutes les affaires.,Ya \'Adlu est Celui qui a le droit de faire ce qu\'Il fait. Ses actions et Ses jugements sont justes et équitables. Ce nom reflète la justice et l\'équilibre parfaits d\'Allah. Il souligne Son rôle dans le maintien de l\'équité et de la droiture dans l\'univers.,Ya Latifu est le Gracieux... Celui qui est bon envers Ses serviteurs et leur accorde des dons. Il comprend les plus fines mystères et subtilités. Ce nom signifie la nature douce et compatissante d\'Allah. Il met en avant Sa bonté et Ses moyens subtils d\'accorder grâce et miséricorde.,Ya Khabiru est Celui qui connaît la vérité des choses. Il est pleinement conscient de toutes les affaires cachées et apparentes. Ce nom souligne la connaissance profonde et la conscience d\'Allah. Il reflète Sa compréhension de l\'essence véritable de toutes choses.,Ya Halimu est Celui qui retarde la punition de ceux qui la méritent et peut ensuite leur pardonner. Il est patient et indulgent. Ce nom signifie la tolérance et la patience d\'Allah. Il reflète Sa volonté de donner du temps pour le repentir et la correction.,Ya-\'Adheemu est le Puissant... Celui qui mérite l\'exaltation... la gloire... la louange et la pureté de toute imperfection. Il est majestueux et grand sous tous les aspects. Ce nom met en avant la grandeur et la majesté d\'Allah. Il reflète Son statut exalté et la révérence qu\'Il mérite.,Ya Ghafuru est le Pardonneur... Celui qui pardonne beaucoup. Son pardon est vaste et couvre tous les péchés pour ceux qui se repentent sincèrement. Ce nom signifie l\'immense miséricorde d\'Allah et Sa disposition à pardonner. Il souligne Sa générosité en pardonnant et en négligeant les fautes.,Ya Shakuru est Celui qui donne beaucoup de récompenses pour une petite obéissance. Il reconnaît et récompense même les plus petits actes de bonté. Ce nom reflète la générosité d\'Allah et Son appréciation des efforts de Ses serviteurs. Il met en avant Sa volonté de multiplier les récompenses pour les bonnes actions.,Ya Aliu est Celui qui est exempt des attributs des créatures. Il est exalté au-dessus de toute la création. Ce nom signifie le statut suprême et la transcendance d\'Allah. Il reflète Son rang élevé et la pureté de Son essence divine.,Ya Kabiru est le Grand... Celui qui est plus grand que tout en statut. Sa grandeur est au-delà de toute compréhension. Ce nom souligne l\'immense grandeur d\'Allah. Il met en avant Sa supériorité sur tout ce qui existe.,Ya Hafidhu est le Protecteur... Celui qui protège tout ce qu\'Il veut protéger. Il sauvegarde toute la création du mal. Ce nom signifie le rôle d\'Allah en tant que gardien et préservateur. Il reflète Sa capacité à maintenir et à protéger Sa création.,Ya Muqitu est le Gardien... le Nourricier... Celui qui a le pouvoir de maintenir toutes choses. Il pourvoit à la subsistance et soutient toute vie. Ce nom met en avant le rôle d\'Allah dans le soutien et la nutrition de Sa création. Il souligne Son soin continu et Sa provision.,Ya Hasibu est Celui qui donne satisfaction. Il est suffisant en tant que protecteur et comptable. Ce nom signifie la capacité d\'Allah à rendre compte de toutes les actions et les œuvres. Il reflète Son rôle dans la fourniture de rétribution et la garantie de la justice.,Ya Jalilu est le Majestueux... Celui qui est attribué à la grandeur de puissance et de gloire de statut. Il est majestueux et vénéré. Ce nom met en avant la grandeur et la majesté d\'Allah. Il reflète Son statut exalté et la révérence qu\'Il commande.,Ya Karimu est le Généreux... Celui qui est attribué à la grandeur de puissance et de gloire de statut. Il est généreux et bienveillant. Ce nom signifie la générosité et la bienveillance d\'Allah. Il met en avant Sa volonté de donner et d\'accorder des faveurs.,Ya Raqibu est Celui dont rien ne Lui échappe. Il observe toutes les actions et pensées. Ce nom souligne la vigilance et la conscience d\'Allah. Il reflète Sa capacité à surveiller et à superviser toute la création.,Ya Mujibu est l\'Auditeur... Celui qui répond à celui qui est dans le besoin s\'il Le demande et sauve celui qui appelle à Lui. Il répond aux prières et aux supplications. Ce nom signifie la disposition d\'Allah à répondre et à aider. Il met en avant Sa réactivité aux appels de Ses serviteurs.,Ya Wasi\'u est l\'Immense... Celui dont la connaissance et la miséricorde englobent toutes choses. Il est illimité dans Ses attributs. Ce nom reflète la nature infinie et la compassion sans bornes d\'Allah. Il met en avant Sa capacité à englober toute la création avec Sa grâce et Sa connaissance.,Ya Hakimu est le Juge des Juges... Celui qui est correct dans Ses actions. Sa sagesse gouverne toutes les actions et les décrets. Ce nom signifie la sagesse parfaite et le jugement d\'Allah. Il met en avant Sa capacité à prendre des décisions justes et sages.,Ya Wadudu est Celui qui aime Ses serviteurs croyants et dont les croyants L\'aiment. Son amour se manifeste dans Sa miséricorde et Ses louanges pour eux. Ce nom reflète l\'affection et la bienveillance d\'Allah envers Ses serviteurs fidèles. Il souligne l\'amour réciproque entre le Créateur et Sa création.,Ya Majeedu est Celui qui a une puissance parfaite... un statut élevé... de la compassion... de la générosité et de la bienveillance. Il est majestueux et honorable. Ce nom signifie la grandeur et la noblesse d\'Allah. Il met en avant Sa position exaltée et la gloire de Ses attributs.,Ya Ba\'ithu est Celui qui ressuscite Ses serviteurs après la mort pour la récompense et/ou la punition. Il ramène les morts à la vie. Ce nom signifie le pouvoir d\'Allah sur la vie et la mort. Il reflète Sa capacité à provoquer la résurrection et à juger tous les êtres.,Ya Shaheedu est Celui dont rien ne Lui échappe. Il est témoin de toutes les actions et événements. Ce nom souligne l\'omniprésence d\'Allah et Son rôle en tant que témoin toujours présent. Il reflète Sa conscience de tout ce qui se passe dans l\'univers.,Ya Haqqu est le Vrai... Celui qui existe réellement. Son existence est absolue et éternelle. Ce nom signifie la réalité et l\'authenticité d\'Allah. Il met en avant Sa position en tant que vérité ultime et fondement de toute existence.,Ya Wakilu est Celui qui donne satisfaction et en qui on peut se fier. Il est le meilleur gardien et le meilleur protecteur. Ce nom reflète la fiabilité et la confiance en Allah. Il souligne Son rôle en tant que celui à qui toutes les affaires sont confiées.,Ya Qawiyyu est le Fort... Celui avec un pouvoir complet. Il est puissant et fort au-delà de toute mesure. Ce nom signifie la force et l\'autorité d\'Allah. Il met en avant Sa capacité à accomplir toutes choses et à protéger Sa création.,Ya Mateenu est Celui avec une puissance extrême qui est ininterrompue et ne se fatigue pas. Sa force est solide et inébranlable. Ce nom reflète la fermeté et la résilience d\'Allah. Il souligne Sa puissance durable et Sa constance.,Ya Waliu est le Supporter et protecteur. Il est l\'ami et l\'aide de Ses serviteurs justes. Ce nom signifie la proximité et le soutien d\'Allah. Il reflète Son rôle en tant que gardien et allié de ceux qui cherchent Sa protection.,Ya Hamiduu est Celui qui mérite d\'être loué. Ses attributs et Ses actions sont dignes de toutes les louanges. Ce nom reflète le mérite d\'Allah pour la gratitude et l\'admiration. Il souligne Sa nature louable et l\'honneur qui Lui est dû.,Ya Muhsi est Celui dont le compte des choses Lui est connu. Il est conscient de toutes les quantités et mesures. Ce nom signifie la connaissance complète d\'Allah de tous les détails. Il reflète Sa capacité à rendre compte de tout ce qui existe.,Ya Mubdiu est Celui qui a créé l\'être humain. Il crée sans aucun modèle préexistant. Ce nom signifie l\'innovation et l\'originalité d\'Allah dans la création. Il met en avant Son rôle en tant que créateur initial de toutes choses.,Ya Mu\'idu est Celui qui ramène les créatures après la mort. Il restaure la vie et ressuscite les morts. Ce nom signifie le pouvoir d\'Allah sur la vie et la mort. Il reflète Sa capacité à ressusciter et à ramener Sa création.,Ya Muhyi est Celui qui donne vie à ce qui est sans vie. Il ravive la vie physique et spirituelle. Ce nom signifie le rôle d\'Allah dans la création et le maintien de la vie. Il met en avant Sa capacité à accorder et à renouveler la vie.,Ya Mumitu est Celui qui rend les vivants morts. Il a le contrôle sur la vie et la mort. Ce nom signifie le pouvoir d\'Allah de prendre la vie. Il reflète Son autorité sur la fin de la vie et la transition vers l\'au-delà.,Ya Hayyu est Celui qui est attribué à une vie qui n\'est pas comme la nôtre et n\'est pas celle d\'une combinaison d\'âme... de chair ou de sang. Il possède une vie éternelle et auto-suffisante. Ce nom signifie l\'existence unique et éternelle d\'Allah. Il reflète Sa vitalité et la source de la vie elle-même.,Ya Qayyumu est Celui qui demeure et ne prend pas fin. Il soutient toutes choses par Lui-même et n\'a besoin d\'aucun soutien. Ce nom signifie l\'auto-suffisance et l\'indépendance d\'Allah. Il reflète Son existence éternelle et Son rôle de soutien de toute la création.,Ya Waajidu est Celui qui trouve... le Riche qui n\'est jamais pauvre. Il est auto-suffisant et abondant en richesse. Ce nom signifie la richesse d\'Allah et Sa capacité à pourvoir à tous les besoins. Il reflète Son intégrité et la suffisance de Ses attributs.,Ya Maajidu est le Très Glorieux... Celui qui a une puissance parfaite. Sa grandeur est inégalée et radieuse. Ce nom signifie la magnificence et la splendeur d\'Allah. Il reflète Sa présence majestueuse et la gloire de Son essence divine.,Ya Waahidu est l\'Unique... l\'Éternel... l\'Indépendant. Il est singulier et incomparable. Ce nom signifie l\'unicité et l\'exclusivité d\'Allah. Il reflète Son unité absolue et Son indépendance de toute la création.,Ya Ahadu est l\'Unique sans partenaire. Il n\'a pas d\'égal ni de rival. Ce nom signifie l\'unité indivisible et la singularité d\'Allah. Il reflète Son statut exclusif en tant que seule divinité digne d\'adoration.,Ya Samadu est l\'Éternel... l\'Indépendant... le Maître sur qui on se repose. Il est éternel et immuable. Ce nom signifie la nature éternelle d\'Allah et Son rôle en tant que source ultime de soutien. Il reflète Sa permanence et Sa constance.,Ya Qaadiru est le Capable... Celui attribué au Pouvoir. Il a la capacité d\'accomplir toutes choses. Ce nom signifie l\'omnipotence d\'Allah et Son contrôle sur toutes les affaires. Il reflète Sa puissance illimitée et Son autorité.,Ya Muqtadiru est le Dominant... Celui avec un Pouvoir complet. Son autorité est absolue et irrésistible. Ce nom signifie la souveraineté d\'Allah et Sa capacité à imposer Sa volonté. Il reflète Sa puissance suprême et Son contrôle sur toute la création.,Ya Muqaddimu est Celui qui avance et accélère. Il priorise et facilite les choses selon Sa sagesse. Ce nom signifie la capacité d\'Allah à hâter et à expédier les événements. Il reflète Son pouvoir de provoquer des résultats rapidement et de manière décisive.,Ya Mu\'akhkhiru est Celui qui retarde et diffère. Il reporte les événements selon Son plan divin. Ce nom signifie la sagesse d\'Allah dans le retardement des résultats pour un plus grand dessein. Il reflète Son contrôle du temps et Sa capacité à déterminer le rythme des événements.,Ya Awwalu est le Premier... Celui qui existait avant tout le reste. Il est l\'origine et la source de toute la création. Ce nom signifie la primauté d\'Allah et Son existence intemporelle. Il reflète Sa prééminence et le commencement de toutes choses.,Ya Aakhiru est le Dernier... Celui qui restera après que tout le reste ait péri. Il est éternel et immortel. Ce nom signifie la permanence d\'Allah et Sa présence au-delà de la fin des temps. Il reflète Sa finalité et la conclusion ultime de toute existence.,Ya Dhaahiru est le Manifeste... Celui dont la présence est évidente et claire. Il est apparent et visible dans Ses signes et créations. Ce nom signifie la visibilité d\'Allah et Sa manifestation dans l\'univers. Il reflète Sa clarté et la manifestation évidente de Ses attributs.,Ya Baatinu est le Caché... Celui dont l\'essence est dissimulée et mystérieuse. Il est au-delà de la perception et de la compréhension humaines. Ce nom signifie l\'invisibilité d\'Allah et Sa nature cachée. Il reflète Sa transcendance et la profondeur de Son essence divine.,Ya Waaliu est le Patron... l\'Ami Protecteur qui guide et soutient Ses serviteurs. Il est leur allié et gardien. Ce nom signifie la proximité d\'Allah et Son rôle de compagnon protecteur. Il reflète Son soin et Sa guidance pour ceux qui cherchent Sa protection.,Ya Muta\'ali est le Suprêmement Exalté... Celui dont le statut est incomparable. Il est élevé au-dessus de toute la création. Ce nom signifie la transcendance d\'Allah et Son rang exalté. Il reflète Sa supériorité et l\'élévation de Son essence divine.,Ya Barru est la Source de Bonté... Celui qui est bienveillant et généreux. Il accorde des bénédictions et des faveurs à Sa création. Ce nom signifie la bonté d\'Allah et Sa grâce abondante. Il reflète Sa générosité et l\'abondance de Ses bénédictions.,Ya Tawwaabu est Celui qui revient sans cesse... Celui qui accepte le repentir et pardonne les péchés. Il est miséricordieux et compatissant. Ce nom signifie la volonté d\'Allah de pardonner et Son empressement à accepter ceux qui se tournent vers Lui en repentir. Il reflète Sa miséricorde infinie et Son invitation à revenir à Lui.,Ya Muntaqimu est le Vengeur... Celui qui punit ceux qui transgressent Ses limites. Il impose la justice et la rétribution. Ce nom signifie la colère d\'Allah contre l\'injustice et Son engagement à faire respecter la justice. Il reflète Son rôle de juge ultime et d\'exécuteur de la justice divine.,Ya \'Afuwwu est le Pardonneur... Celui qui pardonne et oublie les fautes. Il efface les péchés et accorde l\'absolution. Ce nom signifie la miséricorde d\'Allah et Sa volonté de pardonner sans garder de rancune. Il reflète Sa générosité en pardonnant Ses serviteurs.,Ya Ra\'ufu est le Compatissant... Celui qui est tendre et miséricordieux. Il ressent de l\'empathie pour Sa création et leur montre de la compassion. Ce nom signifie la douceur et la nature bienveillante d\'Allah. Il reflète Sa sympathie et Son souci du bien-être de Ses serviteurs.,Ya Malik Al Mulki est le Propriétaire de la Souveraineté... Celui qui possède la domination sur toutes choses. Il est le souverain ultime et l\'autorité suprême. Ce nom signifie la royauté d\'Allah et Son contrôle absolu sur l\'univers. Il reflète Sa souveraineté et Son droit de commander et de décréter.,Ya Jal-Jalali Al Ikram est Celui qui possède la grandeur et la noblesse. Il est majestueux et digne de tout honneur et respect. Ce nom signifie le statut exalté d\'Allah et Son mérite de révérence. Il reflète Sa dignité... Sa magnificence et l\'honneur qui Lui est dû.,Ya Muqsitu est Celui qui est juste et équitable dans tous Ses jugements et actions. Il maintient l\'équilibre et l\'équité dans l\'univers. Ce nom signifie l\'engagement d\'Allah envers la justice et l\'équité. Il reflète Son rôle dans la garantie que tous les actes sont récompensés ou punis de manière appropriée.,Ya Jaami\'u est Celui qui rassemble ce qu\'Il veut... quand Il veut. Il rassemblera toutes les créatures pour le Jour du Jugement. Ce nom signifie la capacité d\'Allah à assembler et à unir. Il reflète Son pouvoir de réunir tous les êtres pour rendre compte de leurs actes.,Ya Ghaniu est Celui qui est libre de tout besoin. Il est auto-suffisant et indépendant de toute la création. Ce nom signifie la richesse d\'Allah et Son absence de besoin pour quoi que ce soit en dehors de Lui-même. Il reflète Sa suffisance absolue et Son indépendance.,Ya Mughniu est Celui qui fournit richesse et suffisance à Ses créatures. Il enrichit qui Il veut. Ce nom signifie la générosité d\'Allah et Sa capacité à accorder la prospérité. Il reflète Son rôle dans l\'octroi de l\'abondance et de la richesse à Ses serviteurs.,Ya Mani\'u est Celui qui empêche le mal ou le danger de se produire. Il est le protecteur et le défenseur. Ce nom signifie la capacité d\'Allah à protéger et à défendre contre le danger. Il reflète Son rôle dans la sauvegarde de Sa création contre le mal.,Ya Dharru est Celui qui peut provoquer le mal ou l\'affliction s\'Il le veut. Il a le contrôle sur toutes les circonstances. Ce nom signifie le pouvoir d\'Allah sur l\'adversité et les difficultés. Il reflète Son autorité à provoquer des épreuves comme test ou punition.,Ya Nafi\'u est Celui qui apporte des bienfaits et des bénédictions. Il accorde la bonté et le bien-être. Ce nom signifie le rôle d\'Allah dans la fourniture et la facilitation des résultats positifs. Il reflète Sa capacité à accorder des bienfaits et des faveurs.,Ya Nuru est la Lumière... Celui qui illumine les cieux et la terre. Il guide et apporte de la clarté. Ce nom signifie le rôle d\'Allah en tant que source de guidance et d\'illumination. Il reflète Sa capacité à apporter la lumière dans l\'obscurité et la clarté dans la confusion.,Ya Hadiu est Celui qui guide Ses serviteurs sur le droit chemin. Il fournit direction et inspiration. Ce nom signifie le rôle d\'Allah en tant que source de guidance et de sagesse. Il reflète Sa capacité à conduire Sa création vers la droiture et la vérité.,Ya Badi\'iu est l\'Incomparable... Celui qui crée de manière inégalée et merveilleuse. Il est unique dans Sa création. Ce nom signifie l\'originalité d\'Allah et Son pouvoir créatif inégalé. Il reflète Sa capacité à créer sans précédent ni modèle.,Ya Baaqiu est l\'Éternel... Celui qui demeure quand tout le reste périt. Il est éternel et immuable. Ce nom signifie la permanence d\'Allah et Son existence au-delà du temps. Il reflète Sa continuité et la nature éternelle de Son être.,Ya Waarithu est l\'Héritier... Celui qui demeure après que toute la création soit arrivée à sa fin. Il héritera de la terre et de tout ce qui s\'y trouve. Ce nom signifie la possession ultime d\'Allah et Sa présence durable. Il reflète Son rôle en tant que possesseur final de toutes choses.,Ya Rashidu est le Maître Juste... Celui qui guide sur le chemin de la droiture. Il fournit sagesse et compréhension correcte. Ce nom signifie le rôle d\'Allah en tant qu\'enseignant et guide. Il reflète Sa capacité à conduire Ses serviteurs vers une connaissance juste et bénéfique.,Ya Sabooru est le Patient... Celui qui ne se précipite pas pour punir les pécheurs. Il est indulgent et tolérant. Ce nom signifie la patience d\'Allah et Sa retenue à retarder la punition. Il reflète Sa volonté de donner du temps pour le repentir et Sa capacité à supporter les transgressions humaines."</string>
    <!--    italian-->
    <string name="app_name_it">99 Nomi di Allah</string>
    <string name="language_it">Italiano</string>
    <string name="names_it">"1. Ya Rahmanu,2.	Ya Raheemu,3.	Ya Maliku,4.	Ya Quddusu,5.	Ya Salamu,6.	Ya Mu\'minu,7.	Ya Muhayminu,8.	Ya Azizu,9.	Ya Jabbaaru,10.	Ya Mutakabbiru,11.	Ya Khaaliqu,12.	Ya Baariu,13.	Ya Musawwiru,14.	Ya Ghaffaaru,15.	Ya Qahhaaru,16.	Ya Wahhaabu,17.	Ya Razzaaqu,18.	Ya Fattaahu,19.	Ya Alimu,20.	Ya Qaabidhu,21.	Ya Baasitu,22.	Ya Khaafidhu,23.	Ya Raafi\'u,24.	Ya Mu\'izzu,25.	Ya Muzillu,26.	Ya Sami\'u,27.	Ya Basiru,28.	Ya Hakamu,29.	Ya \'Adlu,30.	Ya Latifu,31.	Ya Khabiru,32.	Ya Halimu,33.	Ya-‘Adheemu,34.	Ya Ghafuru,35.	Ya Shakuru,36.	Ya Aliu,37.	Ya Kabiru,38.	Ya Hafidhu,39.	Ya Muqitu,40.	Ya Hasibu,41.	Ya Jalilu,42.	Ya Karimu,43.	Ya Raqibu,44.	Ya Mujibu,45.	Ya Wasi\'u,46.	Ya Hakimu,47.	Ya Wadudu,48.	Ya Majeedu,49.	Ya Ba\'ithu,50.	Ya Shaheedu,51.	Ya Haqqu,52.	Ya Wakilu,53.	Ya Qawiyyu,54.	Ya Mateenu,55.	Ya Waliu,56.	Ya Hamiduu,57.	Ya Muhsi,58.	Ya Mubdiu,59.	Ya Mu\'idu,60.	Ya Muhyi,61.	Ya Mumitu,62.	Ya Hayyu,63.	Ya Qayyumu,64.	Ya Waajidu,65.	Ya Maajidu,66.	Ya Waahidu,67.	Ya Ahadu,68.	Ya Samadu,69.	Ya Qaadiru,70.	Ya Muqtadiru,71.	Ya Muqaddimu,72.	Ya Mu\'akhkhiru,73.	Ya Awwalu,74.	Ya Aakhiru,75.	Ya Dhaahiru,76.	Ya Baatinu,77.	Ya Waaliu,78.	Ya Muta\'ali,79.	Ya Barru,80.	Ya Tawwaabu,81.	Ya Muntaqimu,82.	Ya \'Afuwwu,83.	Ya Ra\'ufu,84.	Ya Malik Al Mulki,85.	Ya Jal-Jalali Al Ikram,86.	Ya Muqsitu,87.	Ya Jaami\'u,88.	Ya Ghaniu,89.	Ya Mughniu,90.	Ya Mani\'u,91.	Ya Dharru,92.	Ya Nafi\'u,93.	Ya Nuru,94.	Ya Hadiu,95.	Ya Badi\'iu,96.	Ya Baaqiu,97.	Ya Waarithu,98.	Ya Rashidu,99.	Ya Sabooru"</string>

    <string name="meaning_it">"Il Misericordioso, Il Compassionevole, Il Signore Eterno, Il Più Sacro, L\'Incarnazione della Pace, L\'Infusore di Fede, Il Protettore della Sicurezza, Il Potente, L\'Onnipotente, Il Dominante, Il Creatore, L\'Evolutore, Il Plasmante Perfetto, Il Grande Perdonatore, L\'Onnipervadente, Il Sommo Elargitore, Il Fornitore Totale, Il Risolutore Supremo, L\'Onnisciente, Il Limitante, L\'Estensore, Il Riduttore, L\'Elevatore, L\'Onoratore-Elargitore, L\'Umiliante, Il Tuto-Audiente, Il Tuto-Vedente, Il Giudice Imparziale, L\'Incarnazione della Giustizia, Il Conoscitore delle Sottigliezze, L\'Onniconsapevole, Il Clemente, Il Magnifico, Il Grande Perdonatore, Il Riconoscente, L\'Altissimo, Il Grande, Il Protettore, Il Sostenitore, Il Calcolatore, Il Maestoso, Il Generoso, Il Vigile, Il Rispondente, L\'Onnipervadente, Il Saggio, L\'Amante, Il Glorioso, L\'Infusore di Nuova Vita, Il Testimone Tutto-Osservante, L\'Incarnazione della Verità, Il Fedele Universale, Il Forte, Il Fermo, Il Compagno Protettivo, Il Solo-Laudabile, Il Tutto-Enumerante, L\'Originatore, Il Restauratore, Il Mantenitore della Vita, L\'Inflictatore di Morte, L\'Eternamente Vivente, Il Sussistente, Il Puntatore, Il Nobile, L\'Unico, Il Solo, Il Sommo Fornitore, L\'Onnipotente, L\'Autorevolezza Totale, L\'Accellerante, Il Procrastinatore, Il Primissimo, L\'Ultimo Infinito, Il Percepibile, L\'Impercettibile, Il Detentore dell\'Autorità Suprema, L\'Altissimo, La Fonte della Verità, Il Perdonatore di Sempre, Il Vendicatore, Il Sommo Perdonatore, Il Benevolo, Il Possessore Eterno della Sovranità, Il Possessore della Maestà e dell\'Onore, Il Giusto, Il Riunificatore delle Creazioni Sparpagliate, L\'Autosufficiente, Il Fornitore della Sufficienza, Il Prevenente, L\'Arrecante di Danno, Il Fornitore dei Benefici, La Luce Primordiale, Il Guida, L\'Unico, Il Sempre Vivente, L\'Erede Eterno, La Guida al Cammino della Rettitudine, L\'Infinito Endurante"</string>
    <string name="des_it">"Ya Rahmanu è Colui che vuole il bene e la misericordia per tutte le Sue creature. Egli elargisce immense grazie e benedizioni all\'universo... mostrando compassione a tutti gli esseri. La Sua misericordia è vasta e comprende tutte le cose... indipendentemente dalla loro fede o azioni. Questo nome riflette la cura nutriente di Allah per tutta la creazione, Ya Raheemu è Colui che agisce con estrema gentilezza e compassione... in particolare verso i credenti. La Sua misericordia è eterna e si manifesta sia in questo mondo che nell\'Aldilà. Questo nome significa il perdono di Allah e le ricompense che Egli prepara per i fedeli. Sottolinea la Sua natura gentile e compassionevole, Ya Maliku è il Sovrano Signore... Colui con il dominio completo sull\'universo. Il Suo regno è assoluto e la Sua autorità è perfetta e priva di qualsiasi imperfezione. Questo nome illustra il potere e il controllo di Allah su tutte le cose... visibili e invisibili. Egli governa tutta la creazione con saggezza e giustizia, Ya Quddusu è Colui che è puro da ogni imperfezione ed è esaltato sopra tutti i difetti e le debolezze. Egli è libero da tutti gli attributi che implicano difetti o carenze. Questo nome mette in risalto la purezza e la santità di Allah. Riflette la Sua trascendenza e santità... essendo oltre la comprensione umana, Ya Salamu è Colui che è libero da ogni imperfezione e conferisce pace e sicurezza alla Sua creazione. Egli concede tranquillità ai cuori e alle menti... assicurando sicurezza e armonia. Questo nome significa la perfezione di Allah e la pace che deriva dalla sottomissione a Lui. Sottolinea il Suo ruolo di donatore di serenità, Ya Mu\'minu è Colui che fornisce sicurezza e conferma la verità dei Suoi fedeli credenti. Egli offre protezione e pace... proteggendoli dalla paura e dal male. Questo nome enfatizza il ruolo di Allah nel fornire sicurezza e fiducia. Assicura anche ai credenti la verità della loro fede e la realtà delle Sue promesse, Ya Muhayminu è Colui che veglia e protegge tutta la Sua creazione... conoscendo le loro azioni e pensieri. Egli mantiene e sovrintende a tutte le cose con perfetta conoscenza e autorità. Questo nome riflette la vigilanza di Allah e la Sua custodia su tutto. Assicura ai credenti la Sua costante cura e attenzione, Ya Azizu è Colui che è potente e forte... il Soggiogatore che non è sconfitto. Egli è ineguagliabile in potenza e onore... sopraffacendo tutti i Suoi nemici. Questo nome illustra la forza e l\'invincibilità di Allah. Mostra la Sua capacità di prevalere e proteggere coloro che cercano il Suo aiuto, Ya Jabbaaru è Colui che costringe e ripristina... esercitando la Sua volontà sulla Sua creazione. Egli ripara ciò che è rotto e impone il Suo decreto su tutto ciò che esiste. Questo nome significa il potere di Allah di far rispettare i Suoi comandi e rettificare le questioni. Riflette anche la Sua capacità di guarire e ristabilire l\'equilibrio, Ya Mutakabbiru è Colui che è chiaro dagli attributi delle creature e dal somigliar loro... ed è supremamente grande. Egli solo possiede grandezza e maestà oltre la comprensione. Questo nome mette in risalto la superiorità e la trascendenza di Allah su tutta la creazione. Sottolinea il Suo status elevato e la dignità della Sua essenza divina, Ya Khaaliqu è Colui che porta tutto dall\'inesistenza all\'esistenza. Egli crea tutte le cose con precisione e scopo. Questo nome riflette la capacità di Allah di originare e innovare la creazione. Sottolinea il Suo ruolo come Creatore ultimo dell\'universo e di tutto ciò che contiene, Ya Baariu è il Creatore... Colui che ha il potere di trasformare le entità in stati diversi. Egli fa sorgere e evolve la Sua creazione secondo la Sua saggezza. Questo nome significa la creatività di Allah e la Sua capacità di formare le Sue creature in modi unici. Evidenzia il Suo ruolo nel modellare e sviluppare tutte le forme di vita, Ya Musawwiru è Colui che forma le Sue creature in diverse forme e aspetti. Egli dà a ciascuna creazione le sue caratteristiche e attributi unici. Questo nome enfatizza il potere artistico di Allah e l\'attenzione ai dettagli nella creazione. Riflette la Sua capacità di progettare e dare forma a tutti gli esseri, Ya Ghaffaaru è Colui che perdona i peccati dei Suoi servi ancora e ancora. Il Suo perdono è vasto... coprendo anche i peccati più gravi per coloro che si pentono. Questo nome significa la misericordia infinita di Allah e la Sua volontà di perdonare. Sottolinea la Sua prontezza a perdonare e purificare coloro che cercano il Suo perdono, Ya Qahhaaru è il Dominante... Colui che ha il potere perfetto e non è incapace di nulla. Egli sovrasta e sottomette la Sua creazione come vuole. Questo nome illustra il controllo assoluto e il dominio di Allah su tutte le cose. Riflette la Sua capacità di sottomettere e la Sua suprema autorità, Ya Wahhaabu è Colui che è Generoso nel dare abbondanza senza alcun ritorno. Egli concede doni e benedizioni dalla Sua munificenza e grazia. Questo nome significa la generosità e la bontà di Allah. Mette in risalto il Suo ruolo come donatore di tutto ciò che è benefico... sia lecito che proibito,Ya Razzaaqu è il Sostenitore... il Provveditore che assicura il sostentamento di tutte le Sue creature. Egli distribuisce le provviste con saggezza e generosità. Questo nome enfatizza il ruolo di Allah nel provvedere ai bisogni della Sua creazione. Sottolinea la Sua cura e benevolenza nel sostenere la vita, Ya Fattaahu è Colui che apre... il Sollevatore... il Giudice che apre per i Suoi servi le questioni mondane e religiose chiuse. Egli concede vittoria... sollievo e soluzioni alle difficoltà. Questo nome significa il potere di Allah di rimuovere gli ostacoli e fornire guida. Riflette il Suo ruolo nel facilitare i percorsi e risolvere i problemi, Ya Alimu è il Conoscitore; Colui dal cui sapere nulla è assente. Egli è consapevole di tutte le cose... passate... presenti e future. Questo nome enfatizza l\'onniscienza di Allah e la Sua perfetta conoscenza di tutti gli affari. Sottolinea la Sua consapevolezza e comprensione di tutta la creazione, Ya Qaabidhu è Colui che restringe il sostentamento con la Sua saggezza. Egli trattiene le provviste secondo il Suo piano divino. Questo nome significa il controllo di Allah sulla distribuzione delle risorse. Evidenzia la Sua saggezza nel determinare ciò che è meglio per la Sua creazione, Ya Baasitu è Colui che espande e amplia il sostentamento con la Sua generosità e misericordia. Egli aumenta le provviste e concede abbondanza. Questo nome riflette la gentilezza e la liberalità di Allah. Enfatizza la Sua capacità di ampliare e benedire la Sua creazione con risorse abbondanti, Ya Khaafidhu è Colui che abbassa chi vuole con la Sua distruzione. Egli abbassa coloro che meritano di essere umiliati. Questo nome significa la giustizia di Allah e il Suo potere di umiliare. Riflette il Suo ruolo nel bilanciare le scale della giustizia abbassando gli arroganti e gli ingiusti, Ya Raafi\'u è l\'Elevatore... Colui che innalza chi vuole con i Suoi doni. Egli eleva lo status dei giusti e dei virtuosi. Questo nome mette in evidenza la capacità di Allah di onorare e innalzare. Riflette la Sua generosità nel concedere alti ranghi e dignità ai Suoi fedeli servi, Ya Mu\'izzu è Colui che conferisce stima a chi vuole; quindi nessuno può degradarlo. Egli concede onore e dignità ai Suoi prescelti. Questo nome significa il potere di Allah di onorare e innalzare. Riflette la Sua autorità nel concedere rispetto e status, Ya Muzillu è l\'Umiliatore... Colui che degrada chi vuole; quindi nessuno può conferirgli stima. Egli abbassa gli arroganti e gli ingiusti. Questo nome enfatizza la giustizia di Allah nell\'abbassare i non meritevoli. Riflette il Suo potere di umiliare e abbassare coloro che sfidano i Suoi comandi, Ya Sami\'u è Colui che sente tutte le cose udibili con il Suo udito eterno senza orecchio... strumento o organo. Egli ascolta le preghiere e le suppliche della Sua creazione. Questo nome significa l\'udito perfetto e completo di Allah. Riflette la Sua attenzione ai bisogni e alle suppliche dei Suoi servi, Ya Basiru è Colui che vede tutte le cose visibili con la Sua visione eterna senza pupilla o alcun altro strumento. Egli osserva tutte le azioni e gli eventi nell\'universo. Questo nome enfatizza la visione onnipresente di Allah. Riflette la Sua consapevolezza e vigilanza su tutta la creazione, Ya Hakamu è il Giudice... e il Suo giudizio è la Sua parola. Egli risolve tutte le questioni con giustizia e saggezza. Questo nome significa il ruolo di Allah come arbitro e giudice ultimo. Sottolinea la Sua autorità nel prendere decisioni eque e la Sua parola finale in tutti gli affari, Ya \'Adlu è Colui che ha diritto di fare ciò che fa. Le Sue azioni e i Suoi giudizi sono equi ed equitativi. Questo nome riflette la giustizia perfetta di Allah e il Suo equilibrio. Sottolinea il Suo ruolo nel mantenere l\'equità e la rettitudine nell\'universo, Ya Latifu è il Grazioso... Colui che è gentile con i Suoi servi e li dota. Egli comprende i misteri e le complessità più sottili. Questo nome significa la natura gentile e compassionevole di Allah. Evidenzia la Sua gentilezza e i Suoi modi sottili di concedere grazia e misericordia, Ya Khabiru è Colui che conosce la verità delle cose. Egli è pienamente consapevole di tutte le questioni nascoste e apparenti. Questo nome enfatizza la profonda conoscenza e consapevolezza di Allah. Riflette la Sua comprensione della vera essenza di tutte le cose, Ya Halimu è Colui che ritarda la punizione per coloro che la meritano e poi potrebbe perdonarli. Egli è paziente e indulgente. Questo nome significa la tolleranza e la pazienza di Allah. Riflette la Sua volontà di dare tempo per il pentimento e la correzione, Ya-\'Adheemu è il Potente... Colui che merita esaltazione... gloria... lode e purezza da ogni imperfezione. Egli è maestoso e grandioso in ogni aspetto. Questo nome mette in evidenza la grandezza e la maestosità di Allah. Riflette il Suo status elevato e la riverenza che merita, Ya Ghafuru è il Perdonatore... Colui che perdona molto. Il Suo perdono è vasto e copre tutti i peccati per coloro che si pentono sinceramente. Questo nome significa l\'immensa misericordia di Allah e la Sua prontezza a perdonare. Enfatizza la Sua grazia nel perdonare e trascurare i difetti, Ya Shakuru è Colui che concede grandi ricompense per poca obbedienza. Egli riconosce e ricompensa anche i più piccoli atti di bontà. Questo nome riflette la generosità e l\'apprezzamento di Allah per gli sforzi dei Suoi servi. Mette in risalto la Sua volontà di moltiplicare le ricompense per le buone azioni, Ya Aliu è Colui che è chiaro dagli attributi delle creature. Egli è esaltato sopra tutta la creazione. Questo nome significa lo status supremo e la trascendenza di Allah. Riflette il Suo rango elevato e la purezza della Sua essenza divina,Ya Kabiru è il Grande... Colui che è più grande di tutto in status. La sua grandezza è al di là della comprensione. Questo nome enfatizza l\'immensa grandezza di Allah. Mette in evidenza la sua superiorità su tutto ciò che esiste, Ya Hafidhu è il Protettore... Colui che protegge ciò che e chiunque Egli voglia proteggere. Egli protegge tutta la creazione dal male. Questo nome significa il ruolo di Allah come guardiano e conservatore. Riflette la sua capacità di mantenere e proteggere la sua creazione, Ya Muqitu è il Guardiano... il Nutritore... Colui che ha il potere di mantenere tutte le cose. Egli fornisce sostentamento e sostiene tutta la vita. Questo nome mette in evidenza il ruolo di Allah nel sostenere e nutrire la sua creazione. Sottolinea la sua continua cura e provvidenza, Ya Hasibu è Colui che dà soddisfazione. Egli è sufficiente come protettore e contabile. Questo nome significa la capacità di Allah di contabilizzare tutte le azioni e i fatti. Riflette il suo ruolo nel fornire ricompensa ed assicurare giustizia, Ya Jalilu è il Beneficente... Colui che è attribuito con la grandezza del potere e la gloria dello status. Egli è maestoso e riverito. Questo nome mette in evidenza la grandezza e la maestosità di Allah. Riflette il suo status esaltato e la riverenza che comanda, Ya Karimu è il Generoso... Colui che è attribuito con la grandezza del potere e la gloria dello status. Egli è generoso e gentile. Questo nome significa la generosità e la benevolenza di Allah. Sottolinea la sua volontà di dare e conferire favori, Ya Raqibu è Colui di cui nulla è assente da Lui. Egli osserva tutte le azioni e i pensieri. Questo nome enfatizza la vigilanza e la consapevolezza di Allah. Riflette la sua capacità di monitorare e sorvegliare tutta la creazione, Ya Mujibu è Colui che ascolta... Colui che risponde a chi ha bisogno se lo chiede e soccorre il desideroso se lo invoca. Egli risponde alle preghiere e alle suppliche. Questo nome significa la prontezza di Allah a rispondere e assistere. Mette in evidenza la sua prontezza a rispondere alle chiamate dei suoi servi, Ya Wasi\'u è il Vasto... Colui la cui conoscenza e misericordia abbracciano tutte le cose. Egli è illimitato nei suoi attributi. Questo nome riflette la natura infinita di Allah e la sua compassione senza limiti. Sottolinea la sua capacità di abbracciare tutta la creazione con la sua grazia e conoscenza, Ya Hakimu è il Giudice dei Giudici... Colui che è corretto nei suoi atti. La sua saggezza governa tutte le azioni e i decreti. Questo nome significa la perfetta saggezza e giudizio di Allah. Mette in evidenza la sua capacità di prendere decisioni giuste e sagge, Ya Wadudu è Colui che ama i suoi servi credenti e i cui credenti lo amano. Il suo amore si manifesta nella sua misericordia e nella sua lode per loro. Questo nome riflette l\'affetto e la gentilezza di Allah verso i suoi fedeli servitori. Sottolinea l\'amore reciproco tra il Creatore e la sua creazione, Ya Majeedu è Colui che è dotato di perfetto potere... alto status... compassione... generosità e gentilezza. Egli è maestoso e onorato. Questo nome significa la grandezza e la nobiltà di Allah. Riflette la sua posizione esaltata e la gloria dei suoi attributi, Ya Ba\'ithu è il Risvegliatore (dalla morte)... Colui che risuscita i suoi servi dopo la morte per ricompensa e/o punizione. Egli ridà vita ai morti. Questo nome significa il potere di Allah sulla vita e sulla morte. Riflette la sua capacità di portare risurrezione e giudicare tutti gli esseri, Ya Shaheedu è Colui di cui nulla è assente da Lui. Egli è testimone di tutte le azioni e gli eventi. Questo nome enfatizza l\'onnipresenza di Allah e il suo ruolo di testimone sempre presente. Riflette la sua consapevolezza di tutto ciò che accade nell\'universo, Ya Haqqu è il Vero... Colui che esiste veramente. La sua esistenza è assoluta ed eterna. Questo nome significa la realtà e l\'autenticità di Allah. Sottolinea la sua posizione come verità ultima e fondamento di tutta l\'esistenza, Ya Wakilu è Colui che dà soddisfazione e su cui si può fare affidamento. Egli è il miglior tutore e fiduciario. Questo nome riflette l\'affidabilità e l\'affidabilità di Allah. Sottolinea il suo ruolo come colui a cui sono affidate tutte le questioni, Ya Qawiyyu è il Forte... Colui con il potere completo. Egli è potente e potente oltre misura. Questo nome significa la forza e l\'autorità di Allah. Sottolinea la sua capacità di realizzare tutte le cose e proteggere la sua creazione, Ya Mateenu è Colui con un potere estremo che non è interrotto e che non si stanca. La sua forza è solida e ferma. Questo nome riflette la fermezza e la resilienza di Allah. Mette in evidenza il suo potere duraturo e la sua fermezza, Ya Waliu è il Sostenitore e il protettore. Egli fa amicizia e aiuta i suoi servi giusti. Questo nome significa la vicinanza e il supporto di Allah. Riflette il suo ruolo come guardiano e alleato di coloro che cercano la sua protezione, Ya Hamiduu è il Lodato che merita di essere lodato. I suoi attributi e le sue azioni sono degni di ogni lode. Questo nome riflette la degna gratitudine e l\'ammirazione di Allah. Sottolinea la sua natura lodabile e l\'onore che gli spetta, Ya Muhsi è Colui che conosce il conteggio di tutte le cose. Egli è consapevole di tutte le quantità e misure. Questo nome significa la conoscenza completa di Allah di tutti i dettagli. Riflette la sua capacità di contabilizzare tutto ciò che esiste, Ya Mubdiu è Colui che ha iniziato l\'essere umano. Egli crea senza alcun modello preesistente. Questo nome significa l\'innovazione e l\'originalità di Allah nella creazione. Mette in evidenza il suo ruolo come creatore iniziale di tutte le cose, Ya Mu\'idu è Colui che riporta le creature dopo la morte. Egli ripristina la vita e ridà vita ai morti. Questo nome significa il potere di Allah sulla vita e sulla morte. Riflette la sua capacità di risuscitare e riportare in vita la sua creazione, Ya Muhyi è Colui che dà vita a ciò che è privo di vita. Egli ravviva sia la vita fisica che spirituale. Questo nome significa il ruolo di Allah nel creare e sostenere la vita. Mette in evidenza la sua capacità di concedere e rinnovare la vita,Ya Mumitu è Colui che rende i viventi morti. Egli ha il controllo sulla vita e sulla morte. Questo nome significa il potere di Allah di togliere la vita. Riflette la sua autorità sulla fine della vita e la transizione all\'aldilà, Ya Hayyu è Colui a cui è attribuita una vita diversa dalla nostra e non è quella di una combinazione di anima... carne o sangue. Egli possiede una vita eterna e auto-sostenuta. Questo nome significa l\'esistenza unica ed eterna di Allah. Riflette la sua vitalità e la fonte stessa della vita, Ya Qayyumu è Colui che rimane e non finisce. Egli sostiene tutte le cose da solo e non ha bisogno di alcun sostegno. Questo nome significa l\'autosufficienza e l\'indipendenza di Allah. Riflette la sua esistenza eterna e il suo ruolo di sostenitore di tutta la creazione, Ya Waajidu è il Trovatore... il Ricco che non diventa mai povero. Egli è autosufficiente e abbondante di ricchezza. Questo nome significa la ricchezza di Allah e la sua capacità di provvedere a tutti i bisogni. Riflette la sua completezza e la sufficienza dei suoi attributi, Ya Maajidu è il più Glorioso... Colui che è dotato di potere perfetto. La sua grandezza è insuperabile e radiosa. Questo nome significa la magnificenza e lo splendore di Allah. Riflette la sua presenza maestosa e la gloria della sua essenza divina, Ya Waahidu è l\'Unico... l\'Eterno... l\'Indipendente. Egli è singolare e incomparabile. Questo nome significa l\'unicità e l\'unicità di Allah. Riflette la sua assoluta unità e indipendenza da tutta la creazione, Ya Ahadu è l\'Unico senza partner... l\'Unico. Non ha pari o rivale. Questo nome significa l\'unità indivisibile e l\'unicità di Allah. Riflette il suo status esclusivo come l\'unico dio degno di adorazione, Ya Samadu è l\'Eterno... l\'Indipendente... il Maestro di cui ci si affida. Egli è eterno e immutabile. Questo nome significa la natura eterna di Allah e il suo ruolo come fonte ultima di supporto. Riflette la sua permanenza e costanza, Ya Qaadiru è il Capace... Colui a cui è attribuito il Potere. Ha la capacità di compiere tutte le cose. Questo nome significa l\'onnipotenza di Allah e il suo controllo su tutte le questioni. Riflette il suo potere illimitato e la sua autorità, Ya Muqtadiru è il Dominatore... Colui con il potere completo. La sua autorità è assoluta e irresistibile. Questo nome significa la sovranità di Allah e la sua capacità di imporre la sua volontà. Riflette la sua potenza suprema e il controllo su tutta la creazione, Ya Muqaddimu è Colui che avanza e accelera. Prioritizza e facilita le questioni secondo la sua saggezza. Questo nome significa la capacità di Allah di accelerare e facilitare gli eventi. Riflette il suo potere di portare a compimento gli esiti in modo rapido e risoluto, Ya Mu\'akhkhiru è Colui che ritarda e differisce. Rinvia gli eventi secondo il suo piano divino. Questo nome significa la saggezza di Allah nel ritardare gli esiti per un fine superiore. Riflette il suo controllo sul tempo e la sua capacità di determinare il ritmo degli eventi, Ya Awwalu è il Primo... Colui che esisteva prima di tutto il resto. È l\'origine e la fonte di tutta la creazione. Questo nome significa la precedenza di Allah e la sua esistenza senza tempo. Riflette la sua primarietà e l\'inizio di tutte le cose, Ya Aakhiru è l\'Ultimo... Colui che rimarrà dopo che tutto il resto sarà perito. È eterno e duraturo. Questo nome significa la permanenza di Allah e la sua presenza oltre la fine del tempo. Riflette la sua finalità e la conclusione ultima di tutta l\'esistenza, Ya Dhaahiru è il Manifesto... Colui la cui presenza è evidente e chiara. È evidente e visibile nei suoi segni e nelle sue creazioni. Questo nome significa la visibilità di Allah e la sua manifestazione nell\'universo. Riflette la sua chiarezza e la manifestazione evidente dei suoi attributi, Ya Baatinu è l\'Occulto... Colui la cui essenza è nascosta e misteriosa. È al di là della percezione e della comprensione umana. Questo nome significa l\'invisibilità di Allah e la sua natura nascosta. Riflette la sua trascendenza e la profondità della sua essenza divina, Ya Waaliu è il Patrono... l\'Amico Protettore che guida e sostiene i suoi servitori. È il loro alleato e custode. Questo nome significa la vicinanza di Allah e il suo ruolo come compagno di supporto. Riflette la sua cura e la sua guida per coloro che cercano la sua protezione, Ya Muta\'ali è il Supremamente ELEVATO... Colui il cui stato è al di là del confronto. È elevato sopra tutta la creazione. Questo nome significa la trascendenza di Allah e il suo rango esaltato. Riflette la sua superiorità e l\'elevatezza della sua essenza divina, Ya Barru è la Fonte del Bene... Colui che è gentile e benevolo. Conferisce benedizioni e favori alla sua creazione. Questo nome significa la bontà di Allah e la sua grazia abbondante. Riflette la sua generosità e l\'abbondanza delle sue benedizioni, Ya Tawwaabu è il Sempre Ritornante... Colui che accetta il pentimento e perdona i peccati. È misericordioso e compassionevole. Questo nome significa la volontà di Allah di perdonare e la sua disponibilità ad accettare coloro che si rivolgono a lui in pentimento. Riflette la sua misericordia illimitata e il suo invito a tornare da lui, Ya Muntaqimu è il Vendicatore... Colui che punisce coloro che oltrepassano i suoi limiti.Egli applica la giustizia e la retribuzione. Questo nome significa l\'ira di Allah contro il peccato e il suo impegno a mantenere la giustizia. Riflette il suo ruolo come giudice supremo ed esecutore della giustizia divina, Ya \'Afuwwu è il Perdonatore... Colui che perdona e trascura i difetti. Egli cancella i peccati e concede l\'assoluzione. Questo nome significa la misericordia di Allah e la sua disponibilità a perdonare senza serbare rancore. Riflette la sua generosità nel perdonare i suoi servitori, Ya Ra\'ufu è il Compassionevole... Colui che è tenero e misericordioso. Prova empatia per la sua creazione e mostra loro compassione. Questo nome significa la gentilezza di Allah e la sua natura premurosa. Riflette la sua simpatia e la sua preoccupazione per il benessere dei suoi servitori, Ya Malik Al Mulki è il Possessore della Sovranità... Colui che possiede il dominio su tutte le cose. È il sovrano e l\'autorità ultima. Questo nome significa la regalità di Allah e il suo controllo assoluto sull\'universo. Riflette la sua sovranità e il suo diritto di comandare e decretare, Ya Jal-Jalali Al Ikram è Colui che possiede grandezza e nobiltà. È maestoso e degno di tutto l\'onore e il rispetto. Questo nome significa lo status esaltato di Allah e il suo diritto al rispetto. Riflette la sua dignità... magnificenza e l\'onore che gli è dovuto,Ya Muqsitu è Colui che è giusto e equo in tutti i suoi giudizi e azioni. Mantiene equilibrio ed equità nell\'universo. Questo nome significa l\'impegno di Allah per la giustizia e l\'equità. Riflette il suo ruolo nel garantire che tutte le azioni siano ricompensate o punite in modo appropriato, Ya Jaami\'u\' è Colui che riunisce ciò che vuole... quando vuole. Riunirà tutte le creature per il Giorno del Giudizio. Questo nome significa la capacità di Allah di radunare e unire. Riflette il suo potere di riunire tutti gli esseri per renderli responsabili, Ya Ghaniu è Colui che è privo di qualsiasi bisogno. È autosufficiente e indipendente da tutta la creazione. Questo nome significa la ricchezza di Allah e la sua mancanza di bisogno di qualcosa al di fuori di sé stesso. Riflette la sua assoluta sufficienza e indipendenza, Ya Mughniu è Colui che fornisce ricchezza e sufficienza alle sue creature. Arricchisce chi vuole. Questo nome significa la generosità di Allah e la sua capacità di concedere prosperità. Riflette il suo ruolo nel concedere abbondanza e ricchezza ai suoi servi, Ya Mani\'u\' è Colui che impedisce che si verifichi danno o male. È il protettore e il difensore. Questo nome significa la capacità di Allah di proteggere e schermare dal pericolo. Riflette il suo ruolo nel proteggere la sua creazione dal danno, Ya Dharru è Colui che può causare danno o afflizione se lo vuole. Ha il controllo su tutte le circostanze. Questo nome significa il potere di Allah sull\'avversità e sulle difficoltà. Riflette la sua autorità nel provocare prove come test o punizione, Ya Nafi\'u è Colui che porta benefici e benedizioni. Conferisce bontà e benessere. Questo nome significa il ruolo di Allah nel fornire e facilitare esiti positivi. Riflette la sua capacità di concedere benefici e favorire, Ya Nuru è la Luce... Colui che illumina i cieli e la terra. Guida e fornisce chiarezza. Questo nome significa il ruolo di Allah come fonte di guida e illuminazione. Riflette la sua capacità di portare luce nell\'oscurità e chiarezza nella confusione, Ya Hadiu è Colui che guida i suoi servi sulla retta via. Fornisce direzione e ispirazione. Questo nome significa il ruolo di Allah come fonte di guida e saggezza. Riflette la sua capacità di condurre la sua creazione verso la rettitudine e la verità, Ya Badi\'iu è l\'Incomparabile... Colui che crea in modi incomparabili e meravigliosi. È unico nella sua creazione. Questo nome significa l\'originalità di Allah e il suo incomparabile potere creativo. Riflette la sua capacità di creare senza precedenti o modelli, Ya Baaqiu è l\'Eterno... Colui che rimane quando tutto il resto perisce. È eterno e immutabile. Questo nome significa la permanenza di Allah e la sua esistenza al di là del tempo. Riflette la sua continuità e la natura eterna del suo essere, Ya Waarithu è l\'Erede... Colui che rimane dopo che tutta la creazione è giunta al termine. Erediterà la terra e tutto ciò che contiene. Questo nome significa la proprietà finale di Allah e la sua presenza duratura. Riflette il suo ruolo come possessore finale di tutte le cose, Ya Rashidu è il Maestro Giusto... Colui che guida sulla via della rettitudine. Fornisce saggezza e comprensione corretta. Questo nome significa il ruolo di Allah come insegnante e guida. Riflette la sua capacità di condurre i suoi servi verso una conoscenza retta e benefica, Ya Sabooru è il Paziente... Colui che non si affretta a punire i peccatori. È paziente e tollerante. Questo nome significa la pazienza di Allah e la sua moderazione nel ritardare la punizione. Riflette la sua volontà di dare tempo per il pentimento e la sua resistenza nel trattare con le trasgressioni umane."</string>
    <!--    dutch-->
    <string name="app_name_de">99 Namen van Allah</string>
    <string name="language_de">Dutch</string>
    <string name="names_de">"1. Ya Rahmanu,2.	Ya Raheemu,3.	Ya Maliku,4.	Ya Quddusu,5.	Ya Salamu,6.	Ya Mu\'minu,7.	Ya Muhayminu,8.	Ya Azizu,9.	Ya Jabbaaru,10.	Ya Mutakabbiru,11.	Ya Khaaliqu,12.	Ya Baariu,13.	Ya Musawwiru,14.	Ya Ghaffaaru,15.	Ya Qahhaaru,16.	Ya Wahhaabu,17.	Ya Razzaaqu,18.	Ya Fattaahu,19.	Ya Alimu,20.	Ya Qaabidhu,21.	Ya Baasitu,22.	Ya Khaafidhu,23.	Ya Raafi\'u,24.	Ya Mu\'izzu,25.	Ya Muzillu,26.	Ya Sami\'u,27.	Ya Basiru,28.	Ya Hakamu,29.	Ya \'Adlu,30.	Ya Latifu,31.	Ya Khabiru,32.	Ya Halimu,33.	Ya-‘Adheemu,34.	Ya Ghafuru,35.	Ya Shakuru,36.	Ya Aliu,37.	Ya Kabiru,38.	Ya Hafidhu,39.	Ya Muqitu,40.	Ya Hasibu,41.	Ya Jalilu,42.	Ya Karimu,43.	Ya Raqibu,44.	Ya Mujibu,45.	Ya Wasi\'u,46.	Ya Hakimu,47.	Ya Wadudu,48.	Ya Majeedu,49.	Ya Ba\'ithu,50.	Ya Shaheedu,51.	Ya Haqqu,52.	Ya Wakilu,53.	Ya Qawiyyu,54.	Ya Mateenu,55.	Ya Waliu,56.	Ya Hamiduu,57.	Ya Muhsi,58.	Ya Mubdiu,59.	Ya Mu\'idu,60.	Ya Muhyi,61.	Ya Mumitu,62.	Ya Hayyu,63.	Ya Qayyumu,64.	Ya Waajidu,65.	Ya Maajidu,66.	Ya Waahidu,67.	Ya Ahadu,68.	Ya Samadu,69.	Ya Qaadiru,70.	Ya Muqtadiru,71.	Ya Muqaddimu,72.	Ya Mu\'akhkhiru,73.	Ya Awwalu,74.	Ya Aakhiru,75.	Ya Dhaahiru,76.	Ya Baatinu,77.	Ya Waaliu,78.	Ya Muta\'ali,79.	Ya Barru,80.	Ya Tawwaabu,81.	Ya Muntaqimu,82.	Ya \'Afuwwu,83.	Ya Ra\'ufu,84.	Ya Malik Al Mulki,85.	Ya Jal-Jalali Al Ikram,86.	Ya Muqsitu,87.	Ya Jaami\'u,88.	Ya Ghaniu,89.	Ya Mughniu,90.	Ya Mani\'u,91.	Ya Dharru,92.	Ya Nafi\'u,93.	Ya Nuru,94.	Ya Hadiu,95.	Ya Badi\'iu,96.	Ya Baaqiu,97.	Ya Waarithu,98.	Ya Rashidu,99.	Ya Sabooru"</string>

    <string name="meaning_de">"De Weldadige,De Genadevol le,De Eeuwige Heer,De Allerheiligste,De Belichaming van Vrede,De Gever van Geloof,De Bewaker van Veiligheid,De Machtige,De Almachtige,De Dominante,De Schepper,De Evoluerende,De Perfecte Vormgever,De Grote Vergever,De Alomtegenwoordige,De Hoogste Schenker,De Totale Voorziener,De Hoogste Oplosser,De Alwetende,De Beperkende,De Verbreder,De Verminderende,De Verheffer,De Eerbrenger-Schenker,De Vernederaar,De Alles-Horende,De Alles-Ziende,De Onpartijdige Rechter,De Belichaming van Gerechtigheid,De Kenner van Subtiliteiten,De Alwetende,De Genadevolle,De Grote,De Grote Vergever,De Erkennende,De Verhevene,De Grote,De Beschermer,De Onderhouder,De Rekeninghouder,De Majestueuze,De Gulzige,De Waakzame,De Antwoordende,De Alomtegenwoordige,De Wijze,De Liefdevolle,De Glorieuze,De Nieuwe Levengever,De Alles Observerende Getuige,De Belichaming van Waarheid,De Universele Trustee,De Sterke,De Stevige,De Beschermende Partner,De Unieke Prijzenswaardige,De Alomvattende,De Oorsprong,De Hersteller,De Onderhouder van het Leven,De Levenseindigende,De Eeuwig Levende,De Zelfvoorzienende,De Wijzer,De Edel,De Enige,De Enige,De Hoogste Voorziener,De Almachtige,De Alautoritaire,De Versnellende,De Uitsteller,De Eerste,De Laatste,De Waarneembare,De Onwaarneembare,De Bezitter van de Hoogste Autoriteit,De Extreem Verhevene,De Bron van Waarheid,De Altijd Accepterende van Berouw,De Wreker,De Hoogste Vergever,De Vriendelijke,De Eeuwige Bezitter van Soevereiniteit,De Bezitter van Majesteit en Eer,De Rechtvaardige,De Verzamelaar van Verspreide Scheppingen,De Zelfvoorzienende,De Schenker van Voldoende,De Voorkomer,De Beroerder,De Schenker van Voordelen,Het Primaire Licht,De Leider,De Unieke,De Altijd Overlevende,De Eeuwige Erfgenaam,De Gids naar het Pad van Rechtschapenheid,De Extreem Duurzame"</string>
    <string name="des_de">"Ya Rahmanu is Degene die goedheid en genade wil voor al Zijn schepselen. Hij schenkt immense genade en zegeningen aan het universum en toont mededogen aan alle wezens. Zijn genade is groot en omvat alle dingen... ongeacht hun geloof of daden. Deze naam weerspiegelt Allah\'s zorgzame zorg voor de hele schepping., Ya Raheemu is Degene die handelt met extreme vriendelijkheid en mededogen... vooral jegens gelovigen. Zijn genade is eeuwig en manifesteert zich zowel in deze wereld als in het Hiernamaals. Deze naam betekent Allah\'s vergeving en de beloningen die Hij voorbereidt voor de gelovigen. Het benadrukt Zijn zachte en medelevende aard., Ya Maliku is de Soevereine Heer... Degene met volledige heerschappij over het universum. Zijn heerschappij is absoluut... en Zijn autoriteit is perfect en vrij van elke imperfectie. Deze naam illustreert Allah\'s macht en controle over alle zaken... zowel zichtbaar als onzichtbaar. Hij regeert de hele schepping met wijsheid en rechtvaardigheid., Ya Quddusu is Degene die puur is van elke imperfectie en verheven is boven alle gebreken en zwakheden. Hij is vrij van alle attributen die defect of tekortkoming impliceren. Deze naam benadrukt Allah\'s zuiverheid en heiligheid. Het weerspiegelt Zijn transcendentie en heiligheid... die menselijk begrip te boven gaat., Ya Salamu is Degene die vrij is van elke imperfectie en vrede en veiligheid schenkt aan Zijn schepping. Hij verleent rust aan harten en geesten... en zorgt voor veiligheid en harmonie. Deze naam betekent Allah\'s perfectie en de vrede die voortkomt uit overgave aan Hem. Het benadrukt Zijn rol als de gever van sereniteit., Ya Mu\'minu is Degene die veiligheid biedt en de waarheid van Zijn trouwe gelovigen bevestigt. Hij biedt bescherming en vrede... en beschermt hen tegen angst en schade. Deze naam benadrukt Allah\'s rol in het bieden van veiligheid en vertrouwen. Het verzekert de gelovigen ook van de waarheid van hun geloof en de realiteit van Zijn beloften., Ya Muhayminu is Degene die waakt over en beschermt al Zijn schepselen... wetende wat hun daden en gedachten zijn. Hij onderhoudt en overziet alle dingen met perfecte kennis en autoriteit. Deze naam weerspiegelt Allah\'s waakzaamheid en Zijn bewaking over alles. Het verzekert gelovigen van Zijn constante zorg en aandacht., Ya Azizu is Degene die machtig en sterk is... de Overweldiger die niet overwonnen wordt. Hij is ongeëvenaard in macht en eer... en overwint al Zijn vijanden. Deze naam illustreert Allah\'s kracht en onoverwinnelijkheid. Het toont Zijn vermogen om te zegevieren en degenen te beschermen die Zijn hulp zoeken., Ya Jabbaaru is Degene die dwingt en herstelt... en Zijn wil oplegt aan Zijn schepping. Hij herstelt het gebrokene en legt Zijn decreet op aan alles wat bestaat. Deze naam betekent Allah\'s macht om Zijn geboden te handhaven en zaken te rectificeren. Het weerspiegelt ook Zijn vermogen om te genezen en balans te herstellen., Ya Mutakabbiru is Degene die vrij is van de attributen van de schepselen en het op hen lijken... en die uiterst groot is. Hij alleen bezit grootheid en majesteit die het begrip te boven gaan. Deze naam benadrukt Allah\'s superioriteit en transcendentie boven alle schepselen. Het benadrukt Zijn verheven status en de waardigheid van Zijn goddelijke wezen., Ya Khaaliqu is Degene die alles van niet-bestaan naar bestaan brengt. Hij schept alle dingen met precisie en doel. Deze naam weerspiegelt Allah\'s vermogen om schepping te beginnen en te innoveren. Het benadrukt Zijn rol als de ultieme Schepper van het universum en alles wat het bevat., Ya Baariu is de Maker... de Schepper die de macht heeft om entiteiten in verschillende staten te veranderen. Hij brengt voort en evolueert Zijn schepping volgens Zijn wijsheid. Deze naam betekent Allah\'s creativiteit en Zijn vermogen om Zijn schepselen op unieke manieren te vormen. Het benadrukt Zijn rol in het vormen en ontwikkelen van alle levensvormen., Ya Musawwiru is Degene die Zijn schepselen in verschillende vormen en gedaantes vormt. Hij geeft elk schepsel zijn unieke kenmerken en eigenschappen. Deze naam benadrukt Allah\'s artistieke kracht en aandacht voor detail in de schepping. Het weerspiegelt Zijn vermogen om vorm te geven en vorm te geven aan alle wezens., Ya Ghaffaaru is Degene die keer op keer de zonden van Zijn dienaren vergeeft. Zijn vergeving is groot en bedekt zelfs de ernstigste zonden voor degenen die berouw tonen. Deze naam betekent Allah\'s grenzeloze genade en bereidheid om te vergeven. Het benadrukt Zijn bereidheid om te vergeven en degenen te reinigen die Zijn vergeving zoeken., Ya Qahhaaru is de Dominante... Degene die de perfecte macht heeft en niet onmachtig is over iets. Hij overweldigt en onderwerpt Zijn schepping zoals Hij wil. Deze naam illustreert Allah\'s absolute controle en dominantie over alle dingen. Het weerspiegelt Zijn vermogen om te onderwerpen en Zijn opperste autoriteit., Ya Wahhaabu is Degene die Gul is in het geven van overvloed zonder enige tegenprestatie. Hij schenkt geschenken en zegeningen uit Zijn overvloed en genade. Deze naam betekent Allah\'s vrijgevigheid en vriendelijkheid. Het benadrukt Zijn rol als de gever van alles wat ten goede komt... zowel wettig als verboden.,Ya Razzaaqu is de Onderhouder... de Voorziener die zorgt voor het levensonderhoud van al Zijn schepselen. Hij verdeelt voorzieningen met wijsheid en vrijgevigheid. Deze naam benadrukt Allah\'s rol in het voorzien in de behoeften van Zijn schepping. Het onderstreept Zijn zorg en welwillendheid in het in stand houden van het leven., Ya Fattaahu is de Opener... de Ontlaster... de Rechter die voor Zijn dienaren de gesloten wereldlijke en religieuze zaken opent. Hij schenkt overwinning... verlichting en oplossingen voor moeilijkheden. Deze naam betekent Allah\'s kracht om obstakels te verwijderen en leiding te geven. Het weerspiegelt Zijn rol in het vergemakkelijken van wegen en het oplossen van problemen., Ya Alimu is de Wetende... Degene voor wie niets afwezig is uit Zijn kennis. Hij is op de hoogte van alle dingen... verleden... heden en toekomst. Deze naam benadrukt Allah\'s alwetendheid en Zijn perfecte kennis van alle zaken. Het onderstreept Zijn bewustzijn en begrip van de hele schepping., Ya Qaabidhu is Degene die het levensonderhoud beperkt door Zijn wijsheid. Hij onthoudt voorzieningen volgens Zijn goddelijk plan. Deze naam betekent Allah\'s controle over de verdeling van middelen. Het benadrukt Zijn wijsheid in het bepalen wat het beste is voor Zijn schepping., Ya Baasitu is Degene die het levensonderhoud vergroot en verruimt met Zijn vrijgevigheid en genade. Hij verhoogt voorzieningen en schenkt overvloed. Deze naam weerspiegelt Allah\'s vriendelijkheid en gulheid. Het benadrukt Zijn vermogen om Zijn schepping te verrijken en te zegenen met overvloedige middelen., Ya Khaafidhu is Degene die verlaagt wie Hij wil door Zijn vernietiging. Hij brengt degenen neer die het verdienen vernederd te worden. Deze naam betekent Allah\'s rechtvaardigheid en Zijn kracht om te vernederen. Het weerspiegelt Zijn rol in het in evenwicht brengen van de weegschaal van rechtvaardigheid door de arrogante en onrechtvaardige te verlagen., Ya Raafi\'u is de Verheffer... Degene die verhoogt wie Hij wil door Zijn schenking. Hij verheft de status van de rechtvaardigen en deugdzaamen. Deze naam benadrukt Allah\'s vermogen om te eren en te verheffen. Het weerspiegelt Zijn vrijgevigheid in het toekennen van hoge rangen en waardigheid aan Zijn trouwe dienaren., Ya Mu\'izzu is Degene die eer schenkt aan wie Hij wil; daarom is er niemand die hem kan vernederen. Hij schenkt eer en waardigheid aan Zijn uitverkorenen. Deze naam betekent Allah\'s macht om te eren en te verheffen. Het weerspiegelt Zijn autoriteit in het schenken van respect en status., Ya Muzillu is de Vernederaar... Degene die vernedert wie Hij wil; daarom is er niemand die hem eer kan geven. Hij brengt de arrogante en onrechtvaardige neer. Deze naam benadrukt Allah\'s rechtvaardigheid in het verlagen van de onwaardige. Het weerspiegelt Zijn kracht om te vernederen en degenen te vernederen die Zijn geboden tarten., Ya Sami\'u is Degene die alle dingen hoort die gehoord worden door Zijn eeuwig gehoor zonder oor... instrument of orgaan. Hij luistert naar de gebeden en smeekbeden van Zijn schepping. Deze naam betekent Allah\'s perfecte en uitgebreide gehoor. Het weerspiegelt Zijn aandacht voor de behoeften en smeekbeden van Zijn dienaren., Ya Basiru is Degene die alle dingen ziet die gezien worden door Zijn eeuwig zicht zonder pupil of enig ander instrument. Hij observeert alle handelingen en gebeurtenissen in het universum. Deze naam benadrukt Allah\'s alomtegenwoordige visie. Het weerspiegelt Zijn bewustzijn en waakzaamheid over de hele schepping., Ya Hakamu is de Heerser... en Zijn oordeel is Zijn woord. Hij beslecht alle zaken met rechtvaardigheid en wijsheid. Deze naam betekent Allah\'s rol als de ultieme arbiter en rechter. Het benadrukt Zijn autoriteit in het maken van rechtvaardige beslissingen en Zijn laatste woord in alle zaken., Ya \'Adlu is Degene die gerechtigd is te doen wat Hij doet. Zijn daden en oordelen zijn rechtvaardig en eerlijk. Deze naam weerspiegelt Allah\'s perfecte rechtvaardigheid en evenwicht. Het onderstreept Zijn rol in het handhaven van rechtvaardigheid en rechtschapenheid in het universum., Ya Latifu is de Genadige... Degene die vriendelijk is voor Zijn dienaren en hen begunstigt. Hij begrijpt de fijnste mysteries en intricaties. Deze naam betekent Allah\'s zachte en medelevende aard. Het benadrukt Zijn vriendelijkheid en Zijn subtiele manieren om genade en barmhartigheid te schenken., Ya Khabiru is Degene die de waarheid van dingen kent. Hij is volledig op de hoogte van alle verborgen en duidelijke zaken. Deze naam benadrukt Allah\'s diepe kennis en bewustzijn. Het weerspiegelt Zijn begrip van de ware essentie van alle dingen., Ya Halimu is Degene die de bestraffing voor degenen die het verdienen uitstelt en hen dan misschien vergeeft. Hij is geduldig en lankmoedig. Deze naam betekent Allah\'s tolerantie en geduld. Het weerspiegelt Zijn bereidheid om tijd te geven voor berouw en correctie., Ya-\'Adheemu is de Machtige... Degene die verheven is... glorierijk... verheven en zuiver van alle imperfectie. Hij is majestueus en groot in elk opzicht. Deze naam benadrukt Allah\'s grootheid en majesteit. Het weerspiegelt Zijn verheven status en de eerbied die Hij verdient., Ya Ghafuru is de Vergevensgezinde... Degene die veel vergeeft. Zijn vergeving is uitgebreid en dekt alle zonden voor degenen die oprecht berouw tonen. Deze naam betekent Allah\'s immense genade en bereidheid om te vergeven. Het benadrukt Zijn vrijgevigheid in het vergeven en over het hoofd zien van fouten., Ya Shakuru is Degene die veel beloning geeft voor een beetje gehoorzaamheid. Hij erkent en beloont zelfs de kleinste daden van goedheid. Deze naam weerspiegelt Allah\'s vrijgevigheid en waardering voor de inspanningen van Zijn dienaren. Het benadrukt Zijn bereidheid om beloningen voor goede daden te vermenigvuldigen., Ya Aliu is Degene die vrij is van de attributen van de schepselen. Hij is verheven boven de hele schepping. Deze naam betekent Allah\'s hoogste status en transcendentie. Het weerspiegelt Zijn hoge rang en de zuiverheid van Zijn goddelijke essentie.,Ya Kabiru is de Grote... Degene die in status groter is dan alles. Zijn grootsheid is onbegrijpelijk. Deze naam benadrukt Allah\'s immense grootheid. Het onderstreept Zijn superioriteit over alles wat bestaat., Ya Hafidhu is de Beschermer... Degene die beschermt wat en wie Hij wil beschermen. Hij behoedt de hele schepping voor schade. Deze naam betekent Allah\'s rol als bewaker en beschermer. Het weerspiegelt Zijn vermogen om Zijn schepping te onderhouden en te beschermen., Ya Muqitu is de Wachter... de Voeder... Degene die de macht heeft om alle dingen in stand te houden. Hij voorziet in levensonderhoud en ondersteunt al het leven. Deze naam benadrukt Allah\'s rol in het onderhouden en voeden van Zijn schepping. Het onderstreept Zijn voortdurende zorg en voorziening., Ya Hasibu is Degene die voldoening geeft. Hij is voldoende als beschermer en berekenaar. Deze naam betekent Allah\'s vermogen om voor alle acties en daden te rekenen. Het weerspiegelt Zijn rol in het bieden van vergelding en het waarborgen van rechtvaardigheid., Ya Jalilu is de Weldadige... Degene die wordt toegeschreven met grootheid van macht en glorie van status. Hij is majestueus en vereerd. Deze naam benadrukt Allah\'s grootsheid en majesteit. Het weerspiegelt Zijn verheven status en de eerbied die Hij opeist., Ya Karimu is de Genadevolle... Degene die wordt toegeschreven met grootheid van macht en glorie van status. Hij is overvloedig en vriendelijk. Deze naam betekent Allah\'s vrijgevigheid en welwillendheid. Het benadrukt Zijn bereidheid om te geven en gunsten te schenken., Ya Raqibu is Degene van wie niets afwezig is. Hij observeert alle handelingen en gedachten. Deze naam benadrukt Allah\'s waakzaamheid en bewustzijn. Het weerspiegelt Zijn vermogen om de hele schepping te monitoren en te overzien., Ya Mujibu is de Verhoorder... Degene die degene in nood antwoordt als hij Hem vraagt en de verlangende redt als hij Hem aanroept. Hij reageert op gebeden en smeekbeden. Deze naam betekent Allah\'s bereidheid om te antwoorden en te helpen. Het benadrukt Zijn ontvankelijkheid voor de oproepen van Zijn dienaren., Ya Wasi\'u is de Oneindige... Degene wiens kennis en genade alle dingen omvatten. Hij is grenzeloos in Zijn eigenschappen. Deze naam weerspiegelt Allah\'s oneindige aard en grenzeloze mededogen. Het benadrukt Zijn vermogen om de hele schepping te omhullen met Zijn genade en kennis., Ya Hakimu is de Rechter der Rechters... Degene die correct is in Zijn daden. Zijn wijsheid beheerst alle handelingen en decreten. Deze naam betekent Allah\'s perfecte wijsheid en oordeel. Het benadrukt Zijn vermogen om rechtvaardige en wijze beslissingen te nemen., Ya Wadudu is Degene die Zijn gelovige dienaren liefheeft en wiens gelovigen Hem liefhebben. Zijn liefde komt tot uiting in Zijn genade en lof voor hen. Deze naam weerspiegelt Allah\'s genegenheid en vriendelijkheid jegens Zijn trouwe dienaren. Het benadrukt de wederzijdse liefde tussen de Schepper en Zijn schepping., Ya Majeedu is Degene met perfecte macht... hoge status... mededogen... vrijgevigheid en vriendelijkheid. Hij is majestueus en eerbiedwaardig. Deze naam betekent Allah\'s grootsheid en edelmoedigheid. Het benadrukt Zijn verheven positie en de glorie van Zijn eigenschappen., Ya Ba\'ithu is de Opwekker (uit de dood)... Degene die Zijn dienaren na de dood doet herleven voor beloning en/of straf. Hij brengt de doden tot leven. Deze naam betekent Allah\'s macht over leven en dood. Het weerspiegelt Zijn vermogen om wederopstanding te bewerkstelligen en alle wezens te oordelen., Ya Shaheedu is Degene van wie niets afwezig is. Hij is getuige van alle handelingen en gebeurtenissen. Deze naam benadrukt Allah\'s alomtegenwoordigheid en Zijn rol als immer aanwezige getuige. Het weerspiegelt Zijn bewustzijn van alles wat in het universum gebeurt., Ya Haqqu is de Ware... Degene die werkelijk bestaat. Zijn bestaan is absoluut en eeuwig. Deze naam betekent Allah\'s realiteit en authenticiteit. Het benadrukt Zijn positie als de ultieme waarheid en de basis van al het bestaan., Ya Wakilu is Degene die voldoening geeft en op wie men kan vertrouwen. Hij is de beste bewaker en vertrouwenspersoon. Deze naam weerspiegelt Allah\'s betrouwbaarheid en vertrouwen. Het benadrukt Zijn rol als degene aan wie alle zaken worden toevertrouwd., Ya Qawiyyu is de Sterke... Degene met volledige macht. Hij is machtig en krachtig zonder maat. Deze naam betekent Allah\'s kracht en autoriteit. Het benadrukt Zijn vermogen om alle dingen te volbrengen en Zijn schepping te beschermen., Ya Mateenu is Degene met extreme macht die ononderbroken is en die niet moe wordt. Zijn kracht is solide en onveranderlijk. Deze naam weerspiegelt Allah\'s standvastigheid en veerkracht. Het benadrukt Zijn blijvende kracht en standvastigheid., Ya Waliu is de Ondersteuner en beschermer. Hij is bevriend en helpt Zijn rechtvaardige dienaren. Deze naam betekent Allah\'s nabijheid en steun. Het weerspiegelt Zijn rol als beschermer en bondgenoot voor degenen die Zijn bescherming zoeken., Ya Hamiduu is Degene die geprezen wordt en die het verdient geprezen te worden. Zijn eigenschappen en daden zijn het waard om geprezen te worden. Deze naam weerspiegelt Allah\'s waardigheid voor dankbaarheid en bewondering. Het benadrukt Zijn lofwaardige aard en de eer die Hem toekomt., Ya Muhsi is Degene die de telling van dingen kent. Hij is op de hoogte van alle hoeveelheden en maten. Deze naam betekent Allah\'s alomvattende kennis van alle details. Het weerspiegelt Zijn vermogen om alles in het bestaan te tellen., Ya Mubdiu is Degene die de mens heeft gestart. Hij schept zonder enig vooraf bestaand model. Deze naam betekent Allah\'s innovatie en originaliteit in de schepping. Het benadrukt Zijn rol als de eerste schepper van alle dingen., Ya Mu\'idu is Degene die de schepselen na de dood terugbrengt. Hij herstelt het leven en doet de doden herleven. Deze naam betekent Allah\'s macht over leven en dood. Het weerspiegelt Zijn vermogen om Zijn schepping te doen herleven en terug te brengen., Ya Muhyi is Degene die leven geeft aan de levenloze. Hij herleeft zowel fysiek als spiritueel leven. Deze naam betekent Allah\'s rol in het scheppen en in stand houden van leven. Het benadrukt Zijn vermogen om leven te schenken en te vernieuwen.,Ya Mumitu is Degene die het levende dood maakt. Hij heeft controle over leven en dood. Deze naam betekent Allah\'s macht om leven weg te nemen. Het weerspiegelt Zijn autoriteit over het einde van het leven en de overgang naar het hiernamaals., Ya Hayyu is Degene die wordt toegeschreven met een leven dat niet zoals ons leven is en niet dat van een combinatie van ziel... vlees of bloed. Hij bezit eeuwig en zelfvoorzienend leven. Deze naam betekent Allah\'s unieke en eeuwige bestaan. Het weerspiegelt Zijn vitaliteit en de bron van het leven zelf., Ya Qayyumu is Degene die blijft en niet eindigt. Hij onderhoudt alle dingen door Zichzelf en heeft geen ondersteuning nodig. Deze naam betekent Allah\'s zelfvoorzienendheid en onafhankelijkheid. Het weerspiegelt Zijn eeuwige bestaan en Zijn rol als de onderhouder van de hele schepping., Ya Waajidu is de Vinder... de Rijke die nooit arm is. Hij is zelfvoorzienend en overvloedig in rijkdom. Deze naam betekent Allah\'s rijkdom en Zijn vermogen om in alle behoeften te voorzien. Het weerspiegelt Zijn volledigheid en de toereikendheid van Zijn eigenschappen., Ya Maajidu is de Allerheerlijkste... Degene met perfecte macht. Zijn grootsheid is ongeëvenaard en stralend. Deze naam betekent Allah\'s pracht en praal. Het weerspiegelt Zijn majestueuze aanwezigheid en de glorie van Zijn goddelijke essentie., Ya Waahidu is de Ene... de Eeuwige... de Onafhankelijke. Hij is uniek en onvergelijkbaar. Deze naam betekent Allah\'s eenheid en uniciteit. Het weerspiegelt Zijn absolute eenheid en onafhankelijkheid van de hele schepping., Ya Ahadu is Degene zonder partner... de Unieke. Hij heeft geen gelijke of rivaal. Deze naam betekent Allah\'s ondeelbare eenheid en singulariteit. Het weerspiegelt Zijn exclusieve status als de enige godheid die waard is om aanbeden te worden., Ya Samadu is de Eeuwige... de Onafhankelijke... de Meester op wie vertrouwd wordt. Hij is eeuwig en onveranderlijk. Deze naam betekent Allah\'s eeuwige natuur en Zijn rol als de ultieme bron van ondersteuning. Het weerspiegelt Zijn permanentie en bestendigheid., Ya Qaadiru is de Machtige... Degene die wordt toegeschreven met Macht. Hij heeft het vermogen om alle dingen te volbrengen. Deze naam betekent Allah\'s almacht en Zijn controle over alle zaken. Het weerspiegelt Zijn onbeperkte kracht en autoriteit., Ya Muqtadiru is de Dominante... Degene met volledige Macht. Zijn autoriteit is absoluut en onweerstaanbaar. Deze naam betekent Allah\'s soevereiniteit en Zijn vermogen om Zijn wil af te dwingen. Het weerspiegelt Zijn opperste macht en controle over de hele schepping., Ya Muqaddimu is Degene die vooruitgaat en versnelt. Hij geeft prioriteit en faciliteert zaken volgens Zijn wijsheid. Deze naam betekent Allah\'s vermogen om gebeurtenissen te versnellen en te bespoedigen. Het weerspiegelt Zijn kracht om snel en resoluut resultaten te bereiken., Ya Mu\'akhkhiru is Degene die uitstelt en vertraagt. Hij stelt gebeurtenissen uit volgens Zijn goddelijk plan. Deze naam betekent Allah\'s wijsheid in het uitstellen van uitkomsten voor een groter doel. Het weerspiegelt Zijn controle over de tijd en Zijn vermogen om het tempo van gebeurtenissen te bepalen., Ya Awwalu is de Eerste... Degene die bestond voor alles. Hij is de oorsprong en bron van alle schepping. Deze naam betekent Allah\'s voorrang en Zijn tijdloze bestaan. Het weerspiegelt Zijn primaat en het begin van alle dingen., Ya Aakhiru is de Laatste... Degene die zal blijven nadat alles is vergaan. Hij is eeuwig en onvergankelijk. Deze naam betekent Allah\'s permanentie en Zijn aanwezigheid voorbij het einde van de tijd. Het weerspiegelt Zijn finaliteit en de uiteindelijke conclusie van al het bestaan., Ya Dhaahiru is de Manifest... Degene wiens aanwezigheid evident en duidelijk is. Hij is duidelijk en zichtbaar in Zijn tekenen en scheppingen. Deze naam betekent Allah\'s zichtbaarheid en Zijn manifestatie in het universum. Het weerspiegelt Zijn helderheid en de duidelijke weergave van Zijn eigenschappen., Ya Baatinu is de Verborgen... Degene wiens essentie verborgen en mysterieus is. Hij is buiten menselijke waarneming en begrip. Deze naam betekent Allah\'s onzichtbaarheid en Zijn verborgen aard. Het weerspiegelt Zijn transcendentie en de diepte van Zijn goddelijke essentie., Ya Waaliu is de Beschermer... de Beschermende Vriend die Zijn dienaren begeleidt en ondersteunt. Hij is hun bondgenoot en bewaker. Deze naam betekent Allah\'s nabijheid en Zijn rol als een ondersteunende metgezel. Het weerspiegelt Zijn zorg en begeleiding voor degenen die Zijn bescherming zoeken., Ya Muta\'ali is de Hoogst Verhevene... Degene wiens status ongeëvenaard is. Hij is verheven boven alle schepping. Deze naam betekent Allah\'s transcendentie en Zijn verheven rang. Het weerspiegelt Zijn superioriteit en de verhevenheid van Zijn goddelijke essentie., Ya Barru is de Bron van Goedheid... Degene die vriendelijk en welwillend is. Hij schenkt zegeningen en gunsten aan Zijn schepping. Deze naam betekent Allah\'s goedheid en Zijn overvloedige genade. Het weerspiegelt Zijn vrijgevigheid en de overvloed van Zijn zegeningen., Ya Tawwaabu is de Altijd Bekeerde... Degene die berouw accepteert en zonden vergeeft. Hij is genadig en mededogend. Deze naam betekent Allah\'s bereidheid om te vergeven en Zijn bereidheid om degenen die zich tot Hem wenden in berouw te accepteren. Het weerspiegelt Zijn grenzeloze genade en Zijn uitnodiging om tot Hem terug te keren., Ya Muntaqimu is de Wreker... Degene die degenen straft die Zijn grenzen overschrijden. Hij handhaaft gerechtigheid en vergelding. Deze naam betekent Allah\'s toorn tegen onrechtvaardigheid en Zijn toewijding aan het handhaven van rechtvaardigheid. Het weerspiegelt Zijn rol als de ultieme rechter en uitvoerder van goddelijke rechtvaardigheid., Ya \'Afuwwu is de Vergever... Degene die vergeeft en fouten over het hoofd ziet. Hij wist zonden uit en schenkt absolutie. Deze naam betekent Allah\'s genade en Zijn bereidheid om te vergeven zonder wrok te koesteren. Het weerspiegelt Zijn vrijgevigheid in het vergeven van Zijn dienaren., Ya Ra\'ufu is de Barmhartige... Degene die teder en genadig is. Hij voelt empathie voor Zijn schepping en toont hen mededogen. Deze naam betekent Allah\'s zachtheid en Zijn zorgzame aard. Het weerspiegelt Zijn medeleven en zorg voor het welzijn van Zijn dienaren., Ya Malik Al Mulki is de Eigenaar van Soevereiniteit... Degene die heerschappij heeft over alle dingen. Hij is de ultieme heerser en autoriteit. Deze naam betekent Allah\'s koningschap en Zijn absolute controle over het universum. Het weerspiegelt Zijn soevereiniteit en Zijn recht om te bevelen en te beslissen., Ya Jal-Jalali Al Ikram is Degene die grootheid en edelheid bezit. Hij is majestueus en waardig voor alle eer en respect. Deze naam betekent Allah\'s verheven status en Zijn waardigheid voor eerbied. Het weerspiegelt Zijn waardigheid... pracht en de eer die Hem toekomt.,Ya Muqsitu is Degene die eerlijk en rechtvaardig is in al Zijn oordelen en daden. Hij handhaaft balans en rechtvaardigheid in het universum. Deze naam betekent Allah\'s toewijding aan rechtvaardigheid en eerlijkheid. Het weerspiegelt Zijn rol in het verzekeren dat alle daden passend worden beloond of gestraft., Ya Jaami\'u is Degene die samenbrengt wat Hij wil... wanneer Hij wil. Hij zal alle schepselen verzamelen voor de Dag des Oordeels. Deze naam betekent Allah\'s vermogen om bijeen te brengen en te verenigen. Het weerspiegelt Zijn kracht om alle wezens bijeen te brengen voor verantwoording., Ya Ghaniu is Degene die vrij is van elke behoefte. Hij is zelfvoorzienend en onafhankelijk van de hele schepping. Deze naam betekent Allah\'s rijkdom en Zijn gebrek aan behoefte aan iets buiten Hemzelf. Het weerspiegelt Zijn absolute toereikendheid en onafhankelijkheid., Ya Mughniu is Degene die rijkdom en toereikendheid schenkt aan Zijn schepselen. Hij verrijkt wie Hij wil. Deze naam betekent Allah\'s vrijgevigheid en Zijn vermogen om voorspoed te schenken. Het weerspiegelt Zijn rol in het verlenen van overvloed en rijkdom aan Zijn dienaren., Ya Mani\'u is Degene die voorkomt dat schade of kwaad plaatsvindt. Hij is de beschermer en verdediger. Deze naam betekent Allah\'s vermogen om te beschermen en te behoeden voor gevaar. Het weerspiegelt Zijn rol in het veiligstellen van Zijn schepping tegen schade., Ya Dharru is Degene die schade of beproeving kan veroorzaken als Hij dat wil. Hij heeft controle over alle omstandigheden. Deze naam betekent Allah\'s macht over tegenspoed en moeilijkheden. Het weerspiegelt Zijn autoriteit om beproevingen te brengen als een test of straf., Ya Nafi\'u is Degene die voordelen en zegeningen brengt. Hij schenkt goedheid en welzijn. Deze naam betekent Allah\'s rol in het verschaffen en faciliteren van positieve uitkomsten. Het weerspiegelt Zijn vermogen om voordelen en gunsten te schenken., Ya Nuru is het Licht... Degene die de hemelen en de aarde verlicht. Hij leidt en verschaft helderheid. Deze naam betekent Allah\'s rol als bron van leiding en verlichting. Het weerspiegelt Zijn vermogen om licht te brengen in duisternis en helderheid in verwarring., Ya Hadiu is Degene die Zijn dienaren naar het rechte pad leidt. Hij verschaft richting en inspiratie. Deze naam betekent Allah\'s rol als bron van leiding en wijsheid. Het weerspiegelt Zijn vermogen om Zijn schepping te leiden naar rechtvaardigheid en waarheid., Ya Badi\'iu is de Onovertroffen... Degene die op ongeëvenaarde en wonderlijke manieren creëert. Hij is uniek in Zijn schepping. Deze naam betekent Allah\'s originaliteit en Zijn ongeëvenaarde scheppingskracht. Het weerspiegelt Zijn vermogen om te creëren zonder precedent of model., Ya Baaqiu is de Eeuwige... Degene die blijft wanneer al het andere vergaat. Hij is eeuwig en onveranderlijk. Deze naam betekent Allah\'s permanentie en Zijn bestaan voorbij de tijd. Het weerspiegelt Zijn continuïteit en de eeuwige aard van Zijn wezen., Ya Waarithu is de Erfgenaam... Degene die blijft nadat de hele schepping ten einde is gekomen. Hij zal de aarde en alles erop erven. Deze naam betekent Allah\'s uiteindelijke eigendom en Zijn blijvende aanwezigheid. Het weerspiegelt Zijn rol als de uiteindelijke bezitter van alle dingen., Ya Rashidu is de Rechtvaardige Leraar... Degene die leidt naar het pad van rechtvaardigheid. Hij verschaft wijsheid en correct begrip. Deze naam betekent Allah\'s rol als leraar en gids. Het weerspiegelt Zijn vermogen om Zijn dienaren te leiden naar rechtvaardige en nuttige kennis., Ya Sabooru is de Geduldige... Degene die niet haast om zondaars te straffen. Hij is lankmoedig en tolerant. Deze naam betekent Allah\'s geduld en Zijn terughoudendheid in het uitstellen van straf. Het weerspiegelt Zijn bereidheid om tijd te geven voor berouw en Zijn uithoudingsvermogen in het omgaan met menselijke overtredingen."</string>
    <!--    portuguese-->
    <string name="app_name_pr">99 Nomes de Alá</string>
    <string name="language_pr">Português</string>
    <string name="names_pr">"1. Ya Rahmanu,2.	Ya Raheemu,3.	Ya Maliku,4.	Ya Quddusu,5.	Ya Salamu,6.	Ya Mu\'minu,7.	Ya Muhayminu,8.	Ya Azizu,9.	Ya Jabbaaru,10.	Ya Mutakabbiru,11.	Ya Khaaliqu,12.	Ya Baariu,13.	Ya Musawwiru,14.	Ya Ghaffaaru,15.	Ya Qahhaaru,16.	Ya Wahhaabu,17.	Ya Razzaaqu,18.	Ya Fattaahu,19.	Ya Alimu,20.	Ya Qaabidhu,21.	Ya Baasitu,22.	Ya Khaafidhu,23.	Ya Raafi\'u,24.	Ya Mu\'izzu,25.	Ya Muzillu,26.	Ya Sami\'u,27.	Ya Basiru,28.	Ya Hakamu,29.	Ya \'Adlu,30.	Ya Latifu,31.	Ya Khabiru,32.	Ya Halimu,33.	Ya-‘Adheemu,34.	Ya Ghafuru,35.	Ya Shakuru,36.	Ya Aliu,37.	Ya Kabiru,38.	Ya Hafidhu,39.	Ya Muqitu,40.	Ya Hasibu,41.	Ya Jalilu,42.	Ya Karimu,43.	Ya Raqibu,44.	Ya Mujibu,45.	Ya Wasi\'u,46.	Ya Hakimu,47.	Ya Wadudu,48.	Ya Majeedu,49.	Ya Ba\'ithu,50.	Ya Shaheedu,51.	Ya Haqqu,52.	Ya Wakilu,53.	Ya Qawiyyu,54.	Ya Mateenu,55.	Ya Waliu,56.	Ya Hamiduu,57.	Ya Muhsi,58.	Ya Mubdiu,59.	Ya Mu\'idu,60.	Ya Muhyi,61.	Ya Mumitu,62.	Ya Hayyu,63.	Ya Qayyumu,64.	Ya Waajidu,65.	Ya Maajidu,66.	Ya Waahidu,67.	Ya Ahadu,68.	Ya Samadu,69.	Ya Qaadiru,70.	Ya Muqtadiru,71.	Ya Muqaddimu,72.	Ya Mu\'akhkhiru,73.	Ya Awwalu,74.	Ya Aakhiru,75.	Ya Dhaahiru,76.	Ya Baatinu,77.	Ya Waaliu,78.	Ya Muta\'ali,79.	Ya Barru,80.	Ya Tawwaabu,81.	Ya Muntaqimu,82.	Ya \'Afuwwu,83.	Ya Ra\'ufu,84.	Ya Malik Al Mulki,85.	Ya Jal-Jalali Al Ikram,86.	Ya Muqsitu,87.	Ya Jaami\'u,88.	Ya Ghaniu,89.	Ya Mughniu,90.	Ya Mani\'u,91.	Ya Dharru,92.	Ya Nafi\'u,93.	Ya Nuru,94.	Ya Hadiu,95.	Ya Badi\'iu,96.	Ya Baaqiu,97.	Ya Waarithu,98.	Ya Rashidu,99.	Ya Sabooru"</string>

    <string name="meaning_pr">"O Benfeitor,O Misericordioso,O Senhor Eterno,O Mais Sagrado,A Encarnação da Paz,O Infusor de Fé,O Preservador da Segurança,O Poderoso,O Onipotente,O Dominante,O Criador,O Evolucionador,O Modelador Perfeito,O Grande Perdoador,O Todo-Poderoso,O Supremo Doador,O Provedor Total,O Supremo Solucionador,O Onisciente,O Restritivo,O Expansor,O Redutor,O Elevador,O Honrador-Doador,O Humilhador,O Todo-Ouvinte,O Todo-Observador,O Juiz Imparcial,A Encarnação da Justiça,O Conhecedor das Sutilezas,O Todo-Conhecedor,O Clemente,O Magnífico,O Grande Perdoador,O Reconhecedor,O Sublime,O Grande,O Guardião,O Sustentador,O Contador,O Majestoso,O Generoso,O Vigilante,O Respondente,O Todo-Permeante,O Sábio,O Amoroso,O Glorioso,O Infusor de Nova Vida,O Testemunho Observador,A Encarnação da Verdade,O Fiduciário Universal,O Forte,O Firme,O Associado Protetor,O Único Louvável,O Todo-Enumerador,O Originador,O Restaurador,O Mantenedor da Vida,O Infusor de Morte,O Eterno Vivo,O Auto-Subsistente,O Indicador,O Nobre,O Único,O Provedor Supremo,O Onipotente,O Todo-Autoritário,O Acelerador,O Procrastinador,O Primeiro,O Último,O Perceptível,O Imperceptível,O Detentor da Autoridade Suprema,O Extremamente Exaltado,A Fonte da Verdade,O Sempre Aceitador do Arrependimento,O Retaliador,O Supremo Perdoador,O Benigno,O Eterno Possuidor de Soberania,O Possuidor de Majestade e Honra,O Justo,O Reunidor de Criações Dispersas,O Auto-Suficiente,O Doador de Suficiência,O Preventivo,O Aflitivo,O Doador de Benefícios,A Luz Principal,O Provedor de Orientação,O Único,O Sempre Vivo,O Herdeiro Eterno,O Guia para o Caminho da Retidão,O Extremamente Duradouro"</string>
    <string name="des_pr">"Ya Rahmanu é Aquele que deseja bondade e misericórdia para todas as Suas criaturas. Ele concede imensa graça e bênçãos ao universo... mostrando compaixão a todos os seres. Sua misericórdia é vasta e abrange todas as coisas... independentemente de sua fé ou ações. Este nome reflete o cuidado nutridor de Allah para com toda a criação., Ya Raheemu é Aquele que age com extrema bondade e compaixão... especialmente para com os crentes. Sua misericórdia é eterna e se manifesta tanto neste mundo quanto no Além. Este nome significa o perdão de Allah e as recompensas que Ele prepara para os fiéis. Enfatiza Sua natureza gentil e compassiva., Ya Maliku é o Senhor Soberano... Aquele com domínio completo sobre o universo. Seu governo é absoluto... e Sua autoridade é perfeita e livre de qualquer imperfeição. Este nome ilustra o poder e o controle de Allah sobre todas as coisas... visíveis e invisíveis. Ele governa toda a criação com sabedoria e justiça., Ya Quddusu é Aquele que é puro de qualquer imperfeição e é exaltado acima de todas as falhas e fraquezas. Ele é livre de todos os atributos que implicam defeito ou deficiência. Este nome destaca a pureza e santidade de Allah. Reflete Sua transcendência e santidade... estando além da compreensão humana., Ya Salamu é Aquele que está livre de toda imperfeição e concede paz e segurança à Sua criação. Ele concede tranquilidade aos corações e mentes... garantindo segurança e harmonia. Este nome significa a perfeição de Allah e a paz que vem da submissão a Ele. Ressalta Seu papel como o doador de serenidade., Ya Mu\'minu é Aquele que oferece segurança e confirma a verdade dos Seus fiéis crentes. Ele oferece proteção e paz... protegendo-os do medo e do mal. Este nome enfatiza o papel de Allah em prover segurança e confiança. Também assegura aos crentes a veracidade de sua fé e a realidade de Suas promessas., Ya Muhayminu é Aquele que vigia e protege toda a Sua criação... conhecendo suas ações e pensamentos. Ele mantém e supervisiona todas as coisas com conhecimento e autoridade perfeitos. Este nome reflete a vigilância de Allah e Sua guarda sobre tudo. Assegura aos crentes Seu cuidado constante e atenção., Ya Azizu é Aquele que é poderoso e forte... o Derrotador que não é derrotado. Ele é incomparável em poder e honra... superando todos os Seus inimigos. Este nome ilustra a força e invencibilidade de Allah. Mostra Sua capacidade de prevalecer e proteger aqueles que buscam Sua ajuda., Ya Jabbaaru é Aquele que compele e restaura... exercendo Sua vontade sobre Sua criação. Ele conserta o que está quebrado e impõe Seu decreto sobre tudo o que existe. Este nome significa o poder de Allah para impor Seus comandos e retificar as questões. Também reflete Sua capacidade de curar e restaurar o equilíbrio., Ya Mutakabbiru é Aquele que está livre dos atributos das criaturas e de assemelhar-se a elas... e que é supremamente grande. Somente Ele possui grandeza e majestade além da compreensão. Este nome destaca a superioridade e transcendência de Allah sobre toda a criação. Enfatiza Seu status exaltado e a dignidade de Sua essência divina., Ya Khaaliqu é Aquele que traz tudo da não-existência à existência. Ele cria todas as coisas com precisão e propósito. Este nome reflete a capacidade de Allah de originar e inovar a criação. Ressalta Seu papel como o Criador supremo do universo e de tudo o que ele contém., Ya Baariu é o Fazedor... o Criador que tem o poder de transformar entidades em diferentes estados. Ele traz à tona e evolui Sua criação de acordo com Sua sabedoria. Este nome significa a criatividade de Allah e Sua habilidade de formar Suas criaturas de maneiras únicas. Destaca Seu papel em moldar e desenvolver todas as formas de vida., Ya Musawwiru é Aquele que forma Suas criaturas em diferentes formas e aspectos. Ele dá a cada criação suas características e atributos únicos. Este nome enfatiza o poder artístico de Allah e a atenção aos detalhes na criação. Reflete Sua habilidade de desenhar e dar forma a todos os seres., Ya Ghaffaaru é Aquele que perdoa os pecados de Seus servos repetidamente. Seu perdão é vasto... cobrindo até mesmo os pecados mais graves para aqueles que se arrependem. Este nome significa a misericórdia ilimitada de Allah e Sua disposição para perdoar. Ressalta Sua prontidão para perdoar e limpar aqueles que buscam Seu perdão., Ya Qahhaaru é o Dominador... Aquele que tem o poder perfeito e não é incapaz de nada. Ele domina e subjuga Sua criação como deseja. Este nome ilustra o controle absoluto e a dominância de Allah sobre todas as coisas. Reflete Sua capacidade de subjugar e Sua autoridade suprema., Ya Wahhaabu é Aquele que é Generoso em dar abundantemente sem qualquer retorno. Ele concede presentes e bênçãos de Sua bondade e graça. Este nome significa a generosidade e a bondade de Allah. Destaca Seu papel como o doador de tudo o que beneficia... seja lícito ou proibido.,Ya Razzaaqu é o Sustentador... o Provedor que garante o sustento de todas as Suas criaturas. Ele distribui provisões com sabedoria e generosidade. Este nome enfatiza o papel de Allah em prover para as necessidades de Sua criação. Destaca Seu cuidado e benevolência em sustentar a vida., Ya Fattaahu é o Abridor... o Aliviador... o Juiz que abre para Seus servos as questões mundanas e religiosas fechadas. Ele concede vitória... alívio e soluções para as dificuldades. Este nome significa o poder de Allah para remover obstáculos e fornecer orientação. Reflete Seu papel em facilitar caminhos e resolver questões., Ya Alimu é o Sábio; Aquele de quem nada está ausente do conhecimento. Ele está ciente de todas as coisas... passadas... presentes e futuras. Este nome enfatiza a onisciência de Allah e Seu conhecimento perfeito de todos os assuntos. Destaca Sua consciência e compreensão de toda a criação., Ya Qaabidhu é Aquele que restringe o sustento por Sua sabedoria. Ele retém provisões de acordo com Seu plano divino. Este nome significa o controle de Allah sobre a distribuição de recursos. Destaca Sua sabedoria em determinar o que é melhor para Sua criação., Ya Baasitu é Aquele que expande e amplia o sustento com Sua generosidade e misericórdia. Ele aumenta provisões e concede abundância. Este nome reflete a bondade e liberalidade de Allah. Enfatiza Sua capacidade de ampliar e abençoar Sua criação com recursos abundantes., Ya Khaafidhu é Aquele que abaixa quem Ele deseja por Sua destruição. Ele humilha aqueles que merecem ser rebaixados. Este nome significa a justiça de Allah e Seu poder para abater. Reflete Seu papel em equilibrar as balanças da justiça ao rebaixar os arrogantes e injustos., Ya Raafi\'u é o Elevador... Aquele que eleva quem Ele deseja por Seu dom. Ele eleva o status dos justos e virtuosos. Este nome destaca a capacidade de Allah de honrar e exaltar. Reflete Sua generosidade em conceder altos postos e dignidade aos Seus fiéis servos., Ya Mu\'izzu é Aquele que dá estima a quem Ele deseja; portanto... ninguém pode degradá-lo. Ele concede honra e dignidade aos Seus escolhidos. Este nome significa o poder de Allah para honrar e elevar. Reflete Sua autoridade em conceder respeito e status., Ya Muzillu é o Humilhador... Aquele que degrada quem Ele deseja; portanto... ninguém pode lhe dar estima. Ele derruba os arrogantes e injustos. Este nome enfatiza a justiça de Allah em rebaixar os indignos. Reflete Seu poder de humilhar e abater aqueles que desafiam Seus comandos., Ya Sami\'u é Aquele que ouve todas as coisas que são ouvidas por Sua audição eterna sem ouvido... instrumento ou órgão. Ele escuta as orações e súplicas de Sua criação. Este nome significa a audição perfeita e abrangente de Allah. Reflete Sua atenção às necessidades e súplicas de Seus servos., Ya Basiru é Aquele que vê todas as coisas que são vistas por Sua visão eterna sem pupila ou qualquer outro instrumento. Ele observa todas as ações e eventos no universo. Este nome enfatiza a visão onipresente de Allah. Reflete Sua consciência e vigilância sobre toda a criação., Ya Hakamu é o Governante... e Seu julgamento é Sua palavra. Ele resolve todas as questões com justiça e sabedoria. Este nome significa o papel de Allah como o árbitro e juiz supremo. Destaca Sua autoridade em tomar decisões justas e Sua palavra final em todos os assuntos., Ya \'Adlu é Aquele que tem o direito de fazer o que faz. Suas ações e julgamentos são justos e equitativos. Este nome reflete a justiça e equilíbrio perfeitos de Allah. Destaca Seu papel em manter a equidade e retidão no universo., Ya Latifu é o Gracioso... Aquele que é gentil com Seus servos e os concede. Ele entende os mistérios e intrincidades mais sutis. Este nome significa a natureza gentil e compassiva de Allah. Destaca Sua bondade e Seus modos sutis de conceder graça e misericórdia., Ya Khabiru é Aquele que conhece a verdade das coisas. Ele está plenamente ciente de todos os assuntos ocultos e aparentes. Este nome enfatiza o conhecimento profundo e a consciência de Allah. Reflete Sua compreensão da verdadeira essência de todas as coisas., Ya Halimu é Aquele que adia o castigo para aqueles que merecem e depois pode perdoá-los. Ele é paciente e leniente. Este nome significa a tolerância e paciência de Allah. Reflete Sua disposição em dar tempo para arrependimento e correção., Ya-\'Adheemu é o Poderoso... Aquele que merece exaltação... glória... louvor e pureza de toda imperfeição. Ele é majestoso e grandioso em todos os aspectos. Este nome destaca a grandeza e majestade de Allah. Reflete Seu status exaltado e a reverência que Ele merece., Ya Ghafuru é o Perdoador... Aquele que perdoa muito. Seu perdão é extenso e cobre todos os pecados para aqueles que se arrependem sinceramente. Este nome significa a imensa misericórdia de Allah e Sua prontidão para perdoar. Enfatiza Sua generosidade em perdoar e ignorar as falhas., Ya Shakuru é Aquele que dá uma grande recompensa por uma pequena obediência. Ele reconhece e recompensa até mesmo os menores atos de bondade. Este nome reflete a generosidade e apreciação de Allah pelos esforços de Seus servos. Destaca Sua disposição em multiplicar recompensas por boas ações., Ya Aliu é Aquele que está livre dos atributos das criaturas. Ele é exaltado acima de toda a criação. Este nome significa o status supremo e transcendência de Allah. Reflete Seu alto posto e a pureza de Sua essência divina.,Ya Kabiru é o Grande... Aquele que é maior do que tudo em status. Sua grandeza é incompreensível. Este nome enfatiza a imensa grandeza de Allah. Destaca Sua superioridade sobre tudo o que existe., Ya Hafidhu é o Protetor... Aquele que protege o que e quem Ele deseja proteger. Ele salvaguarda toda a criação do mal. Este nome significa o papel de Allah como o guardião e preservador. Reflete Sua capacidade de manter e proteger Sua criação., Ya Muqitu é o Guardião... o Alimentador... Aquele que tem o poder de sustentar todas as coisas. Ele fornece sustento e apoia toda a vida. Este nome destaca o papel de Allah em sustentar e nutrir Sua criação. Enfatiza Seu cuidado contínuo e provisão., Ya Hasibu é Aquele que dá satisfação. Ele é suficiente como protetor e contador. Este nome significa a capacidade de Allah de contabilizar todas as ações e feitos. Reflete Seu papel em proporcionar retribuição e garantir a justiça., Ya Jalilu é o Beneficente... Aquele que é atribuído com grandeza de poder e glória de status. Ele é majestoso e reverenciado. Este nome destaca a grandeza e majestade de Allah. Reflete Seu status exaltado e a reverência que Ele comanda., Ya Karimu é o Gracioso... Aquele que é atribuído com grandeza de poder e glória de status. Ele é generoso e bondoso. Este nome significa a generosidade e benevolência de Allah. Destaca Sua disposição em dar e conceder favores., Ya Raqibu é Aquele de quem nada está ausente. Ele observa todas as ações e pensamentos. Este nome enfatiza a vigilância e consciência de Allah. Reflete Sua capacidade de monitorar e supervisionar toda a criação., Ya Mujibu é o Atencioso... Aquele que responde ao necessitado se ele pedir e resgata o anelante se ele invocar. Ele responde às orações e súplicas. Este nome significa a prontidão de Allah para responder e ajudar. Destaca Sua receptividade aos chamados de Seus servos., Ya Wasi\'u é o Vasto... Aquele cujo conhecimento e misericórdia abrangem todas as coisas. Ele é ilimitado em Seus atributos. Este nome reflete a natureza infinita e a compaixão sem limites de Allah. Enfatiza Sua capacidade de abranger toda a criação com Sua graça e conhecimento., Ya Hakimu é o Juiz dos Juízes... Aquele que está correto em Seus atos. Sua sabedoria governa todas as ações e decretos. Este nome significa a sabedoria perfeita e o julgamento de Allah. Destaca Sua capacidade de tomar decisões que são justas e sábias., Ya Wadudu é Aquele que ama Seus servos crentes e cujos crentes O amam. Seu amor se manifesta em Sua misericórdia e louvor por eles. Este nome reflete o afeto e a bondade de Allah para com Seus servos fiéis. Enfatiza o amor recíproco entre o Criador e Sua criação., Ya Majeedu é Aquele com poder perfeito... status elevado... compaixão... generosidade e bondade. Ele é majestoso e honrado. Este nome significa a grandeza e nobreza de Allah. Destaca Sua posição exaltada e a glória de Seus atributos., Ya Ba\'ithu é o Ressuscitador (da morte)... Aquele que ressuscita Seus servos após a morte para recompensa e/ou punição. Ele traz os mortos à vida. Este nome significa o poder de Allah sobre a vida e a morte. Reflete Sua capacidade de realizar a ressurreição e julgar todos os seres., Ya Shaheedu é Aquele de quem nada está ausente. Ele testemunha todas as ações e eventos. Este nome enfatiza a onipresença de Allah e Seu papel como uma testemunha sempre presente. Reflete Sua consciência de tudo o que acontece no universo., Ya Haqqu é o Verdadeiro... Aquele que verdadeiramente existe. Sua existência é absoluta e eterna. Este nome significa a realidade e autenticidade de Allah. Enfatiza Sua posição como a verdade última e a base de toda a existência., Ya Wakilu é Aquele que dá satisfação e em quem se confia. Ele é o melhor guardião e fiduciário. Este nome reflete a confiabilidade e a confiança em Allah. Enfatiza Seu papel como aquele a quem todos os assuntos são confiados., Ya Qawiyyu é o Forte... Aquele com poder completo. Ele é poderoso e forte além da medida. Este nome significa a força e autoridade de Allah. Destaca Sua capacidade de realizar todas as coisas e proteger Sua criação., Ya Mateenu é Aquele com poder extremo que é ininterrupto e Ele não se cansa. Sua força é sólida e inabalável. Este nome reflete a firmeza e a resiliência de Allah. Enfatiza Seu poder duradouro e firmeza., Ya Waliu é o Apoiador e protetor. Ele é amigo e ajuda Seus servos justos. Este nome significa a proximidade e o apoio de Allah. Reflete Seu papel como guardião e aliado daqueles que buscam Sua proteção., Ya Hamiduu é o Louvado... Aquele que merece ser louvado. Seus atributos e ações são dignos de todo louvor. Este nome reflete o merecimento de Allah de gratidão e admiração. Enfatiza Sua natureza louvável e a honra que Lhe é devida., Ya Muhsi é Aquele que a contagem das coisas é conhecida por Ele. Ele está ciente de todas as quantidades e medidas. Este nome significa o conhecimento abrangente de Allah de todos os detalhes. Reflete Sua capacidade de contabilizar tudo o que existe., Ya Mubdiu é Aquele que iniciou o ser humano. Ele cria sem nenhum modelo preexistente. Este nome significa a inovação e originalidade de Allah na criação. Destaca Seu papel como o criador inicial de todas as coisas., Ya Mu\'idu é Aquele que traz de volta as criaturas após a morte. Ele restaura a vida e revive os mortos. Este nome significa o poder de Allah sobre a vida e a morte. Reflete Sua capacidade de ressuscitar e trazer de volta Sua criação., Ya Muhyi é Aquele que dá vida ao inanimado. Ele revive tanto a vida física quanto espiritual. Este nome significa o papel de Allah em criar e sustentar a vida. Destaca Sua capacidade de conceder e renovar a vida.,Ya Mumitu é Aquele que torna os vivos mortos. Ele tem controle sobre a vida e a morte. Este nome significa o poder de Allah para tirar a vida. Reflete Sua autoridade sobre o fim da vida e a transição para o além., Ya Hayyu é Aquele que é atribuído a uma vida que não é como a nossa vida e não é a de uma combinação de alma... carne ou sangue. Ele possui vida eterna e autossustentável. Este nome significa a existência única e eterna de Allah. Reflete Sua vitalidade e a fonte da própria vida., Ya Qayyumu é Aquele que permanece e não tem fim. Ele sustenta todas as coisas por Si mesmo e não necessita de nenhum suporte. Este nome significa a autossuficiência e independência de Allah. Reflete Sua existência eterna e Seu papel como o sustentador de toda a criação., Ya Waajidu é o Encontrador... o Rico que nunca é pobre. Ele é autossuficiente e abundante em riquezas. Este nome significa a riqueza de Allah e Sua capacidade de prover para todas as necessidades. Reflete Sua completude e a suficiência de Seus atributos., Ya Maajidu é o Mais Glorioso... Aquele que tem poder perfeito. Sua grandeza é incomparável e radiante. Este nome significa a magnificência e o esplendor de Allah. Reflete Sua presença majestosa e a glória de Sua essência divina., Ya Waahidu é o Único... o Eterno... o Independente. Ele é singular e incomparável. Este nome significa a unicidade e a singularidade de Allah. Reflete Sua unidade absoluta e independência de toda a criação., Ya Ahadu é o Único sem parceiro... o Ímpar. Ele não tem igual ou rival. Este nome significa a unidade indivisível e a singularidade de Allah. Reflete Seu status exclusivo como a única divindade digna de adoração., Ya Samadu é o Eterno... o Independente... o Mestre em quem se confia. Ele é eterno e imutável. Este nome significa a natureza eterna de Allah e Seu papel como a fonte última de apoio. Reflete Sua permanência e constância., Ya Qaadiru é o Capaz... Aquele atribuído com Poder. Ele tem a capacidade de realizar todas as coisas. Este nome significa a onipotência de Allah e Seu controle sobre todos os assuntos. Reflete Seu poder ilimitado e autoridade., Ya Muqtadiru é o Dominante... Aquele com poder completo. Sua autoridade é absoluta e irresistível. Este nome significa a soberania de Allah e Sua capacidade de impor Sua vontade. Reflete Seu supremo poder e controle sobre toda a criação., Ya Muqaddimu é Aquele que avança e acelera. Ele prioriza e facilita as questões de acordo com Sua sabedoria. Este nome significa a capacidade de Allah de acelerar e expedir eventos. Reflete Seu poder para trazer resultados rapidamente e de forma decisiva., Ya Mu\'akhkhiru é Aquele que atrasa e adia. Ele adia eventos de acordo com Seu plano divino. Este nome significa a sabedoria de Allah em retardar os resultados para um propósito maior. Reflete Seu controle sobre o tempo e Sua capacidade de determinar o ritmo dos eventos., Ya Awwalu é o Primeiro... Aquele que existia antes de tudo o mais. Ele é a origem e a fonte de toda a criação. Este nome significa a precedência de Allah e Sua existência atemporal. Reflete Sua primazia e o início de todas as coisas., Ya Aakhiru é o Último... Aquele que permanecerá depois que tudo o mais tiver perecido. Ele é eterno e duradouro. Este nome significa a permanência de Allah e Sua presença além do fim do tempo. Reflete Sua finalidade e a conclusão última de toda a existência., Ya Dhaahiru é o Manifesto... Aquele cuja presença é evidente e clara. Ele é aparente e visível em Seus sinais e criações. Este nome significa a visibilidade de Allah e Sua manifestação no universo. Reflete Sua clareza e a demonstração evidente de Seus atributos., Ya Baatinu é o Oculto... Aquele cuja essência é oculta e misteriosa. Ele está além da percepção e compreensão humanas. Este nome significa a invisibilidade de Allah e Sua natureza oculta. Reflete Sua transcendência e a profundidade de Sua essência divina., Ya Waaliu é o Patrono... o Amigo Protetor que guia e apoia Seus servos. Ele é seu aliado e guardião. Este nome significa a proximidade de Allah e Seu papel como um companheiro de apoio. Reflete Seu cuidado e orientação para aqueles que buscam Sua proteção., Ya Muta\'ali é o Supremamente Exaltado... Aquele cujo status é incomparável. Ele está elevado acima de toda a criação. Este nome significa a transcendência de Allah e Seu status exaltado. Reflete Sua superioridade e a elevação de Sua essência divina., Ya Barru é a Fonte de Bondade... Aquele que é gentil e benevolente. Ele concede bênçãos e favores à Sua criação. Este nome significa a bondade de Allah e Sua abundante graça. Reflete Sua generosidade e a abundância de Suas bênçãos., Ya Tawwaabu é o Sempre Retornante... Aquele que aceita o arrependimento e perdoa os pecados. Ele é misericordioso e compassivo. Este nome significa a disposição de Allah para perdoar e Sua prontidão para aceitar aqueles que se voltam para Ele em arrependimento. Reflete Sua misericórdia infinita e Seu convite para retornar a Ele., Ya Muntaqimu é o Vingador... Aquele que pune aqueles que transgridem Seus limites. Ele aplica justiça e retribuição. Este nome significa a ira de Allah contra a injustiça e Seu compromisso de manter a justiça. Reflete Seu papel como o juiz supremo e executor da justiça divina., Ya \'Afuwwu é o Perdoador... Aquele que perdoa e ignora falhas. Ele apaga os pecados e concede absolvição. Este nome significa a misericórdia de Allah e Sua disposição para perdoar sem guardar rancores. Reflete Sua generosidade em perdoar Seus servos., Ya Ra\'ufu é o Compassivo... Aquele que é terno e misericordioso. Ele sente empatia por Sua criação e lhes mostra compaixão. Este nome significa a gentileza de Allah e Sua natureza carinhosa. Reflete Sua simpatia e preocupação pelo bem-estar de Seus servos., Ya Malik Al Mulki é o Proprietário da Soberania... Aquele que possui domínio sobre todas as coisas. Ele é o governante e autoridade suprema. Este nome significa a realeza de Allah e Seu controle absoluto sobre o universo. Reflete Sua soberania e Seu direito de comandar e decretar., Ya Jal-Jalali Al Ikram é Aquele que possui grandeza e nobreza. Ele é majestoso e digno de toda honra e respeito. Este nome significa o status exaltado de Allah e Seu merecimento de reverência. Reflete Sua dignidade... magnificência e a honra que Lhe é devida.,Ya Muqsitu é Aquele que é justo e equitativo em todos os Seus julgamentos e ações. Ele mantém o equilíbrio e a equidade no universo. Este nome significa o compromisso de Allah com a justiça e a equidade. Reflete Seu papel em garantir que todas as ações sejam recompensadas ou punidas adequadamente., Ya Jaami\'u é Aquele que reúne o que Ele quer... quando Ele quer. Ele reunirá todas as criaturas para o Dia do Julgamento. Este nome significa a capacidade de Allah de reunir e unir. Reflete Seu poder de trazer todos os seres para a prestação de contas., Ya Ghaniu é Aquele que é livre de qualquer necessidade. Ele é autossuficiente e independente de toda a criação. Este nome significa a riqueza de Allah e Sua ausência de necessidade de qualquer coisa fora de Si mesmo. Reflete Sua suficiência absoluta e independência., Ya Mughniu é Aquele que provê riqueza e suficiência às Suas criaturas. Ele enriquece quem Ele quer. Este nome significa a generosidade de Allah e Sua capacidade de conceder prosperidade. Reflete Seu papel em conceder abundância e riqueza aos Seus servos., Ya Mani\'u é Aquele que impede que o mal ou dano ocorram. Ele é o protetor e o defensor. Este nome significa a capacidade de Allah de proteger e defender do perigo. Reflete Seu papel em salvaguardar Sua criação do mal., Ya Dharru é Aquele que pode causar dano ou aflição se Ele quiser. Ele tem controle sobre todas as circunstâncias. Este nome significa o poder de Allah sobre a adversidade e a dificuldade. Reflete Sua autoridade para trazer provações como um teste ou punição., Ya Nafi\'u é Aquele que traz benefícios e bênçãos. Ele concede bondade e bem-estar. Este nome significa o papel de Allah em prover e facilitar resultados positivos. Reflete Sua capacidade de conceder benefícios e favores., Ya Nuru é a Luz... Aquele que ilumina os céus e a terra. Ele guia e proporciona clareza. Este nome significa o papel de Allah como uma fonte de orientação e iluminação. Reflete Sua capacidade de trazer luz à escuridão e clareza à confusão., Ya Hadiu é Aquele que guia Seus servos para o caminho certo. Ele proporciona direção e inspiração. Este nome significa o papel de Allah como uma fonte de orientação e sabedoria. Reflete Sua capacidade de conduzir Sua criação à retidão e à verdade., Ya Badi\'iu é o Incomparável... Aquele que cria de maneiras inigualáveis e maravilhosas. Ele é único em Sua criação. Este nome significa a originalidade de Allah e Seu poder criativo incomparável. Reflete Sua capacidade de criar sem precedentes ou modelo., Ya Baaqiu é o Eterno... Aquele que permanece quando tudo o mais perece. Ele é eterno e imutável. Este nome significa a permanência de Allah e Sua existência além do tempo. Reflete Sua continuidade e a natureza eterna de Seu ser., Ya Waarithu é o Herdeiro... Aquele que permanece depois que toda a criação chega ao fim. Ele herdará a terra e tudo o que nela há. Este nome significa a posse final de Allah e Sua presença duradoura. Reflete Seu papel como o possuidor final de todas as coisas., Ya Rashidu é o Mestre Justo... Aquele que guia para o caminho da retidão. Ele proporciona sabedoria e compreensão correta. Este nome significa o papel de Allah como mestre e guia. Reflete Sua capacidade de conduzir Seus servos ao conhecimento reto e benéfico., Ya Sabooru é o Paciente... Aquele que não se apressa em punir os pecadores. Ele é tolerante e longânimo. Este nome significa a paciência de Allah e Sua resistência em retardar a punição. Reflete Sua disposição em dar tempo para o arrependimento e Sua perseverança em lidar com as transgressões humanas."</string>
    <!--    russian-->
    <string name="app_name_ru">99 Имен Аллаха</string>
    <string name="language_ru">Русский</string>
    <string name="names_ru">"1. Ya Rahmanu,2.	Ya Raheemu,3.	Ya Maliku,4.	Ya Quddusu,5.	Ya Salamu,6.	Ya Mu\'minu,7.	Ya Muhayminu,8.	Ya Azizu,9.	Ya Jabbaaru,10.	Ya Mutakabbiru,11.	Ya Khaaliqu,12.	Ya Baariu,13.	Ya Musawwiru,14.	Ya Ghaffaaru,15.	Ya Qahhaaru,16.	Ya Wahhaabu,17.	Ya Razzaaqu,18.	Ya Fattaahu,19.	Ya Alimu,20.	Ya Qaabidhu,21.	Ya Baasitu,22.	Ya Khaafidhu,23.	Ya Raafi\'u,24.	Ya Mu\'izzu,25.	Ya Muzillu,26.	Ya Sami\'u,27.	Ya Basiru,28.	Ya Hakamu,29.	Ya \'Adlu,30.	Ya Latifu,31.	Ya Khabiru,32.	Ya Halimu,33.	Ya-‘Adheemu,34.	Ya Ghafuru,35.	Ya Shakuru,36.	Ya Aliu,37.	Ya Kabiru,38.	Ya Hafidhu,39.	Ya Muqitu,40.	Ya Hasibu,41.	Ya Jalilu,42.	Ya Karimu,43.	Ya Raqibu,44.	Ya Mujibu,45.	Ya Wasi\'u,46.	Ya Hakimu,47.	Ya Wadudu,48.	Ya Majeedu,49.	Ya Ba\'ithu,50.	Ya Shaheedu,51.	Ya Haqqu,52.	Ya Wakilu,53.	Ya Qawiyyu,54.	Ya Mateenu,55.	Ya Waliu,56.	Ya Hamiduu,57.	Ya Muhsi,58.	Ya Mubdiu,59.	Ya Mu\'idu,60.	Ya Muhyi,61.	Ya Mumitu,62.	Ya Hayyu,63.	Ya Qayyumu,64.	Ya Waajidu,65.	Ya Maajidu,66.	Ya Waahidu,67.	Ya Ahadu,68.	Ya Samadu,69.	Ya Qaadiru,70.	Ya Muqtadiru,71.	Ya Muqaddimu,72.	Ya Mu\'akhkhiru,73.	Ya Awwalu,74.	Ya Aakhiru,75.	Ya Dhaahiru,76.	Ya Baatinu,77.	Ya Waaliu,78.	Ya Muta\'ali,79.	Ya Barru,80.	Ya Tawwaabu,81.	Ya Muntaqimu,82.	Ya \'Afuwwu,83.	Ya Ra\'ufu,84.	Ya Malik Al Mulki,85.	Ya Jal-Jalali Al Ikram,86.	Ya Muqsitu,87.	Ya Jaami\'u,88.	Ya Ghaniu,89.	Ya Mughniu,90.	Ya Mani\'u,91.	Ya Dharru,92.	Ya Nafi\'u,93.	Ya Nuru,94.	Ya Hadiu,95.	Ya Badi\'iu,96.	Ya Baaqiu,97.	Ya Waarithu,98.	Ya Rashidu,99.	Ya Sabooru"</string>

    <string name="meaning_ru">"Благодетель,Милостивый,Вечный Господь,Наисвятейший,Воплощение Мира,Дарующий Веру,Сохранитель Безопасности,Могущественный,Всемогущий,Господствующий,Творец,Эволюционирующий,Совершенный Формирователь,Великий Прощающий,Вездесущий,Верховный Даритель,Общий Обеспечитель,Верховный Решатель,Всезнающий,Ограничивающий,Расширяющий,Уменьшающий,Возвышающий,Дарующий Почет-Даритель,Унижатель,Все-Слышащий,Все-Видящий,Беспристрастный Судья,Воплощение Справедливости,Знающий Тонкости,Всеведущий,Милосердный,Великий,Великий Прощающий,Признающий,Возвышенный,Великий,Хранитель,Поддерживающий,Счетчик,Величественный,Щедрый,Наблюдающий,Отвечающий,Все-Проникающий,Мудрый,Любящий,Славный,Дарующий Новую Жизнь,Наблюдающий Свидетель,Воплощение Истины,Всеобщий Доверенный,Сильный,Твердый,Защитный Партнер,Достойный Хвалы,Всеисчисляющий,Создатель,Восстановитель,Поддерживающий жизнь,Наводящий Смерть,Вечно Живой,Самостоятельный,Указующий,Благородный,Единый,Единственный,Высший Обеспечитель,Всемогущий,Все-авторитетный,Ускоряющий,Медлящий,Первый,Последний,Зримый,Незримый,Обладатель Верховной Власти,Чрезвычайно Возвышенный,Источник Истины,Всегда Принимающий Покаяние,Мстящий,Верховный Прощающий,Добрый,Вечный Обладатель Суверенитета,Обладатель Величия и Чести,Справедливый,Собиратель Разрозненных Творений,Самодостаточный,Дарующий Достаток,Предотвращающий,Наносящий Боль,Дарующий Блага,Главный Свет,Руководитель,Уникальный,Вечно Живущий,Вечный Наследник,Руководитель на Путь Праведности,Чрезвычайно Долговечный"</string>





</resources>
